<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>/TechnoTravel-in/</title>
   
   <link>/TechnoTravel-in/</link>
   <description>The daily source of digital inspirations</description>
   <language>en-in</language>
   
   <title>
   <![CDATA[ TechnoTravel.in ]]>
   </title>
   <description>
   <![CDATA[ The daily source of digital inspirations ]]>
   </description>
   <link>/TechnoTravel-in/</link>
   <image>
   <url>/TechnoTravel-in/assets/images/favicon.ico</url>
   <title>TechnoTravel.in</title>
   <link>/TechnoTravel-in/</link>
   </image>
   <generator>Jekyll 3.6.2</generator>
   <lastBuildDate></lastBuildDate>
   <atom:link href="/TechnoTravel-in/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
   <ttl>60</ttl>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Google Launches Crazy 1000Mbps Fiber Internet Today</title>
	  <link>/TechnoTravel-in/2012/07/google-launches-crazy-1000mbps-fiber-internet-today</link>
		
				
						<author>Rajat Patel</author>
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
	  <pubDate>2012-07-28T12:07:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/TechnoTravel-in/2012/07/google-launches-crazy-1000mbps-fiber-internet-today</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-cWlHCbRol8o/UBPVHv3JrmI/AAAAAAAAA4U/Minx4Dj1_l0/s1600/rabbit-new-endframe.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="158" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-cWlHCbRol8o/UBPVHv3JrmI/AAAAAAAAA4U/Minx4Dj1_l0/s640/rabbit-new-endframe.jpg" width="640" /></a></div><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">The unbelievably fast 1000Mbps Fiber Internet is unveiled by Google toady in Kansas City. And to add to that, it'll have no bandwidth cap, no overage fees and moreover, it'll give away a humongous 1TB of cloud storage data absolutely free!</span><br /><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><br /><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">In addition to this, Google has also introduced the TV service called Google Fiber Television with the help of this Google Fiber Internet. This seems similar to Google TV that we reviewed here, but according to google, it's more compiled and revamped which can record as many as 500 Hours of heavy HD videos. (With a 1000Mbps you'd rather expect that!).&nbsp;</span><span style="background-color: white; color: #333333; font-family: Georgia, Times, 'Liberation Serif', serif; font-size: 15px; line-height: 22px; text-align: -webkit-auto;">&nbsp;</span><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">There will be remote apps for iOS and Android, both of which will have voice control, and at some point they'll get video streaming as well. The TV package will have all broadcast networks, along with hundreds of "Fiber channels".</span><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><object class="BLOGGER-youtube-video" classid="clsid:D27CDB6E-AE6D-11cf-96B8-444553540000" codebase="http://download.macromedia.com/pub/shockwave/cabs/flash/swflash.cab#version=6,0,40,0" data-thumbnail-src="http://2.gvt0.com/vi/A9v11qJTG8o/0.jpg" height="266" width="420"><param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/A9v11qJTG8o&fs=1&source=uds" /><param name="bgcolor" value="#FFFFFF" /><param name="allowFullScreen" value="true" /><embed width="320" height="266"  src="http://www.youtube.com/v/A9v11qJTG8o&fs=1&source=uds" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" allowfullscreen="true"></embed></object></div><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Oh and a one thing worth mentioning here is that you'll get a Nexus 7 free for signing up for a TV package.</span><br /><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><br /><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">There is a $300 construction fee for installing the fiber at your house, though. But Google is waiving that fee for new customers at the start. The internet and TV package, along with the 1TB of storage, is $120 per month. An internet-only package, with the 1TB, is $70 per month. And if you decide to pay the construction fee, you can also choose a FREE 5Mbps down 1Mbps up internet package. You can break that payment down to $25/month for the first year, with a minimum of 7 years of free service, too.</span><br /><div><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">The distance between Google Fiber and its competitors is comical. While yes, Google Fiber is only in Kansas City for now, the closest you can get to it commercially is&nbsp;Verizon's 300Mbps connection over FiOS, which can reach that speed, but more often comes in well below. And that's more than three times slower than the gigabit connection Google just birthed. </span><br /><div><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">That kind of scope and performance has had competitors running scared enough to put out bounties for on-the-ground information about Google Fiber.&nbsp;</span><br /><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Huh, I wish I'd have been an American rather than a 5Mbps max Indian!</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">[Inputs From <a href="http://fiber.google.com/about/" target="_blank">Google Fiber</a>, <a href="http://gizmodo.com/5929295/googles-crazy-1000mbps-fiber-internet-connection-is-out-today" target="_blank">GIZMODO</a> via <a href="http://digg.com/newsbar/Technology/google_s_crazy_1000mbps_fiber_internet_connection_is_out_today" target="_blank">Digg</a>]</span></div><div><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div></div>
	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>[Infographic] The Android Story - History of Android</title>
	  <link>/TechnoTravel-in/2011/08/infographic-android-story-history-of</link>
		
				
						<author>Rajat Patel</author>
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
	  <pubDate>2011-08-15T19:01:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/TechnoTravel-in/2011/08/infographic-android-story-history-of</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><span style="color: black;"><span style="font-family: Verdana,sans-serif;"><span style="font-size: small;">The Android operating system have grown faster than anything in this smartphone oriented world. As the recent news buzzing about <a href="http://www.technotravel.in/2011/08/google-acquires-motorola-mobility-what.html" target="_blank&quot;">Google-Motorola deal and the future prospects</a>, it's a time to relive the moments and witness the twist and turns of probably the fastest developing and expanding operating system - Android.&nbsp;</span></span></span><br /><span style="color: black;"><span style="font-family: Verdana,sans-serif;"><span style="font-size: small;"><br /></span></span></span><br /><span style="color: black;"><span style="font-family: Verdana,sans-serif;"><span style="font-size: small;">It all started in October, 2003, when the Android was invented by Andy Rubin, Rich Minner, Nick Sears and Chris White in Palo Alto, California. It was not much publicized until Google acquired Android Inc in August, 2005. And after that, who on earth don't know the success story of Android.</span></span></span><br /><span style="color: black;"><span style="font-family: Verdana,sans-serif;"><span style="font-size: small;"><br /></span></span></span><br /><span style="color: black;"><span style="font-family: Verdana,sans-serif;"><span style="font-size: small;">So, on this occasion I would like to share the creative infographic made by <a href="http://www.xcubelabs.com/" target="_blank&quot;">[x]cubelabs</a> about the Android History and Developments. Hope you'll enjoy it!</span></span></span><br /><br /><br /></div><a href="http://www.xcubelabs.com/the-android-story.php"target="_blank"><img alt="The-Andriod-Story" border="0" src="http://www.xcubelabs.com/images/android-infograph.png" /></a><br /><div style="font-family: Verdana,sans-serif;">Infographic by <a href="http://www.xcubelabs.com/" target="_blank&quot;">Android Developers at [x]cubelabs</a> </div></div>
	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Google acquires Motorola Mobility - What Next?</title>
	  <link>/TechnoTravel-in/2011/08/google-acquires-motorola-mobility-what</link>
		
				
						<author>Rajat Patel</author>
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
	  <pubDate>2011-08-15T18:46:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/TechnoTravel-in/2011/08/google-acquires-motorola-mobility-what</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-d71fb-srCL8/Tklo87edzNI/AAAAAAAAALw/F80ztphfny0/s1600/google-motorola.top.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-d71fb-srCL8/Tklo87edzNI/AAAAAAAAALw/F80ztphfny0/s1600/google-motorola.top.jpg" /></a></div><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana,sans-serif;">Since its launch in November 2007, Android has not only dramatically  increased consumer choice but also improved the entire mobile experience  for users. Today, more than 150 million Android devices have been  activated worldwide—with over 550,000 devices now lit up every  day—through a network of about 39 manufacturers and 231 carriers in 123  countries. Given Android’s phenomenal success, we are always looking for  new ways to supercharge the Android ecosystem. That is why I am so  excited today to announce that we have agreed to acquire Motorola.</span><br /><br /><blockquote><span style="font-family: Verdana,sans-serif;"><span style="font-size: small;">The above words are said by Larry Page</span></span>, <span style="font-family: Verdana,sans-serif;">CEO of Google Inc while announcing the breaking news of Google acquiring Motorola at the rate of $40 per share of Motorola Mobility. The deal sets around $12.5 billion (About Rs.54000 Crore).</span></blockquote><br /><div style="font-family: Verdana,sans-serif;">He also said, "Motorola has a history of over 80 years of innovation in communications  technology and products, and in the development of intellectual  property, which have helped drive the remarkable revolution in mobile  computing we are all enjoying today. Its many industry milestones  include the introduction of the world’s first portable cell phone nearly  30 years ago, and the StarTAC—the smallest and lightest phone on earth  at time of launch. In 2007, Motorola was a founding member of the Open Handset Alliance  that worked to make Android the first truly open and comprehensive  platform for mobile devices. I have loved my Motorola phones from the  StarTAC era up to the current DROIDs."</div><div style="font-family: Verdana,sans-serif;"><br /></div><div style="font-family: Verdana,sans-serif;">"The combination of Google and Motorola will not only supercharge  Android, but will also enhance competition and offer consumers  accelerating innovation, greater choice, and wonderful user experiences.  I am confident that these great experiences will create huge value for  shareholders."<br /><br />So, after hearing this news, the obvious question that strikes through head "What Next?".&nbsp; So, here are some topics to be thinked about this Google-Motorola combination.<br /><br /><b>A Big Turn in Smartphone market</b><br /><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana,sans-serif;">The </span>Smartphone market biggies like Samsung, HTC, and 39 others, who are in partnership with Google for their Android Operating System, are expected to be more concerned over this Google surprise move then Apple or Microsoft. Well, no one knows what Google gonna do now, but for now, by acquiring the Hardware manufacturer, it's clear that Google wants to turn up heat in the fastest growing Smartphone market with their arch rivels, Apple and Microsoft. Moreover, it seems like a move to give wings to the expansion plans of the projects like <a href="http://www.technotravel.in/2011/07/preview-google-tv-where-television.html" target="_blank&quot;">Google TV</a>. <br /><br /><b>A Manufacturing Spin Out?</b><br /><br />According to <a href="http://saulhansell.blogspot.com/2011/08/six-thoughts-on-goog-moto.html" target="_blank&quot;">Saul Hansell</a>, I also believe that within the decade — if not much sooner — Google will likely spin-out  Motorola’s manufacturing business. As Hansell says, “It’s just not what  [Google does], and it’s not what they need in the long run.”<br /><br /><div><b>Google Strategy</b> </div><div></div><div>This deal is not an endorsement of the Steve  Jobs doctrine that the best way to make software is to control the  hardware that runs it.</div>I think Google believes that, but only  really for the hardware that runs its data centers. Google is to its  core a cloud computing company. It sees hardware as little more than  devices to run browsers of various sorts, which is a way to describe  Android.</div><div style="font-family: Verdana,sans-serif;"><br /><b>Patent Issues</b><br /><br />Google says that they are in this deal mainly because of the patent issues with the counterparts. They are Microsoft, Apple and Oracle. They see themselves in a patent war. So, why buy patents when they can buy a whole company?<br /><br /><b>Will Google TV be benefited?&nbsp; </b><br /><br />For me, the answer is a big "Yes". Given the fact that Motorola is a very large cable box maker, Google would definitely have thought about Google TV expansion with some Moto touch.<br /><br />So, for now we can only wait and watch for the time to come as it is gonna be interesting talking point in the coming future.<br /><br />Also See : <a href="http://www.technotravel.in/2011/08/infographic-android-story-history-of.html"target=_blank">[Infographic] The Android Story - History of Android</a><br /><br />&nbsp; </div></div>
	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>[Review] Google TV - Where television meets the search engine!</title>
	  <link>/TechnoTravel-in/2011/07/preview-google-tv-where-television</link>
		
				
						<author>Rajat Patel</author>
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
	  <pubDate>2011-07-26T07:57:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/TechnoTravel-in/2011/07/preview-google-tv-where-television</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-KyGKcYaXEfk/Ti5ygD8APQI/AAAAAAAAAGs/ro0uDLZ0_C4/s1600/sony-internet-tv-home-screen-with-remote.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="274" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-KyGKcYaXEfk/Ti5ygD8APQI/AAAAAAAAAGs/ro0uDLZ0_C4/s320/sony-internet-tv-home-screen-with-remote.jpg" width="320" /></a></div><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">We haven't been this excited about TV since Saturday morning cartoons. Not only are TVs the center of our living rooms, but five billions of us use them. That is more then the number of the people who use mobile phones or computers.</span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Knowing how the web radically transformed these devices, we wondered what it could do for the most ubiquitous screen in the world. Which is why we've been busy geeking out on how to make TV as awesome as possible.</span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">The result is Google TV. It's an adventure where TV meets web, apps, search and the world's creativity. Like Android, it will be an open source platform. From the start, it will able to work with any TV. And before long, anyone will be able to build apps for it!</span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">These above three paragraphs are not mine. These are of Google for it's new project Google TV. Where you can Browse the whole web, Use the most powerful applications, and do many more things that the conventional TVs can't do.</span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-Ab-l7528PIw/Ti5yqyxUQUI/AAAAAAAAAGw/HCGMK4qSbKk/s1600/google-tv-logo3-m.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="295" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-Ab-l7528PIw/Ti5yqyxUQUI/AAAAAAAAAGw/HCGMK4qSbKk/s320/google-tv-logo3-m.png" width="320" /></a></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><br /></div><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">So, hare are some features of Google TV.</span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif; font-size: large;"><b><u>Advantages:</u></b></span><br /><br /><ul style="text-align: left;"><li><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><b>Search The Web</b> : As a pioneer in the search engine, it's not a surprise that Google adds this feature in Google TV. You can search any channel, any app or any other topic on the web right from your TV.<br />&nbsp;</span></li><li><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><b>Browse The Whole Web</b> : Google TV has no limitations for browsing the web. Means the limitations like only browse those sites which are&nbsp;compatible with Google TV, browse only channel sites etc. But Google TV offers you to browse the whole web. Not some of it, whole of it!<br />&nbsp;</span></li><li><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><b>Apps on Your Television</b> : Your smartphone has apps. Now your TV has too. Google TV offers several apps, and this year developers will also be able to create their own.<br />&nbsp; </span></li><li><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><b>Use your Phone as a Remote Control </b>: Google TV offers the best feature to use your smartphone as a remote control. Now no need to have an extra remote with you alongside smartphone while watching TV. Only smartphone would do!<br />&nbsp;</span></li><li><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><b>TV gets a Homepage</b> : The Home Screen is very customizable and user friendly which gives you a freedom to quickly access your favourite channels, apps and websites.<br />&nbsp;</span></li><li><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><b>TV or Web or Both! </b>: In Google TV, switching between TV and web is seamless. Want to use both at the same time?....No problem, you can watch TV and browse the web at a same time on the same screen.<br />&nbsp;</span></li><li><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><b>Search and Record</b> : If you are a DISH Network subscriber, you will enjoy enhanced features like recording and DVR access right from your search bar.<br />&nbsp;</span></li><li><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><b>Compatibility</b> : Google TV is very much compatible with your existing TV and Internet. No need to spend extra bucks for it!<br />&nbsp;</span></li><li><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><b>Setup </b>: It's very easy to setup Google TV as it is as compatible as anything with your existing TV and Internet.<br />&nbsp;</span></li><li><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><b>Spotlight</b> : The world's leading websites and channels are being tweaked and perfected for the television.<br /></span></li></ul><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Google TV is now available in USA. And Google is also planning the&nbsp;</span><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">aggressive expansion in 2011 and 2012. Let's hope it arrives as soon as possible in India!</span><br /><div><div><div><div><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif; font-size: large;"><b><u>Disadvantages</u></b>:</span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Now if we take a look at the other side of the coin, it's learnt that Google is not trying any drastically different then Apple and Microsoft other than implementing it on Android platform and&nbsp;</span><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">encouraging 3rd party applications.&nbsp;</span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">For Indian users who hope to see Google TV in their homes in time to come there might be some bad news. First of all the technical requirements are high even for users residing in US, forget about that in India-</span><br /><br /><ul style="text-align: left;"><li><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">If you don’t buy a Sony HDTV, you need to buy additional external hardware.<br />&nbsp;&nbsp;</span></li><li><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">It will eventually integrate with Sony PlayStation, again asking too much from an Indian user.<br />&nbsp;</span></li><li><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">For good performance minimum bandwidth requirement is a 3Mbps connection. The average&nbsp;Indian&nbsp;home bandwidth is not more then 512 kbps to 1 Mbps.<br />&nbsp;</span></li><li><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Not many users are aware of Android platform or apps in India.(Though the number of the Android users is increasing in India.)</span></li></ul><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">I guess from an Indian perspective we still have a lot to catch up before we can even think of having Google TV in India. We need to have better DTH/Video-on-demand services and good TV guides/mobile applications to make user aware of the importance of having such services in India.</span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Let's wait and watch. What say??</span><br /><br /></div></div></div></div></div>
	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
