<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>/TechnoTravel-in/</title>
   
   <link>/TechnoTravel-in/</link>
   <description>The daily source of digital inspirations</description>
   <language>en-in</language>
   
   <title>
   <![CDATA[ TechnoTravel.in ]]>
   </title>
   <description>
   <![CDATA[ The daily source of digital inspirations ]]>
   </description>
   <link>/TechnoTravel-in/</link>
   <image>
   <url>/TechnoTravel-in/assets/images/favicon.ico</url>
   <title>TechnoTravel.in</title>
   <link>/TechnoTravel-in/</link>
   </image>
   <generator>Jekyll 3.6.2</generator>
   <lastBuildDate></lastBuildDate>
   <atom:link href="/TechnoTravel-in/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
   <ttl>60</ttl>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Remotely Flash Files onto Your Android via RemoteFlash [App]</title>
	  <link>/TechnoTravel-in/remotely-flash-files-onto-your-android</link>
		
				
						<author>Rajat Patel</author>
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
	  <pubDate>2013-06-09T08:16:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/TechnoTravel-in/remotely-flash-files-onto-your-android</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on">As a frequent flasher or ROMs, Mods and Kernels, I know the pain of losing out the USB cable only a couple minutes ago before Flashing "commence"!!&nbsp;Then there’s the trial and error process that comes with testing new themes, mods, and ROMs. However, this can all be avoided simply with&nbsp;RemoteFlash. The remote flashing app developed by XDA-Developers member <a href="http://forum.xda-developers.com/showthread.php?t=2307677" target="_blank">Prl91</a>.<br /><br />RemoteFlash allows you to flash ROMS, Mods, and Updates directly from your computer, over WiFi. As of the moment it only allows one file to be flashed at a time. The limit will be raised as the development goes on, but for the time being, RemoteFlash just about serves our purpose.&nbsp;<div><br /></div><div>Though one "downside" you might consider here is that this app uses "OpenRecoveryScript". So that if you have TWRP [TeamWin Recovery Project], then you are good to go, but the users with CWM [ClockWorkMod] Recovery installed might not have the smooth ride. Though&nbsp;CWM may be usable depending on the build installed.</div><div><br />To use RemoteFlash simply download two files at the end of this post. One is a standalone Java application that you run on your computer. The other file is the RemoteFlash apk. After downloading and installing both programs, run the RemoteFlash apk. You will only need to run the app once. After opening RemoteFlash the first time just reboot your device.</div><div><br /></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-FDAheKADpmQ/UbQ4fAYMWZI/AAAAAAAAB1w/-E6qFGpUehU/s1600/Screenshot_2013-06-09-13-02-40.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="400" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-FDAheKADpmQ/UbQ4fAYMWZI/AAAAAAAAB1w/-E6qFGpUehU/s400/Screenshot_2013-06-09-13-02-40.png" width="225" /></a></div><div><br /></div><div>As soon as your device boots back up, RemoteFlash service will be running in background. You can then open the PC client and click "Auto-Scan"(It may take anywhere between a second and two minutes to find your device), check/uncheck "Wipe Data/Cache", and click "Go".&nbsp;</div><div><br /></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-KBwarw_gwWU/UbQ4tlFd0CI/AAAAAAAAB14/1ygf5ozM1Ms/s1600/09-06-2013+01-13-59+PM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-KBwarw_gwWU/UbQ4tlFd0CI/AAAAAAAAB14/1ygf5ozM1Ms/s1600/09-06-2013+01-13-59+PM.png" /></a></div><div><br /></div><div><br /></div><div>You will then be prompted to select a file, and it will be flashed directly to your device.</div><div><br /></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-J3jKOoG06a4/UbQ4y4ojtLI/AAAAAAAAB2A/EtNBroUHJJY/s1600/09-06-2013+01-27-46+PM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-J3jKOoG06a4/UbQ4y4ojtLI/AAAAAAAAB2A/EtNBroUHJJY/s1600/09-06-2013+01-27-46+PM.png" /></a></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><br /></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: left;">After the flashing starts, the file will be downloaded and flashed automatically onto your device!!</div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: left;"><br /></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-XJns2qWqFlY/UbQ5tJGi3SI/AAAAAAAAB2Q/iH9d929YOe8/s1600/Screenshot_2013-06-09-13-24-55%5B1%5D.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="400" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-XJns2qWqFlY/UbQ5tJGi3SI/AAAAAAAAB2Q/iH9d929YOe8/s400/Screenshot_2013-06-09-13-24-55%5B1%5D.png" width="225" /></a></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: left;"><br /></div><h3 style="text-align: left;">Downloads</h3><div style="text-align: left;"><ul style="text-align: left;"><li><a href="https://www.box.net/shared/9p4srm7e4wodsoal4dkb" target="_blank">RemoteFlashPC-V0.3.jar</a></li><li><a href="https://www.box.net/s/8tg94szvm6aywz1o5oyv" target="_blank">RemoteFlashV0.7.apk</a></li></ul>[Source : <a href="http://forum.xda-developers.com/showthread.php?t=2307677" target="_blank">xda-developers</a>]</div></div>
	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>How To Add "Command Prompt Here" Menu In Folder Right Click Menu</title>
	  <link>/TechnoTravel-in/how-to-add-command-prompt-here-menu-in-folder-right-click-menu</link>
		
				
						<author>Rajat Patel</author>
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
	  <pubDate>2012-11-20T06:57:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/TechnoTravel-in/how-to-add-command-prompt-here-menu-in-folder-right-click-menu</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-0ha89vgz4KA/UKsnZpeSuWI/AAAAAAAABZs/z9lMYLnSuXs/s1600/20-11-2012+11-45-37+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-0ha89vgz4KA/UKsnZpeSuWI/AAAAAAAABZs/z9lMYLnSuXs/s1600/20-11-2012+11-45-37+AM.png" /></a></div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Well, there is a rather unknown or "only known to the geeks" shortcut of holding shift key while right clicking on any folder shows up the option "Open Command Prompt Here.."..but I bet 90% of us didn't knew that before they read it here. Now, as we geeks are considered to be laziest person on earth (In terms of physical work, of course!), we're going to prove that right here right now.</span><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Now coming back to the topic, here we've tweaked the registry entries for our goods to remove that "holding shift" barrier to show up "Open Command Prompt Here.." option in the folder right click menu. After editing the registry as mentioned in this post, there is no need to press shift key to have this option. It'll be enabled by default. :cool:</span><br /><h3 style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Manual Method</span></h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">The first method must be the manual method. Because if I provide one-click solution here, we geeks are too lazy to read the whole article, I guess. So, first we'll see how it's done manually and then an automatic gift will be presented!</span><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">First go to start menu and type regedit.</span><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-L0fotn7avgw/UKsnlIz4fYI/AAAAAAAABZ0/aLxvIZlS5cg/s1600/20-11-2012+11-49-22+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-L0fotn7avgw/UKsnlIz4fYI/AAAAAAAABZ0/aLxvIZlS5cg/s1600/20-11-2012+11-49-22+AM.png" /></a></div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Click on regedit.exe which will open Registry Editor.</span><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Now navigate to the following folder :&nbsp;</span><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><b>HKEY_CLASSES_ROOT\Drive\shell\cmd</b></span>&nbsp;</blockquote><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-hf0o9MRuDvc/UKsnxjCyIhI/AAAAAAAABZ8/MvPzZ3wPS9A/s1600/20-11-2012+11-54-55+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-hf0o9MRuDvc/UKsnxjCyIhI/AAAAAAAABZ8/MvPzZ3wPS9A/s1600/20-11-2012+11-54-55+AM.png" /></a></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div>Rename the “Extended” key on the right to something else, like “Extended-Orig”. (Note that you could simply delete the value, but renaming it ensures that you can quickly rename it back to reverse the change)<br /><br />To add the item to the folder context menu, browse down to the following key:</span><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><b>HKEY_CLASSES_ROOT\Directory\shell\cmd</b></span></blockquote><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"> And rename the same “Extended” key here. The changes should be immediate.</span><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/--5VgFofikpI/UKsoJ8Ac-RI/AAAAAAAABaE/ET4dfAO15bg/s1600/20-11-2012+11-55-31+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/--5VgFofikpI/UKsoJ8Ac-RI/AAAAAAAABaE/ET4dfAO15bg/s1600/20-11-2012+11-55-31+AM.png" /></a></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Download This Registry Tweak</span></h3><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">If you are not good at these sought of geeky stuff, just download the following file. There are two files in the downloaded zip, namely,&nbsp;DisableCommandPromptHereAlways.reg and&nbsp;EnableCommandPromptHereAlways.reg.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="https://www.box.net/shared/zx4qo74lwbz3d8w1r3yb">Download EnableCommandPromptHere Registry Tweak (705 Bytes)</a></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Just double click on&nbsp;EnableCommandPromptHereAlways.reg to enable this tweak.&nbsp;</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><i>Note : While you try to open any of these above mentioned registry files, a warning will appear. You should click on "Yes" to proceed further.</i></span></div></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><i><br /></i></span></div></div>
	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>6 Reasons Why Windows 8 Is More Secure Than Windows 7</title>
	  <link>/TechnoTravel-in/6-reasons-why-windows-8-is-more-secure-than-windows-7</link>
		
				
						<author>Rajat Patel</author>
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
	  <pubDate>2012-11-09T08:01:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/TechnoTravel-in/6-reasons-why-windows-8-is-more-secure-than-windows-7</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Official release of Windows 8 is a talk of the town right now. Some think it's just a new visual interface slapped on top of Windows 7, and if you think so, I'm afraid you are wrong!&nbsp;Windows 8 has seen a lot of security improvements, including an inbuilt antivirus, an application reputation system, and protection from boot-time rootkits and viruses/malwares.</span><br /><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">There are quite a few low-level security improvements under the hood as well. Microsoft&nbsp;hasn't&nbsp;spelled out all of them, but Windows 8 manages memory in a more secure way and includes features that make it more secure than Windows 7 and security vulnerabilities harder to exploit.</span><br /><div><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">So, here we're discussing the major security improvements that Windows has seen from transition to Windows 8 from Windows 7. There are 6 of them to be precise, so here we go.</span></div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Windows Defender (An Integrated Antivirus)</span></h3><div><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Finally, yeah finally, Microsoft has come up with an inbuilt or integrated Antivirus solution that ships with any edition of Windows 8. It's named Windows Defender - but it's just a rename of the popular free antivirus Microsoft Security Essentials. It's the same Microsoft Security Essential that you might be using on your Windows 7 PC (If not upgraded to Windows 8 yet!). Though you can any antivirus that you want on your Windows 8 machine. In such scenario, Windows Defender will disable itself automatically in order to avoid any conflicts with the third party antivirus. Though you need not to do so, as Windows Defender is a very capable product that you won't need any third party antivirus. Moreover, it's deeply integrated into the system that ensures that Windows users will finally have an integrated antivirus protection out-of-the-box.</span><br /><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-ZG-xWxl6RP4/UJy2qTWTGNI/AAAAAAAABWg/uk-Wlbno_jc/s1600/image34.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="288" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-ZG-xWxl6RP4/UJy2qTWTGNI/AAAAAAAABWg/uk-Wlbno_jc/s400/image34.png" width="400" /></a></div><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">There is an Anti-Malware Solution As Well</span></h3><div><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">In Windows 8, the booting priority of the antivirus is set higher than any other components. Which means that at boot time, first the antivirus will start and will check drivers for any&nbsp;suspicious malwares. This greatly protects the PC from the rootkit attack that starts before antivirus and hide from them.&nbsp;Windows Defender starts earlier in the boot process out-of-the-box, and third-party antivirus vendors can also add the Early-Launch Anti-Malware (ELAM) feature to their products. </span></div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Secure Boot</span></h3><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">On new Windows 8 computers that use the UEFI firmware instead of the old-style BIOS, Secure Boot guarantees that only specially signed and approved software can run at boot. On current computers, malware could install a malicious boot loader that loads before the Windows boot loader, starting a boot-level rootkit (or “bootkit”) before Windows even launches. The rootkit could then hide itself from Windows and antivirus software, pulling the strings in the background.<br /><br />On Intel x86 PCs, you’ll be able to add your own security keys to the UEFI firmware, so you could even have your system boot only secure Linux boot loaders that you’ve signed.</span><br /><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Improvements in Memory Management</span></h3><div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-hXu1m_mNCgI/UJy3KjfE5bI/AAAAAAAABWo/cLhFN3j_G_4/s1600/pile-of-ram.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="184" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-hXu1m_mNCgI/UJy3KjfE5bI/AAAAAAAABWo/cLhFN3j_G_4/s400/pile-of-ram.jpg" width="400" /></a></div><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">In this area, Microsoft has made many under-the-hood improvements compared to Windows 7 in Windows 8.&nbsp;</span><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">When a security hole is found, these improvements can make the security hole harder or even impossible to exploit. Some types of exploits that function on earlier versions of Windows wouldn’t function at all on Windows 8.</span></div><div><br /></div><span style="color: #444444;"><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Microsoft hasn’t spelled out all of these improvements, but they have mentioned a few:</span></span><br /><ul><li><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Mitigations that were once applied to Windows applications are now also applied to the Windows kernel.</span></li><li><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">ASLR (Address Space Layout Randomization) has been extended to more parts of Windows, randomly moving data and code around in memory to make it harder to exploit.</span></li><li><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Internet Explorer 10 includes improvements that make 75% of the security vulnerabilities reported over the last two years more difficult to exploit.</span></li><li><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">The Windows heap, where Windows applications receive their memory from, includes additional checks to defend against exploit techniques.</span></li></ul><div><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">If you're interested in exploring all the improvements, they <a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/b/b8/archive/2011/09/15/protecting-you-from-malware.aspx">can be found here</a>.</span></div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Sandboxing of The New Apps</span></h3><span style="color: #444444;"><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Apps for Windows 8’s new Modern interface (formerly known as Metro) are sandboxed and restricted in what they can do on your computer.<br /><br />On the Windows desktop, applications had full access to your system. If you downloaded and ran a Windows game, it could install drivers on your system, read files from everywhere on your hard drive, and install malware on your computer. Even if programs&nbsp;run with limited credentials thanks to UAC, they typically install with Administrator privileges and can do anything they want during installation.<br /><br />Windows 8 apps function more like web pages and mobile apps on other popular mobile platforms. When you install an app from the Windows Store, that app has limited access to your system. It can’t run in the background and monitor all your keystrokes, logging your credit card number and online banking passwords like applications on the traditional Windows desktop can. it doesn’t have access to every file on your system.<br /><br />Apps for Windows 8’s new Modern interface are also only available through the Windows Store, which is more controversial. However, users can’t install malicious Modern apps from outside the store. They’d have to go through the Windows Store, where Microsoft has the ability to pull them if they’re discovered to be malicious.</span></span><br /><span style="color: #444444;"><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></span><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-xDxx6SpC0Fc/UJy3rKzTpII/AAAAAAAABWw/wKRWCI-Hd-M/s1600/image35.png" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-xDxx6SpC0Fc/UJy3rKzTpII/AAAAAAAABWw/wKRWCI-Hd-M/s1600/image35.png" /></a></div><span style="color: #444444;"><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></span><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Smartscreen Filter</span></h3><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-L2bA2tQjdgA/UJy35z6TlKI/AAAAAAAABW4/uv-0m-xpI2o/s1600/image47.png" imageanchor="1" style="clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;"><img border="0" height="175" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-L2bA2tQjdgA/UJy35z6TlKI/AAAAAAAABW4/uv-0m-xpI2o/s400/image47.png" width="400" /></a></div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span style="color: #444444;">Previously used only in Internet Explorer, the SmartScreen filter is now implemented at the operating system-level. It will be used to scan EXE files you download from Internet Explorer, Mozilla Firefox, Google Chrome, and other programs. When you download and double-click an EXE file, Windows will scan the file and send its signature to Microsoft’s servers. If the application is known-good, such as the installer for iTunes, Photoshop, or another popular program, Windows will allow it to run. If it’s known-bad, perhaps if it contains malware, Windows will prevent it from running. If it’s new and Windows doesn’t know what it is, Windows will warn you and allow you to bypass the warning.</span><br /><br /><br /><span style="color: #444444;">This feature should help less-experienced users from downloading and running malicious programs from the Internet. Even new pieces of malware will be detected by the SmartScreen filter as an unknown new program that should be approached with caution.</span></span><br /><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span style="color: #444444;"><br /></span></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span style="color: #444444;">So, the conclusion is that Windows 8 is&nbsp;definitely&nbsp;more secure than Windows 7.&nbsp;An integrated antivirus and application reputation system, along with a tamed app ecosystem that replaces the wild-west nature of previous versions of Windows, will probably make the most difference for inexperienced users that may not have ran an antivirus or knew which applications were safe to install on previous versions of Windows. Low-level improvements to the way Windows manages memory will help everyone, even power users like us!</span></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span style="color: #444444;"><br /></span></span></div></div>
	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>How To Check Disk For Errors In Windows [A Complete Guide]</title>
	  <link>/TechnoTravel-in/how-to-check-disk-for-errors-in-windows-a-complete-guide</link>
		
				
						<author>Rajat Patel</author>
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
	  <pubDate>2012-08-26T06:57:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/TechnoTravel-in/how-to-check-disk-for-errors-in-windows-a-complete-guide</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">The <a href="http://www.technotravel.in/2011/08/how-computer-hard-drive-actually-works.html">computer hard disk</a> is the mind of your system which memorize every data about your computer even if it is turned off. In day-to-day basis, we often doesn't take care of it more because it is less prone to errors than the other components of your machine and works almost flawlessly every time. But it is also a mechanical part of your system which might come under the "Error Attack". So here we're discussing about the hard disk errors and the ways to&nbsp;diagnose and prevent them from&nbsp;occurring as well.&nbsp;</span><br /><h3 style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">How Could You Know That Your Disk Is Suffering From Errors?</span></h3><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">There is a nominal reduce in performance which goes unnoticed many times if your disk is suffering from errors. If the amount of errors is large, the transfer speed of your hard drive reduces eventually as the time goes on. The slump in performance might get unnoticed if the your system is equipped with big memory and mighty processor. Which means that if your system is equipped with robust hardware, even a slight performance dip is worth considering!</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">The checking disk of errors is very easy and can be performed by a novice user as well. There are actually two methods to do that. One is for regular users which deals with windows' user interface using Windows Explorer and the other one is more robust but a bit harder (Not for geeky personalities though), using Command Line Interface.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">As the mass community is not-so geeky, we'll first discuss about the easier way using Windows Explorer.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">First of all open "Computer" in Windows Explorer. This will show the drives that are currently connected to your computer.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-vim9kv9iW2s/UDnGBekwRgI/AAAAAAAABR0/c6W0Wrob-O4/s1600/26-08-2012+11-30-34+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-vim9kv9iW2s/UDnGBekwRgI/AAAAAAAABR0/c6W0Wrob-O4/s1600/26-08-2012+11-30-34+AM.png" /></a></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Now Right Click on the drive that you want to check for errors. Click Properties.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-zaFvyNOgUac/UDnGKK3s4JI/AAAAAAAABR8/PDMQfiKfRJU/s1600/26-08-2012+11-33-11+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-zaFvyNOgUac/UDnGKK3s4JI/AAAAAAAABR8/PDMQfiKfRJU/s1600/26-08-2012+11-33-11+AM.png" /></a></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Navigate to Tools tab where you'll find the option to check disk for errors. Click on Check Now (Administrator privileges&nbsp;are required).</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/--Q09ZMHB35c/UDnGRmuyVBI/AAAAAAAABSE/aKixNdr_kfM/s1600/26-08-2012+11-33-38+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/--Q09ZMHB35c/UDnGRmuyVBI/AAAAAAAABSE/aKixNdr_kfM/s1600/26-08-2012+11-33-38+AM.png" /></a></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">The pop-up will come up with two options with the option already checked saying "Automatically fix file system errors" and the other one is "Scan for and attempt recovery of bad errors".</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">The "Automatically fix file system errors" attempts to solve the detected errors automatically on its own. If this option is left unchecked, the Disk Check utility will only check and display errors, but won't solve it.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">If both the options are checked, it will thoroughly check the disk for errors and will also attempt to solve any physical errors on your hard drive if there exists any. Due to such functionality, it is&nbsp;get-able&nbsp;that it will obviously take more time than the regular Disk Checking but it is more accurate as well.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">The time taken by this process depends upon the size of the file it is checking. Means, larger the size of file is, the more time it takes to check.</span></div><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><b>Note</b> If one or more of the files on the hard disk are open, you will receive the following message:</span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Chkdsk cannot run because the volume is in use by another process. Would you like to schedule this volume to be checked the next time the system restarts?</span></blockquote><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-vYUHvuaUmq8/UDnGbGiKZyI/AAAAAAAABSM/TkkPzUwzt1M/s1600/26-08-2012+11-33-59+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-vYUHvuaUmq8/UDnGbGiKZyI/AAAAAAAABSM/TkkPzUwzt1M/s1600/26-08-2012+11-33-59+AM.png" /></a></div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Click on schedule disk check to schedule it on the next reboot.</span><br /><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Using Command Line Interface</span>&nbsp;</h3><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">You can do this above mentioned processes and more with chkdsk.exe utility which runs via command line interface. The command that we'll use is CHKDSK.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><pre><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Syntax<br />      CHKDSK [drive:][[<i>path</i>]<i>filename</i>] [/F] [/V] [/R] [/L[:<i>size</i>]] <br /><br />Key<br />   [<i>drive</i>:]   The drive to check. <br />   <br />   <i>filename</i>   File(s) to check for fragmentation (FAT only). <br />   <br />   /F         Automatically Fix file system errors on the disk.<br /><br />   /X         Fix file system errors on the disk, (Win2003 and above)<br />              dismounts the volume first, closing all open file handles.<br />   <br />   /R         Scan for and attempt Recovery of bad sectors.<br />   <br />   /V         Display the full path and name of every file on the disk. <br />   <br />   /L:<i>size</i>    NTFS only: change the log file size to the specified number of kilobytes. <br />              If size is not specified, displays the current log size and the drive type<br />              (FAT or NTFS).<br /><br />   /C         Skip directory corruption checks. <br /><br />   /I         Skip corruption checks that compare directory entries to the<br />              file record segment (FRS) in the volume's master file table (MFT)</span></pre><pre></pre><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Example:</span></h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">CHKDSK C: /F</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-sfB1dXRmG8I/UDnHUuq8wPI/AAAAAAAABSU/kVxEAhqKxrY/s1600/26-08-2012+12-19-48+PM.png" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-sfB1dXRmG8I/UDnHUuq8wPI/AAAAAAAABSU/kVxEAhqKxrY/s1600/26-08-2012+12-19-48+PM.png" /></a></div><div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Fixing Errors /F</span></h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">If the drive is the boot partition, you will be prompted to run the check during the next boot<br /><br />If you specify the /f switch, chkdsk will show an error if open files are found on the disk.<br /><br />Chkdsk /f will lock the volume, making data unavailable until chkdsk is finished.<br /><br />If you use chkdsk /f on a disk with a very large number of files (millions), chkdsk may take a long time to complete.<br /><br />When you delete a file or folder that has 'custom' permissions, the ACL is not deleted, it is cached. Chkdsk /f will remove ACLs that are no longer used. This is often the cause of the rather worrying message: "Windows found problems with the file system. Run chkdsk with the /F (fix) option to correct these."<br /><br />It is normal for chkdsk /F to remove unused index entries and unused security descriptors every time you run it, these do not indicate a problem with the file system. </span><br /><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Scan only (without /f switch)</span></h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">If a file needs to be fixed chkdsk will alert you with a message but will not fix the error(s). </span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br />chkdsk may report lost allocation units on the disk - it will produce this report even if the files are in-use (open). If corruption is found, consider closing all files and repairing the disk with /F.<br /><br />Running chkdsk on a data volume that is in use by another program or process may incorrectly report errors when none are present. To avoid this, close all programs or processes that have open handles to the volume.</span><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-yibYpWDXuUs/UDnIR3thgjI/AAAAAAAABSk/4hQL2clJVsk/s1600/26-08-2012+12-20-27+PM.png" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em; text-align: center;"><img border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-yibYpWDXuUs/UDnIR3thgjI/AAAAAAAABSk/4hQL2clJVsk/s1600/26-08-2012+12-20-27+PM.png" /></a><br />&nbsp;<span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br />On computers running Windows 2003 SP1, chkdsk automatically creates a shadow copy, so you can check volumes that are 'in use' by another program or process. This enables an accurate report against a live file server. On earlier versions of Windows, chkdsk would always lock the volume, making data unavailable.</span><br /><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Run at Bootup</span></h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Running at bootup is often the easiest way to close all open file handles.<br /><br />Use the GUI, chkntfs or the FSUTIL dirty commands to set or query the volumes 'dirty' bit so that Windows will run chkdsk when the computer is restarted.</span><br /><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Event Logs</span></h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Chkdsk will log error messages in the Event Viewer - System Log. <br />Chkdsk /f removes ACLs that are no longer used and reports this in the Event Viewer - Application Log.</span><br /><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Cluster (or block) Size</span></h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">CHKDSK produces a report that shows the the block /cluster size<br />typically: "4096 bytes in each allocation unit." <br />When the cluster size is greater than 4 KB on an NTFS volume, none of the NTFS compression functions are available.</span><br /><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Exit codes</span></h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">0 No errors were found<br />1 Errors were found and fixed.<br />2 Could not check the disk, did not or could not fix errors.</span><br /><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Notes:</span></h3></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Consider the time required to run Chkdsk to repair any errors that occur. Chkdsk times are determined by the number of files on the volume and by the number of files in the largest folder. Chkdsk performance was improved by 30% under Windows 2003 and around 50% in 2008 R2. <br /><br />To issue chkdsk on a hard drive you must be a member of the Administrators group.<br /><br />When CHKDSK is set to run at boot-up there is a delay to allow the check to be cancelled - this can be configured in the registry:<br /><br />HKLM\System\CurrentControlSet\Control\Session Manager<br />REG_DWORD:AutoChkTimeOutData<br />The value is the time in seconds that you want CHKDSK to wait (0 = no delay) default is 10 seconds.<br /><br />Chkdsk is also available from the Recovery Console (with different parameters.)</span><br /><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Disk Errors</span></h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">"The file system structure on the disk is corrupt and unusable"<br /><br />If you have disk corruption, run the drive manufacturers diagnostics: <br /><a href="http://www3.toshiba.co.jp/storage/english/support/index.htm">Toshiba</a> | <a href="http://www.hitachigst.com/portal/site/en/support/">Hitachi</a> | <a href="http://www.pc.ibm.com/ww/hdd/hddredirect.html">ibm</a> | <a href="http://www.seagate.com/www/en-us/support/">Seagate/Maxtor/Freeagent</a> | <a href="http://support.wdc.com/">Western digital</a></span></div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">How To Prevent Disk Errors From Occurring</span></h3><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Well, to fully prevent disks from errors is quite hard task, but you always can take some precautionary measures to reduce the frequency of the&nbsp;occurrence of such errors.</span></div><div><ul><li><b style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Don't ever directly cut the power supply from hard disk.</b><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"> When the hard disk is on and under full operation, the sudden power cuts can hurt your hard disk big times! So prevent your PC from sudden power cuts, which is the only thing that is in our hands to reduce the frequency of error occurrence.</span></li><li><b style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Frequently check and fix disk for errors.</b><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"> Use any one of the above mentioned method at least one a month to let your disk operate smoothly.</span></li></ul></div><div><br /></div></div>
	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>15 Top Free Websites To Backup And Share Your Data On The Cloud</title>
	  <link>/TechnoTravel-in/15-top-free-websites-to-backup-and-share-your-data-on-the-cloud</link>
		
				
						<author>Rajat Patel</author>
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
	  <pubDate>2012-08-20T06:18:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/TechnoTravel-in/15-top-free-websites-to-backup-and-share-your-data-on-the-cloud</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-McsYNYawaME/UDHWAUhyBqI/AAAAAAAABRM/LYhX9HRxYaU/s1600/cloud_storage_2_web_0.png" imageanchor="1" style="clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-McsYNYawaME/UDHWAUhyBqI/AAAAAAAABRM/LYhX9HRxYaU/s1600/cloud_storage_2_web_0.png" /></a></div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Well, backups are essential and we've been told many times how important they are, although we may not pay attention to it until it's too late and we lose all our data! Though you can always backup your important data on your external physical hard drive,&nbsp;but free online backup services provide useful redundancy that could save your data big time!</span><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">If you are a regular TechnoTravel.in reader, you may get this now that we're fan of <a href="http://www.technotravel.in/2012/08/pros-and-cons-of-cloud-basedonline-antivirus.html">cloud computing</a> and we will be writing numerous articles in coming future to let the world understand it's pros and cons. So, as a part of that effort, here we're mentioning out some useful and FREE websites, 15 to be precise, that offer free cloud storage space to let you backup, share or synchronize your data. Each of these services offers a free plan, most also having options for paid subscriptions that offer more storage space, and possibly additional features. Most of these services offer useful backup features such as automatic backups, scheduling, versioning, and restore features. Some services offer other useful features, such as the ability to access your backed up files anywhere using a browser or mobile apps and the ability to stream your media files to your mobile device.</span><br /><h3 style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Microsoft SkyDrive</span></h3><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="http://windows.microsoft.com/en-US/skydrive/home" target="_blank">Microsoft SkyDrive</a> offers 7GB of free data for the new subscribers. It used to offer 25GB in its initial stages, but now it's reduced down to 7GB. Though 7GB is also a good cloud storage space. The old subscribers, like me, are allowed to keep their 25GBs for free.</span></div><div><br /></div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Store your files on SkyDrive and you can access them from your Android phone, iPhone, iPad, Windows phone in addition to your PC or Mac.&nbsp;Use SkyDrive to share large files and photos with your friends and family. They only need a web browser to access the files and photos.</span><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Though there are some drawbacks of SkyDrive that are worth mentioning here. Firstly, it&nbsp;doesn't&nbsp;offer any considerable security to the files you upload, so if you are about to upload your sensitive data on SkyDrive, stop here. The other drawback is that it offers only one folder named SkyDrive, thus if you have data sorted out in many folders, you might find it difficult to upload it on SkyDrive.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">With 7 GB of free storage, SkyDrive is a good place to store your photos and other non-sensitive documents. Use other free backup services for your sensitive and private files. We mention which ones provide encryption for files uploaded to and retrieved from their service.</span><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-9Eick34xGX4/UDHSVClEmVI/AAAAAAAABPU/Pr2qfk2ov9s/s1600/20-08-2012+10-05-48+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-9Eick34xGX4/UDHSVClEmVI/AAAAAAAABPU/Pr2qfk2ov9s/s1600/20-08-2012+10-05-48+AM.png" /></a></div><div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Box</span></h3><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="http://www.box.com/" target="_blank">Box</a>&nbsp;is a good backup solution for the small but important files, as it offers 5GB of storage space with the file size limit of 100MB.&nbsp;The free account also allows you to create file sharing links and provides secure transfer and storage of your data. You can access your data anywhere, anytime, on any device, such as a desktop computer, a laptop, an iPhone, an iPad, or an Android device.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Organize your files online using folders just like you would on your desktop PC. Edit your documents online and save them directly back into your Box account using your native desktop applications.&nbsp;Use Box to share large files easily, rather than trying to email big files, such as videos or presentations.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">If you need more than 5 GB of storage space, you can <a href="https://www.box.com/pricing/">upgrade your account</a> to 25 GB of space for $9.99 per month, or 50 GB of space for $19.99 per month. Both of these plans also increases the maximum file size to 1 GB. Business and Enterprise plans are also available.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-zAi1Hd63YG8/UDHSuhHtm0I/AAAAAAAABPc/gzy0f6a9Yo4/s1600/20-08-2012+10-20-16+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-zAi1Hd63YG8/UDHSuhHtm0I/AAAAAAAABPc/gzy0f6a9Yo4/s1600/20-08-2012+10-20-16+AM.png" /></a></div><div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">ADrive</span></h3><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="http://www.adrive.com/" target="_blank">ADrive</a> offers a personal basic plan that offers 50GB of free cloud storage and features allows you to&nbsp;backup, share, access, and edit your data from anywhere you have Internet access.&nbsp;</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Share large files with family and friends using ADrive’s File Sharing feature. You can get a unique link for a file you want to share in an email. Simply email that link to anyone with whom you want to share that file. If you don’t want to share a file anymore, you can “unshare” it as well.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">You can also edit your word processing documents, spreadsheets, and presentations online. Open, edit, and save your documents directly from within your ADrive account online.<br /><br />Use ADrive’s convenient search tool to find files you want to access or restore without having to browse through all your directories and files.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-RCP22X90_Uk/UDHS4THnIkI/AAAAAAAABPk/Fmq_OVvTJwE/s1600/20-08-2012+10-19-05+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-RCP22X90_Uk/UDHS4THnIkI/AAAAAAAABPk/Fmq_OVvTJwE/s1600/20-08-2012+10-19-05+AM.png" /></a></div><div><div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Comodo Backup</span></h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="http://backup.comodo.com/">Comodo Backup</a> offers 5 GB of free online backup space and a free, lifetime license. Backup your data to  Stream music and videos from and edit documents directly in your online account.<br /><br />Files you choose to backup are encrypted before they leave your computer and are stored encrypted on Comodo’s servers or other storage media you select. You can backup to a network drive, an external hard drive, CD or DVD, ISO file, .zip file, or online storage.<br /><br />Schedule any combination of full, incremental, differential, and synchronized backups to run at a time of your choosing using their flexible scheduler.<br /><br />Files in use are backed up using Volume Shadow Copy technology.<br /><br />Access your files from any computer with an internet connection using their web interface.<br /><br />If you need more storage space, you can <a href="http://backup.comodo.com/download-buy.php">purchase 250 GB</a> for $9.99 per month. You can get two months for free by purchasing one year in advance for $99.99.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-lhPvl2J431o/UDHTEdOLQRI/AAAAAAAABPs/9b76jzAVXJc/s1600/20-08-2012+11-07-57+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-lhPvl2J431o/UDHTEdOLQRI/AAAAAAAABPs/9b76jzAVXJc/s1600/20-08-2012+11-07-57+AM.png" /></a></div><div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">MyOtherDrive</span></h3><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="http://www.myotherdrive.com/" target="_blank">MyOtherDrive</a> offers 2 GB of free cloud storage. With a free account, you get unmetered bandwidth, unattended, or automatic, backup, and AES 128-bit encryption and HTTPS (SSL) connections.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-xYCgTzORlEM/UDHTSsMl8oI/AAAAAAAABP0/zR8hIE0j1H8/s1600/20-08-2012+11-09-22+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-xYCgTzORlEM/UDHTSsMl8oI/AAAAAAAABP0/zR8hIE0j1H8/s1600/20-08-2012+11-09-22+AM.png" /></a></div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">BuddyBackup</span></h3><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="http://www.buddybackup.com/" target="_blank">Buddy Backup</a> has an interesting concept. It allows you to&nbsp;backup your data to your friends, families, and colleague’s computers for free. All backed up files are encrypted locally before they are sent to your buddies’ machines and only you have the encryption keys. So, your buddies can’t read your files.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">You don’t have to worry about your backups staying on your buddies’ computers. You can setup BuddyBackup to backup multiple copies of your files, so you’re sure you have backups. Two copies of your data are spread among your buddies by default. BuddyBackup also regularly checks that your buddies still have your backups. If there is a problem on a buddy’s computer, BuddyBackup automatically backs up your files to a different buddy instead. So, if one of your buddies uninstalls BuddyBackup or their computer fails, your data is still safe</span><span style="color: #333333; font-family: Verdana;"><span style="font-size: 14px; line-height: 17px;">.</span></span><br /><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">You can also backup your data offline to your own external hard drives.<br /><br />If your computer crashes and you have to restore your data to a new computer, you can easily do so by running BuddyBackup on your new computer. You can also recover your files from a friend’s computer, if you haven’t replaced your computer yet, using the Guest Mode. In Guest Mode, you can’t add to backups; you can only restore files from existing backups.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-EJGH6RQiPcM/UDHTf24_H6I/AAAAAAAABP8/_XQN8FSazLY/s1600/20-08-2012+11-11-28+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-EJGH6RQiPcM/UDHTf24_H6I/AAAAAAAABP8/_XQN8FSazLY/s1600/20-08-2012+11-11-28+AM.png" /></a></div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">DropBox</span></h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="https://www.dropbox.com/pricing">Dropbox</a> offers 2 GB of storage for free, and the ability to sync files and folders between your Windows, Mac, or Linux computer and the cloud. Use the desktop client or the web interface to add your files and folders to the Dropbox folder. Once in the Dropbox folder, the files are synced among the PC, the cloud, and any other devices enabled with Dropbox, including mobile devices like phones and tablets.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-P4h_lohISKo/UDHTpvYLUII/AAAAAAAABQE/IVvc5Fm7xEQ/s1600/20-08-2012+11-13-32+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-P4h_lohISKo/UDHTpvYLUII/AAAAAAAABQE/IVvc5Fm7xEQ/s1600/20-08-2012+11-13-32+AM.png" /></a></div><div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">SpiderOak</span></h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="https://spideroak.com/">SpiderOak</a> offers 2 GB of secure, free storage space for online backups, synchronization, sharing, remote access, and storage of your files from unlimited Windows, Mac OS X, and Linux (Ubuntu, Debian, Fedora, and openSUSE) computers and locations, such as USB flash drives, external hard drives, and network drives.</span></div><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">ShareRooms are password-protected locations on SpiderOak’s servers that allow you to securely share files gathered from multiple machines with others. Any data in a ShareRoom is updated automatically when changes are made, and a notification of the changes is sent out as an RSS feed.<br /><br />Apps for Android and iOS devices are provided that allow you to access your data from anywhere. You can view, watch, or listen to any file in your SpiderOak account, visit ShareRooms, share files, and download files to your device for offline access.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-aa2-7qqRkMQ/UDHTzlDPrRI/AAAAAAAABQM/1NWG4PvKTks/s1600/20-08-2012+11-14-43+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-aa2-7qqRkMQ/UDHTzlDPrRI/AAAAAAAABQM/1NWG4PvKTks/s1600/20-08-2012+11-14-43+AM.png" /></a></div><div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">MozyHome Free</span></h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="http://mozy.com/home/free">MozyHome Free</a> offers 2 GB of storage for free along with the option to add more storage space through a paid subscription. Clients for PC and Mac are available for download that you can set up to perform fully automated backups. Select folders to be backed up, set a schedule, and Mozy will keep a backup of these folders online, regularly syncing them without interaction from you. Mozy also provides military-grade encryption prior to transfer using a secure SSL connection.<br /><br />Once you perform your initial backup of your files, Mozy saves bandwidth by only backing up new or changed portions of files, helping to speed up future backups. Mozy also backs up all open and locked files, such as Outlook PST files. You can schedule backups to happen while your computer is on but not in use. Backups can occur daily or weekly at a specific time of day.<br /><br />When you need to restore your data, you can choose to do so using the software client, on the web, or by ordering a DVD to restore. If you’re using Windows, you can also restore your data using the right-click context menu or through the Mozy Virtual Drive. You can restore file versions up to 30 days into the past.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-rwA86PAdYmY/UDHT_OQKyMI/AAAAAAAABQU/Yi9i8FTs1j8/s1600/20-08-2012+11-16-36+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-rwA86PAdYmY/UDHT_OQKyMI/AAAAAAAABQU/Yi9i8FTs1j8/s1600/20-08-2012+11-16-36+AM.png" /></a></div><div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">MiMedia</span></h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="http://www.mimedia.com/">MiMedia</a> offers 7 GB of storage space for free, and features such as secure, automatic online backup and cloud sync. Access your files from anywhere and stream your music and videos and view your photos using MiMedia’s free iPhone and iPad apps. Easily share your photos, videos, and files and post to your favorite social networks.<br /><br />Unlike some other online backup services, MiMedia allows you to backup from any number of computers and devices, such as a laptop, desktop computer, external hard drives, network drives, and more.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-alF-agGJ1sY/UDHULrgcJmI/AAAAAAAABQc/UARiR_BIDOU/s1600/20-08-2012+11-17-55+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-alF-agGJ1sY/UDHULrgcJmI/AAAAAAAABQc/UARiR_BIDOU/s1600/20-08-2012+11-17-55+AM.png" /></a></div><div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Google Drive</span></h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="https://drive.google.com/start?authuser=0#home">Google Drive</a> offers 5 GB of storage for free. Store files online, share them with family and friends, and edit your documents online using Google Docs from your PC or Mac, iPhone, iPad, Android device, and from Chrome OS. View any of over 30 file types on your PC using your browser, without having the program installed on your computer.<br /><br />There are special apps on the Chrome Web Store that allow you to create, open, and share files directly in Google Drive.<br /><br />Search for your files on Google Drive by keyword, and filter by file type, owner, and more. Google Drive’s search feature can even find text in scanned documents and objects in images.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-DmyqP6ugLQQ/UDHUXrp-arI/AAAAAAAABQk/Vs1xakCbvzc/s1600/20-08-2012+11-19-13+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-DmyqP6ugLQQ/UDHUXrp-arI/AAAAAAAABQk/Vs1xakCbvzc/s1600/20-08-2012+11-19-13+AM.png" /></a></div><div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">SugarSync</span></h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="https://www.sugarsync.com/">SugarSync</a> also offers 5 GB of storage space for free. You can use SugarSync not only as an online backup service, but also as a way to sync your files, such as music and photos, among your computers and other devices, such as your Android device, iPhone, iPad, BlackBerry, and Kindle Fire. SugarSync can be handy if you need to transfer files between a PC and a Mac.<br /><br />Just like Mozy, you can backup your data from any folders on your hard drive. You can also select folders to share with your friends and family. You can edit files on your computer while it’s offline, and the changed files are quietly synced with SugarSync the next time your computer is online without interfering with your productivity.<br /><br />SugarSync keeps the previous five versions of all your files so you can reference or restore them in the future. Only the most recent version of each file counts against your storage limit.<br /><br />If you just want to backup a set of files without automatically syncing them or updating them, you can use SugarSync’s Web Archive feature. Everything stored in the Web Archive is accessible from the web and your mobile devices.<br /><br />SugarSync offers mobile apps for devices such as Android, iPad, iPhone, iPod Touch, BlackBerry, and Windows Mobile. You can access files backed up to your SugarSync account from any of your other computers, share photos, upload files and photos of any size from your mobile device to your computer (even if it’s turned off), and even edit documents, depending upon the capabilities of your device.<br /><br />Data uploaded to and retrieved from SugarSync’s servers are sent over the Internet using TLS (SSL 3.3) encryption. Every piece of information moved between your computers, mobile devices, and SugarSync’s servers is verified as a secure communication, whether you are backing up files to their servers or restoring files from them. You can also protect folders you share with other people, such as clients or coworkers.<br /><br />SugarSync offers some handy features for transferring music and photos between your mobile devices and your computers. You can also stream music to your mobile device. For Android devices and iPhones, you can sync your music to your phone so you can listen to it offline. Share a large video file by sending a link to the file rather than sending an email with a large attachment.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-DKUPEZuvOu4/UDHUit9xr7I/AAAAAAAABQs/B6M5dmFB0ek/s1600/20-08-2012+11-20-46+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-DKUPEZuvOu4/UDHUit9xr7I/AAAAAAAABQs/B6M5dmFB0ek/s1600/20-08-2012+11-20-46+AM.png" /></a></div><div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">ElephantDrive</span></h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="http://home.elephantdrive.com/plans-and-pricing/free-plans/">ElephantDrive’s Lite Edition</a> plan offers 2 GB of free online backup space and has all the features of ElephantDrive’s premium plans, including automatic online storage and backup, military-grade encryption, and support for up to three computers or devices. You can also access your data from any internet-enabled device and share files and photos with a single click.<br /><br />One advantage of ElephantDrive’s service is their “Web Explorer.” It allows you to access and upload files using a web browser anywhere you have internet access. You do not have to wait until you have access to an approve device using proprietary software.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-uf9dsPkRSac/UDHUui3tU6I/AAAAAAAABQ0/iNSoCpLnRdw/s1600/20-08-2012+11-23-30+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-uf9dsPkRSac/UDHUui3tU6I/AAAAAAAABQ0/iNSoCpLnRdw/s1600/20-08-2012+11-23-30+AM.png" /></a></div><div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">CrashPlan</span></h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="http://www.crashplan.com/">CrashPlan</a> offers the ability to backup your data to multiple destinations for free (for personal backup). You can backup using your own computers and external hard drives for onsite backups, as well as backup your data to computers belonging to your friends and family for offsite backup.<br /><br />CrashPlan’s backup software runs on PCs, Macs, Linux, and Solaris and backs up data from any combination of these operating systems and from attached hard drives, as well. Backups happen automatically so you don’t have to remember to backup your data or get annoyed from popup dialogs reminding you to perform a backup. You can schedule your backups if you want to control when they are performed. If a backup is interrupted, it is resumed the next time the computers become available again.<br /><br />When you backup data to multiple destinations, your data is sent to one destination one at a time. To make sure you have a full backup as soon as possible, the order of your backups is based on which destination will complete first.<br /><br />With the free version of CrashPlan, your files are secured before they are transferred to CrashPlan’s servers using enterprise-grade, 128-bit encryption. Paid plans provide 448-bit encryption.<br /><br />There are no limitations on the size of files you can backup.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-m8Op9OAwbC4/UDHU9LdRdZI/AAAAAAAABQ8/t1vwlLVwGXg/s1600/20-08-2012+11-25-23+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-m8Op9OAwbC4/UDHU9LdRdZI/AAAAAAAABQ8/t1vwlLVwGXg/s1600/20-08-2012+11-25-23+AM.png" /></a></div><div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Ubuntu One</span></h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="https://one.ubuntu.com/">Ubuntu One</a> allows you to sync up to 5 GB of files to the cloud for free and access it anywhere. It may seem like it’s only for Ubuntu Linux machines, but you can also sync your Windows computer to Ubuntu One account. They offer apps for Android and iOS devices that let you manage your files and photos directly from your mobile device.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-7OGgbbnea9g/UDHVL7nnnLI/AAAAAAAABRE/WHNLOq0LfwQ/s1600/20-08-2012+11-27-11+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-7OGgbbnea9g/UDHVL7nnnLI/AAAAAAAABRE/WHNLOq0LfwQ/s1600/20-08-2012+11-27-11+AM.png" /></a></div><div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">If you don't want to shell out any money on paid cloud storage, then you always can sign up on the multiple websites above to have yourself a decent amount of cloud storage to go with for free. If you sign up for all the above mentioned cloud storage websites, you'll avail yourself as good as 100GB (approx) of cloud storage, which is&nbsp;humongous indeed! However, you must not forget which file is stored at which place, otherwise it can be a headache!!</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif; font-size: xx-small;">Top Image Courtesy : <a href="http://www.savageio.com/page/cloud-storage-backup-services" target="_blank">Savageio.com</a></span></div><div><br /></div></div></div></div>
	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>What is OpenDNS? Why You Absolutely Need It To Stay Secure and Protected?</title>
	  <link>/TechnoTravel-in/what-is-opendns-why-you-absolutely-need-it-to-stay-secure-and-protected</link>
		
				
						<author>Rajat Patel</author>
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
	  <pubDate>2012-08-14T06:36:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/TechnoTravel-in/what-is-opendns-why-you-absolutely-need-it-to-stay-secure-and-protected</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-z7mYAXIUzTA/UCnwYrCBqFI/AAAAAAAABNo/0OtquudE6pg/s1600/common-sprite+(1).png" imageanchor="1" style="clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-z7mYAXIUzTA/UCnwYrCBqFI/AAAAAAAABNo/0OtquudE6pg/s1600/common-sprite+(1).png" /></a></div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Well, instead of diving into OpenDNS thing&nbsp;straight&nbsp;away, we believe you might want to have a look at what DNS actually is? DNS is the abbreviated form of the term "Domain Name Server" (You can actually replace Server with Service or System as well!).</span><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">The primary job of the DNS server is providing the ip address of the different websites to your computer. Which means, when you type www.google.com or www.yahoo.com in your browser address bar, your computer actually queries the DNS server which it is configured to use. In response to that query DNS server returns the ip address of that queried website, in this case say www.google.com. Thus DNS server will return the ip address of www.google.com's server. With the help of this ip address, your computer can finally reach to Google.com. Thus there is an important role of DNS server to let you access the internet from your PC.</span><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">No matter what operating system you use, say <a href="http://www.technotravel.in/search/label/windows">Windows</a>, <a href="http://www.technotravel.in/search/label/Linux">Linux</a> or <a href="http://www.technotravel.in/search/label/iOS">Mac</a>, your computer have to have DNS server configured to be able to access the Internet. Now, by default, your ISP (Internet Service Provider) has their own DNS server in most cases. Thus up till now, if you haven't changed your DNS server ever, then you surely are running your ISP's DNS server.</span><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Unfortunately, your DNS server can be the weakest link in the entire Internet Workflow. In a easy language, no matter how speedy or robust your internet link is, if the DNS server of your ISP is faulty or say tad slow, it can ruin your browsing experience. If the DNS server of your ISP is slow, it takes more time to reply to the query sent by your computer, resulting in the slowness of the rendering of the webpage. And in India, ISPs seems not to be too concerned about having a robust DNS server. Which means, even if your ISP provides you the speed of 2Mbps, it can feel like 1Mbps if your DNS server is running slow!</span><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">To solve this problem,</span><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">We can always opt for any other DNS server which is faster and equipped with more robust features than your ISP's DNS server. There are plenty of fast DNS servers to choose from to use for your computer, but we like OpenDNS the most.</span><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="http://www.opendns.com/" target="_blank">OpenDNS</a> is a dedicated DNS servers. Which directly means that the developer staff at OpenDNS is only focused on making their DNS server faster and more reliable, nothing else. OpenDNS dramatically speeds up your internet connection and also enhances your overall internet experience as you'll get this after reading the full post.</span><br /><h3 style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">How To Get Started?</span></h3><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">There is no need of any software or registration to avail yourself the benefits of OpenDNS. All you need to do is to change your computer's DNS servers with the following ip addresses:</span></div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><ul><li>208.67.222.222&nbsp;</li><li>208.67.220.220</li></ul>Don't know how to change your computer's DNS server? <a href="http://www.technotravel.in/2011/08/how-to-change-dns-servers-for-fast.html" target="">Here</a> is the guide that might help you! <a href="http://www.technotravel.in/2011/08/how-to-change-dns-servers-for-fast.html" target="">How To Change DNS Server in Windows</a></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">The whole process takes a few seconds but with this single step alone, you just made your computer safer and increased the overall browsing speed. Here's why: </span><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Unlike the DNS servers of your less reliable ISP, OpenDNS servers store the IP addresses of millions of websites in their cache so it would take less time to resolve your requests. So if you have asked for an IP address of a website that has been previously requested by another OpenDNS user, you will get the reply instantly.</span><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-oaBfZRblaSg/UCnxP8vAgUI/AAAAAAAABNw/6HbthGSKPuQ/s1600/opendns.gif" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-oaBfZRblaSg/UCnxP8vAgUI/AAAAAAAABNw/6HbthGSKPuQ/s1600/opendns.gif" /></a></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Another huge advantage of OpenDNS is that it prevents phishing sites that has ability to steal your important passwords from loading in your computer. Thus OpenDNS does the job which your normal antivirus can't do.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">The another very good&nbsp;feature&nbsp;is Parental Control. If you enable this, you can actually prevent your kids from accessing porn sites using OpenDNS shield! There are another plenty of features included in the OpenDNS like Solving Typo Errors, Shortcuts for your favorite sites and many more.</span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-s3RfsaRLXqM/UCnxeNMyVYI/AAAAAAAABN4/O6GX8lE3mD0/s1600/14-08-2012+11-37-25+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-s3RfsaRLXqM/UCnxeNMyVYI/AAAAAAAABN4/O6GX8lE3mD0/s1600/14-08-2012+11-37-25+AM.png" /></a></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Thus in many ways, OpenDNS is a very useful and easy to set-up DNS server to enhance your overall internet browsing experience.</span></div><div><br /></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">So why wait? Get started here&nbsp;<a href="http://www.opendns.com/">www.opendns.com</a></span></div><div><br /></div></div>
	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>How To Use Internet Explorer Inside Google Chrome with IE Tab Extension</title>
	  <link>/TechnoTravel-in/how-to-use-internet-explorer-in-google-chrome-with-ie-tab-extension</link>
		
				
						<author>Rajat Patel</author>
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
	  <pubDate>2012-08-09T16:53:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/TechnoTravel-in/how-to-use-internet-explorer-in-google-chrome-with-ie-tab-extension</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-q57Wi6nJKZg/UCPo45TDzpI/AAAAAAAABIY/RaOBWtF1kZE/s1600/chrome-logo-2011-04-27.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-q57Wi6nJKZg/UCPo45TDzpI/AAAAAAAABIY/RaOBWtF1kZE/s1600/chrome-logo-2011-04-27.jpg" /></a></div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Though the Internet Explorer domination from the browser market is over, we still need it to view some Internet Explorer only sites that doesn't support the&nbsp;modern and crowd favorite browsers like <a href="http://www.technotravel.in/search/label/Google%20Chrome" target="_blank">Chrome</a>, <a href="http://www.technotravel.in/search/label/Mozilla%20Firefox" target="_blank">Firefox</a> or Opera. So even Chrome users may have to head over to Internet Explorer to open such Internet Explorer Friendly websites&nbsp;sometimes. To solve this issue, here we've found a very useful extension named IE Tab, which virtually opens up the Internet Explorer inside the Chrome window.</span><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">IE Tab for Chrome is actually invented by the makers of IE Tab for Firefox, which actually emulates the Internet Explorer window in Google Chrome. It can be configured to launch IE based websites directly from the extension that you won't need to even think about heading over to actual Internet Explorer installation on your PC. Though you can't remove Internet Explorer because this extension uses the resources of Internet Explorer installed on your machine. So, don't forget to keep your Internet Explorer up-to-date so that we can be assured of full-proof security.</span><br /><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">What Are The Uses Of It?</span></h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">As mentioned earlier, The IE Tab uses the resources from the actual Internet Explorer installation that resides in your Windows. So if you are using the OS other than Windows, say MacOS or Linux, this extension will not work. If we ignore this limitation, it has many usages:</span><br /><ul><li><b><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Web Development</span></b><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">&nbsp;– View web pages in IE 7, IE 8, or IE 9 mode.</span></li><li><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><b>IE-Only Websites</b> – Load IE-only websites within Google Chrome.</span></li><li><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><b>Outlook Web Access &amp; Sharepoint</b> – Use features that only work in IE.</span></li><li><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><b>ActiveX Controls</b> – Run ActiveX Controls, which is an IE-only technology</span></li></ul><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">How To Use IE Tab</span></h3><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Well, installation is very simple. It is same as any other chrome extension installation. Just head over to <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/hehijbfgiekmjfkfjpbkbammjbdenadd" target="_blank">IE Tab Page of Chrome Web Store</a> and install the extension by clicking "Add to Chrome". It will download and install automatically. When the installation is finished, you'll see the logo containing Internet Explorer at the Extension Bar beside the Wrench Menu of <a href="http://www.technotravel.in/search/label/Google%20Chrome" target="_blank">Google Chrome</a>. Click it to open the Internet Explorer inside Chrome.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-OE2Sv0_lVB8/UCPqE_uT7NI/AAAAAAAABIg/wZ-lQPRg0VM/s1600/09-08-2012+10-12-02+PM.png" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-OE2Sv0_lVB8/UCPqE_uT7NI/AAAAAAAABIg/wZ-lQPRg0VM/s1600/09-08-2012+10-12-02+PM.png" /></a></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">It will open up the currently open tab in the IE Mode. In this screenshot, I had <a href="http://google.com/">google.com</a> already opened, so it opened <a href="http://google.com/">google.com</a> in IE mode. You can browse normally as you would from Internet Explorer. Just enter the URL in the newly created address bar and it will open as if it is opening in the Internet Explorer.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">IE Tab doesn’t integrate perfectly with Chrome – each IE tab frame has its own address bar. To bookmark a page, click the bookmark icon on the IE Tab toolbar. IE Tab will create a bookmark and save it to the “IE Tab” folder on your bookmarks toolbar. When clicked, the bookmark will load the current page in an IE Tab.</span><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">You can tell it’s using Internet Explorer because it isn’t rendering TechnoTravel.in properly. (To be fair, the drop-down menu works properly when IE Tab is set to IE 9 mode, but it uses IE 7 compatibility mode by default.</span><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Advanced Features</span></h3><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">The IE Tab is feature-rich in terms of emulating the Internet Explorer. Just click on the Settings button of the IE Tab Bar to go to the settings page that will let you configure your IE Tab. It is fill with lot of features. Here are the details.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">First of all there are some General Options that needs no&nbsp;explanations!</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-8rGP01QuWrY/UCPqYOq8RgI/AAAAAAAABIo/dQFRpiFEJgA/s1600/09-08-2012+09-53-11+PM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-8rGP01QuWrY/UCPqYOq8RgI/AAAAAAAABIo/dQFRpiFEJgA/s1600/09-08-2012+09-53-11+PM.png" /></a></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Then there is the Auto URL feature. As the name suggest, you can configure to render particular website or link directly from IE Tab, so that you won't need to care to reload that particular website in the IE Tab. It will get captured by the IE Tab automatically.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-6IxUHvyc3cg/UCPqfla69KI/AAAAAAAABIw/0gVBSLm3mds/s1600/09-08-2012+09-53-37+PM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-6IxUHvyc3cg/UCPqfla69KI/AAAAAAAABIw/0gVBSLm3mds/s1600/09-08-2012+09-53-37+PM.png" /></a></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">If there exist some URLs from the Auto URLs that you still want to load via chrome, then you can do that as well. Just add that particular URL in&nbsp;</span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Auto URL Exceptions to serve your cause.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-n2AEZrf-RAs/UCPqmZUDQ3I/AAAAAAAABI4/sUSDgDi-TFM/s1600/09-08-2012+09-53-56+PM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-n2AEZrf-RAs/UCPqmZUDQ3I/AAAAAAAABI4/sUSDgDi-TFM/s1600/09-08-2012+09-53-56+PM.png" /></a></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">There is another interesting feature called IE Compatibility Mode that will load the pages with the IE mode that you want to emulate from. It supports variety of IE modes. By default, IE mode 7 is&nbsp;chosen.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-U7nsRqaumCw/UCPqsKJbo0I/AAAAAAAABJA/_rshrXPW8YA/s1600/09-08-2012+09-54-10+PM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-U7nsRqaumCw/UCPqsKJbo0I/AAAAAAAABJA/_rshrXPW8YA/s1600/09-08-2012+09-54-10+PM.png" /></a></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Do you still wanna use the Internet Explorer instead of this extension? Or have you find any bug that bothers you to do so? Then comment it out to let us know what you feel.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div></div>
	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Pros And Cons Of Cloud Based/Online Anti-Virus</title>
	  <link>/TechnoTravel-in/pros-and-cons-of-cloud-basedonline-antivirus</link>
		
				
						<author>Rajat Patel</author>
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
	  <pubDate>2012-08-07T17:09:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/TechnoTravel-in/pros-and-cons-of-cloud-basedonline-antivirus</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><table cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="float: right; margin-left: 1em; text-align: right;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-3vdOaBcHcaI/UCFJvx5-udI/AAAAAAAABE8/tbS7jK8sPDA/s1600/7557181168_91f4af2d99_n.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="180" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-3vdOaBcHcaI/UCFJvx5-udI/AAAAAAAABE8/tbS7jK8sPDA/s320/7557181168_91f4af2d99_n.jpg" width="320" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">Image Courtesy : <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/61423903@N06/7557181168/" target="_blank">Flickr</a> by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/61423903@N06/" target="_blank">FutUndBeidl</a></td></tr></tbody></table><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">It seems like we're living in the cloud world as more and more apps that we use in a day-to-day life are migrating&nbsp;themselves&nbsp;to the cloud these days. Email, chatting, Office solutions, pictures - almost every thing is using cloud-based solutions these days. And even Antiviruses can't be excluded from this list. There are several online or cloud-based antivirus solutions available on the internet that can scan your computer from the internet browser. But, though online antiviruses are useful, they can't replace the Antivirus that resides in your computer hard drive.</span><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Nevertheless, cloud-based antivirus applications offer a number of benefits and can be very useful for quickly scanning a PC for malware. But just don’t make them your only form of protection!</span><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><b>What Are Cloud Based Antiviruses?</b></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">If you want to access these cloud based antiviruses, all you need is a browser window and a working internet connection. There are plenty antiviruses available like - <a href="http://quickscan.bitdefender.com/" target="_blank">BitDefender Quick Scan</a> and <a href="http://www.eset.com/us/online-scanner/" target="_blank">ESET Online Sacnner</a> - these are cloud based antiviruses that will serve you well. Some antiviruses will download small .exe files to your computer to run the scan and some will use ActiveX controls to run the virus scanner in the browser window right away.</span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-4DVGvNFhs9g/UCFJ-CVTYBI/AAAAAAAABFE/EaJAUn5lcP4/s1600/07-08-2012+10-17-30+PM.png" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="256" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-4DVGvNFhs9g/UCFJ-CVTYBI/AAAAAAAABFE/EaJAUn5lcP4/s320/07-08-2012+10-17-30+PM.png" width="320" /></a></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">In the case of ESET Online Scanner - it will prompt you to download the .exe file to carry out the quick scan on your PC.&nbsp;Bitdefender QuickScan installs a browser extension.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">After you launch the cloud-based antivirus, it will scan your system for potential threats and alert you to them. Depending on the cloud-based antivirus, it may not remove viruses it finds, or it may only perform a quick scan for viruses and other malware, not an in-depth one.</span><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><b><br /></b></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><b>Lack Of Real-Time Scanning</b></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">The biggest drawback of the online antivirus is its&nbsp;inability to monitor your PC in real-time. Though some people might feel that the online security is the one and only threat nowadays and preventing viruses penetrating in their PC through Internet will assure the full security to their computer, then I'm afraid you're wrong here. There are plenty different threats - Viruses, Trojans or Spywares - that have ability to penetrate through the USB drives and damage your computer big time. So it's always advisable to use a well-known native Antivirus on your PC that supports Real-time scanning to help you detect and prevent from such threats.&nbsp;</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">If you are thinking cloud antiviruses as the one and only protection method to&nbsp;prevent&nbsp;your computer from threats, then I advise you to think twice before making such decision only due to the reason explain above - Lack of Real-Time Scanning.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><b>Some Other Limitations of Cloud Antiviruses</b></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Some online antiviruses don’t even perform the functions you might expect from an antivirus. For example, ESET Online Scanner can scan your entire system for malware and quarantine it. However, Bitdefender QuickScan just scans your system’s startup files and memory for viruses – it doesn’t look for dormant viruses hiding elsewhere on your system. If Bitdefender QuickScan finds a virus, it won’t remove it for you – it will recommend you download a full Bitdefender product to remove the virus.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><b>Though There are Some Benefits Too!</b></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Even though Online Virus Scanning Tools might not fancy their chance to be your primary antivirus, there lies some benefits of them that are worth mentioning here.</span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-sbeLK3iJpY4/UCFKQXHf9dI/AAAAAAAABFM/9i3Qg36wftQ/s1600/07-08-2012+10-23-28+PM.png" imageanchor="1" style="clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;"><img border="0" height="197" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-sbeLK3iJpY4/UCFKQXHf9dI/AAAAAAAABFM/9i3Qg36wftQ/s320/07-08-2012+10-23-28+PM.png" width="320" /></a></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><ul><li><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><b>Quick Scanning</b> : Even though it's named as "Quick Scan", the Quick Scan from our native antivirus can take ages if you've lot of stuff loaded on your computer. The Online Antiviruses wins the race here as they scans quickly using the shared Cloud resources that uses robust hardware. So the scan time will always remain low compared to the native Antivirus.</span></li><li><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><b>Great Second Option</b> : As they are speedy, when we've hardly any time to perform a quick scan on our PC, these Online Antiviruses comes in handy. As they are lightening quick, it'll definitely respond quicker than its native counterpart which lies in your machine with less quicker resources!</span></li><li><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><b>Always Up-To-Date</b> : As they are hosted on cloud, one would imagine them to be up-to-date with the latest virus definitions that can really help you detect the newer threat that can easily give a slip to your not-so up-to-date native antivirus.</span></li></ul></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Some people might think how they can use both antiviruses at the same time? Well, there may occur some conflict if you use two antiviruses on a same PC, which they share the resources which results in a conflict. But in the case of Online Antiviruses, as it uses the resources from cloud, there is no reason to worry about any sought of conflict in here!</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><b>Conclusion</b></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-NL-xiRrxWVA/UCFKqPZ17RI/AAAAAAAABFU/u_zr7GiOwJc/s1600/07-08-2012+10-19-24+PM.png" imageanchor="1" style="clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;"><img border="0" height="195" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-NL-xiRrxWVA/UCFKqPZ17RI/AAAAAAAABFU/u_zr7GiOwJc/s320/07-08-2012+10-19-24+PM.png" width="320" /></a></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><b><br /></b></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">As there are more robust and feature rich antiviruses available for free for your PC, there is no need to treat the cloud based antivirus as your primary antivirus. There are quite a few Antiviruses that are available for free like <a href="http://windows.microsoft.com/en-US/windows/products/security-essentials" target="_blank">Microsoft Security Essentials</a> (my personal favorite), <a href="http://www.avast.com/free-antivirus-download" target="_blank">avast!</a> and <a href="http://free.avg.com/ww-en/homepage" target="_blank">AVG</a>.</span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Though there is always good to have a option or two, especially when you're stuck in the worst case scenario, these Online Antiviruses will always come to the rescue!</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div></div>
	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>How To Access Folders Of Your Android On Your PC via FTP</title>
	  <link>/TechnoTravel-in/how-to-access-folders-of-your-android-on-your-pc-via-ftp</link>
		
				
						<author>Rajat Patel</author>
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
	  <pubDate>2012-08-06T06:20:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/TechnoTravel-in/how-to-access-folders-of-your-android-on-your-pc-via-ftp</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-c5lXw4qx5nk/UB9eBBYQi6I/AAAAAAAABCY/IlQgcbvqFQc/s1600/06-08-2012+10-48-30+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-c5lXw4qx5nk/UB9eBBYQi6I/AAAAAAAABCY/IlQgcbvqFQc/s1600/06-08-2012+10-48-30+AM.png" /></a></div><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">You can always access the folders of your Android phone on your PC via third party app named <a href="http://www.technotravel.in/2012/06/wirelessly-operate-your-android-from.html" target="_blank">AirDroid</a> from your browser. But what if you want to access these folders in the Windows Explorer wirelessly? You can always connect your Android to your PC via USB cable, but here we're more focused on the use of Wi-Fi to prevent you from the&nbsp;hassle of carrying USB cable wherever you might go.&nbsp;</span><br /><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">In this scenario, all we need is a wireless protocol to access them. We've earlier talked about&nbsp;</span><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="http://www.technotravel.in/2012/08/how-to-access-folders-from-your-windows-pc-and-stream-videos-over-wifi-on-your-android.html">How To Access Folders From Your Windows PC and Stream Videos Over Wi-Fi On Your Android</a>&nbsp;which uses SMB (Samba) protocol to access the folders, and moreover it's a reverse process of what we're gonna discuss here. So, the only famous protocol left for our cause is the File Transfer Protocol or FTP. Via FTP you can easily access the folders of your Android onto your PC irrespective of operating system on your machine as we believe FTP is supported by most Operating Systems.</span><br /><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><b>Start FTP Server On Your Android</b></span><br /><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">To serve this purpose we'll use the popular, user-friendly, free and feature-rich <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.estrongs.android.pop" target="_blank">ES File Explorer</a>. If you haven't tested it yet then click the link to <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.estrongs.android.pop" target="_blank">download it from Google Play</a>. According to me, it's a must have app for each and every Android user.</span><br /><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">After the installation, open up ES File Explorer and goto Settings. Scroll down until you find a menu called Remote Access.</span><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-DFY8YR2eqlg/UB9fwav_lhI/AAAAAAAABCg/mztjLUMNfLg/s1600/Screenshot_2012-08-06-10-44-48.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-DFY8YR2eqlg/UB9fwav_lhI/AAAAAAAABCg/mztjLUMNfLg/s1600/Screenshot_2012-08-06-10-44-48.png" /></a></div><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Click on it as you'll see a checkbox named Remote Manage. Just check it as you'll find the ftp address of your newly made FTP server which is hosted on your Android. There is a link with the port address in the comment area of that menu entry. Just remember it or type it on a notepad. Thus your FTP server on Android is up and running.</span><br /><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><b>How To Access Folders via Windows Explorer</b></span><br /><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">It's pretty easy over here. Make sure your PC and Android are connected over Wi-Fi. Now just open Windows Explorer window and click the address bar to type the address of the ftp server. E.g <i>ftp://ip address:port</i> which is in my case <i>ftp://192.168.43.1:3127/</i>. Just type this and hit Enter.</span><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-laF8vGYf0wM/UB9g4NBD68I/AAAAAAAABCo/szsy881ojTA/s1600/06-08-2012+11-38-56+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-laF8vGYf0wM/UB9g4NBD68I/AAAAAAAABCo/szsy881ojTA/s1600/06-08-2012+11-38-56+AM.png" /></a></div><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Now you can see the folders of your phone on your PC as if it is connected via USB cable.</span><br /><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><b>How To Access Folders via Browser</b></span><br /><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">If your browser supports FTP (Most browser does!), then just type the link ftp://192.168.x.x:xxxx into the address bar of the browser and you can access folders of your phone on your browser.</span><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-hwtzNyN9m9Q/UB9hhehPaMI/AAAAAAAABCw/Uiwc3_sQn5g/s1600/06-08-2012+10-54-39+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-hwtzNyN9m9Q/UB9hhehPaMI/AAAAAAAABCw/Uiwc3_sQn5g/s1600/06-08-2012+10-54-39+AM.png" /></a></div><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">We've used our favorite Chrome for this purpose. But you are free to use the browser of your choice. Just make sure it supports FTP.</span><br /><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div>
	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>How To Access Folders From Your Windows PC and Stream Videos Over Wi-Fi On Your Android</title>
	  <link>/TechnoTravel-in/how-to-access-folders-from-your-windows-pc-and-stream-videos-over-wifi-on-your-android</link>
		
				
						<author>Rajat Patel</author>
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
	  <pubDate>2012-08-05T05:19:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/TechnoTravel-in/how-to-access-folders-from-your-windows-pc-and-stream-videos-over-wifi-on-your-android</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-f6NS0BjATLg/UB3-s4GE1sI/AAAAAAAAA-w/n8g0zSBfqf4/s1600/Screenshot_2012-08-05-09-46-55.png" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="360" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-f6NS0BjATLg/UB3-s4GE1sI/AAAAAAAAA-w/n8g0zSBfqf4/s640/Screenshot_2012-08-05-09-46-55.png" width="640" /></a></div><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Do you want to play videos of your Windows PC on your Android without going through the process of copying it to your phone? Well, you can do that easily. Share the particular folder that contains videos over the network and you are good to go. Here is the detailed process.</span><br /><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><br /><span style="color: #444444;"><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Android does not&nbsp;naively support the access to the shared Windows folders or Homegroup, but it can be set up easily enough. We've talked earlier about how to&nbsp;<a href="http://www.technotravel.in/2012/06/wirelessly-operate-your-android-from.html">Wirelessly Operate Your Android From Your Favorite Browser with AirDroid</a>,</span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">&nbsp;which supports the reverse process but it can't be used for streaming over Wi-Fi, so we have found another option that will let you stream your computer's videos on to your phone over Wi-Fi.</span></span><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span style="color: #444444;"><br /></span></span><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><b>How To Share a Folder On Windows</b></span><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span style="color: #444444;"><br /></span></span><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span style="color: #444444;">To make a particular folder visible/shared to everyone, you'll need to share it to "Everyone".</span></span><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span style="color: #444444;"><br /></span></span><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span style="color: #444444;">To do so, navigate to that folder and click "Share" and click on "Specific People..".</span></span><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-UCAHdtvgedo/UB3_H5NIXKI/AAAAAAAAA-4/jyRWOlLT190/s1600/05-08-2012+10-01-32+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-UCAHdtvgedo/UB3_H5NIXKI/AAAAAAAAA-4/jyRWOlLT190/s1600/05-08-2012+10-01-32+AM.png" /></a></div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span style="color: #444444;"><br /></span></span><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span style="color: #444444;">From the dropdown menu, select "Everyone" and click "Add".</span></span><br /><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Now, by default "Everyone" will have only "Read" support. But if you want full read and write support, then select "Read/Write" from dropdown. After choosing the&nbsp;appropriate option, click on "share".</span><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-_6c-5VPHVdo/UB3_ZuahP1I/AAAAAAAAA_A/9Bq5RS2ejoY/s1600/05-08-2012+10-02-40+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-_6c-5VPHVdo/UB3_ZuahP1I/AAAAAAAAA_A/9Bq5RS2ejoY/s1600/05-08-2012+10-02-40+AM.png" /></a></div><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><br /><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Now click on "next" and you are all set to access this shared folder! (Turning On sharing might take a while if you are doing it for the first time.)</span><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-HdmlKnvUvZM/UB3_j5D7ltI/AAAAAAAAA_I/iCka93UMsdg/s1600/05-08-2012+10-03-52+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-HdmlKnvUvZM/UB3_j5D7ltI/AAAAAAAAA_I/iCka93UMsdg/s1600/05-08-2012+10-03-52+AM.png" /></a></div><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><br /><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Next, go to the Network and Sharing Center. Click Start, type "Network and Sharing" and press Enter to quickly open it.</span><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-e3Rnd6P4xD8/UB3_rsjAZwI/AAAAAAAAA_Q/ycv7guXIyAM/s1600/05-08-2012+10-04-47+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-e3Rnd6P4xD8/UB3_rsjAZwI/AAAAAAAAA_Q/ycv7guXIyAM/s1600/05-08-2012+10-04-47+AM.png" /></a></div><div><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">In the Advanced Sharing settings&nbsp;you may want to disable password-protected sharing. If you disable password-protected sharing, only folders you share with "Everyone" will be accessible without a password.<br />&nbsp;</span><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-JxitBK759J0/UB3_0mGqV1I/AAAAAAAAA_Y/DjUWDotmHNA/s1600/05-08-2012+10-05-16+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em; text-align: center;"><img border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-JxitBK759J0/UB3_0mGqV1I/AAAAAAAAA_Y/DjUWDotmHNA/s1600/05-08-2012+10-05-16+AM.png" /></a>&nbsp;<span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br />You can also try leaving password-protected sharing enabled, in which case you'll need to enter user account credentials before connecting to your shared folder on Android. This may work, although I couldn’t get it to work, myself.</span></div><div><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><b>How To Access Shared Folders On Android</b></span></div><div><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">To access these shared folders from Windows, we will be using the robust <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.estrongs.android.pop" target="_blank">ES File Explorer</a>&nbsp;which is a high quality, free file explorer with support for SMB (Samba) Protocol to access the shared folders on Windows. Just what we needed!</span></div><div><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">From ES File Explorer’s main screen, swipe from the right to the left to access the LAN section. You can also tap the Local option at the top left corner of the screen and select LAN in the list.&nbsp;</span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-iMNJDLKPEt4/UB4AWJalywI/AAAAAAAAA_o/kHxeeTXdD_o/s1600/Screenshot_2012-08-05-09-47-13.png" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="360" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-iMNJDLKPEt4/UB4AWJalywI/AAAAAAAAA_o/kHxeeTXdD_o/s640/Screenshot_2012-08-05-09-47-13.png" width="640" /></a></div><div><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Tap the New button on the toolbar in the LAN Shares section and select Scan to scan your network for PCs sharing files.&nbsp;</span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-NXcQ3ffX0p4/UB4AtriGh6I/AAAAAAAAA_w/HV3X9n0FUpw/s1600/Screenshot_2012-08-05-09-48-10.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="640" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-NXcQ3ffX0p4/UB4AtriGh6I/AAAAAAAAA_w/HV3X9n0FUpw/s640/Screenshot_2012-08-05-09-48-10.png" width="360" /></a></div><div><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">You can also tap New and select Server to enter your computer’s IP address manually.&nbsp;</span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-eoFlHeUiJH4/UB4A64_uTHI/AAAAAAAAA_4/AcXcg0lNxQY/s1600/Screenshot_2012-08-05-09-48-41.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="640" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-eoFlHeUiJH4/UB4A64_uTHI/AAAAAAAAA_4/AcXcg0lNxQY/s640/Screenshot_2012-08-05-09-48-41.png" width="360" /></a></div><div><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">After the scan is complete, tap a computer to view its shared files. If ES File Explorer finds your computer but continues scanning for more computers, tap the screen to stop the scan process.</span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-LJz0qWrLrC4/UB4BGBh8LcI/AAAAAAAABAA/sfYEE8Cf1cI/s1600/Screenshot_2012-08-05-09-47-39.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="640" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-LJz0qWrLrC4/UB4BGBh8LcI/AAAAAAAABAA/sfYEE8Cf1cI/s640/Screenshot_2012-08-05-09-47-39.png" width="360" /></a></div><div><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Log in as Anonymous if you disabled password-protected sharing earlier. If you didn’t, try to log in with your Windows username and password – this didn't worked for me though.</span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"></div><div><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Browse to the folder you shared in your computer’s file system. I shared my user account’s Videos folder, so I’d tap Users, tap my user account’s name, and tap Videos.</span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-f6NS0BjATLg/UB3-s4GE1sI/AAAAAAAAA-w/n8g0zSBfqf4/s1600/Screenshot_2012-08-05-09-46-55.png" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="360" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-f6NS0BjATLg/UB3-s4GE1sI/AAAAAAAAA-w/n8g0zSBfqf4/s640/Screenshot_2012-08-05-09-46-55.png" width="640" /></a></div><div><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Tap a video, music file, image, text file, or any other type of file to view it. You can also long-press a file to view a menu and optionally copy it to your device.</span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-Xd0ZYlFSZM4/UB4Brp3OsVI/AAAAAAAABAI/_Jo4RKt8yVg/s1600/Screenshot_2012-08-05-09-50-11.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="640" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-Xd0ZYlFSZM4/UB4Brp3OsVI/AAAAAAAABAI/_Jo4RKt8yVg/s640/Screenshot_2012-08-05-09-50-11.png" width="360" /></a></div><div><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span style="color: #444444;">If the file type is supported by Android, it'll straight away start streaming from the shared folder. Cool isn't it?..I've tested this and all videos streamed like a charm. And now I don't need to copy them to watch on my Galaxy Nexus!!</span></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><br /></div></div>
	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
