<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>/TechnoTravel-in/</title>
   
   <link>/TechnoTravel-in/</link>
   <description>The daily source of digital inspirations</description>
   <language>en-in</language>
   
   <title>
   <![CDATA[ TechnoTravel.in ]]>
   </title>
   <description>
   <![CDATA[ The daily source of digital inspirations ]]>
   </description>
   <link>/TechnoTravel-in/</link>
   <image>
   <url>/TechnoTravel-in/assets/images/favicon.ico</url>
   <title>TechnoTravel.in</title>
   <link>/TechnoTravel-in/</link>
   </image>
   <generator>Jekyll 3.6.2</generator>
   <lastBuildDate></lastBuildDate>
   <atom:link href="/TechnoTravel-in/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
   <ttl>60</ttl>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>15 Top Free Websites To Backup And Share Your Data On The Cloud</title>
	  <link>/TechnoTravel-in/15-top-free-websites-to-backup-and-share-your-data-on-the-cloud</link>
		
				
						<author>Rajat Patel</author>
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
	  <pubDate>2012-08-20T11:48:00+05:30</pubDate>
	  <guid>/TechnoTravel-in/15-top-free-websites-to-backup-and-share-your-data-on-the-cloud</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-McsYNYawaME/UDHWAUhyBqI/AAAAAAAABRM/LYhX9HRxYaU/s1600/cloud_storage_2_web_0.png" imageanchor="1" style="clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-McsYNYawaME/UDHWAUhyBqI/AAAAAAAABRM/LYhX9HRxYaU/s1600/cloud_storage_2_web_0.png" /></a></div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Well, backups are essential and we've been told many times how important they are, although we may not pay attention to it until it's too late and we lose all our data! Though you can always backup your important data on your external physical hard drive,&nbsp;but free online backup services provide useful redundancy that could save your data big time!</span><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">If you are a regular TechnoTravel.in reader, you may get this now that we're fan of <a href="http://www.technotravel.in/2012/08/pros-and-cons-of-cloud-basedonline-antivirus.html">cloud computing</a> and we will be writing numerous articles in coming future to let the world understand it's pros and cons. So, as a part of that effort, here we're mentioning out some useful and FREE websites, 15 to be precise, that offer free cloud storage space to let you backup, share or synchronize your data. Each of these services offers a free plan, most also having options for paid subscriptions that offer more storage space, and possibly additional features. Most of these services offer useful backup features such as automatic backups, scheduling, versioning, and restore features. Some services offer other useful features, such as the ability to access your backed up files anywhere using a browser or mobile apps and the ability to stream your media files to your mobile device.</span><br /><h3 style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Microsoft SkyDrive</span></h3><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="http://windows.microsoft.com/en-US/skydrive/home" target="_blank">Microsoft SkyDrive</a> offers 7GB of free data for the new subscribers. It used to offer 25GB in its initial stages, but now it's reduced down to 7GB. Though 7GB is also a good cloud storage space. The old subscribers, like me, are allowed to keep their 25GBs for free.</span></div><div><br /></div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Store your files on SkyDrive and you can access them from your Android phone, iPhone, iPad, Windows phone in addition to your PC or Mac.&nbsp;Use SkyDrive to share large files and photos with your friends and family. They only need a web browser to access the files and photos.</span><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Though there are some drawbacks of SkyDrive that are worth mentioning here. Firstly, it&nbsp;doesn't&nbsp;offer any considerable security to the files you upload, so if you are about to upload your sensitive data on SkyDrive, stop here. The other drawback is that it offers only one folder named SkyDrive, thus if you have data sorted out in many folders, you might find it difficult to upload it on SkyDrive.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">With 7 GB of free storage, SkyDrive is a good place to store your photos and other non-sensitive documents. Use other free backup services for your sensitive and private files. We mention which ones provide encryption for files uploaded to and retrieved from their service.</span><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-9Eick34xGX4/UDHSVClEmVI/AAAAAAAABPU/Pr2qfk2ov9s/s1600/20-08-2012+10-05-48+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-9Eick34xGX4/UDHSVClEmVI/AAAAAAAABPU/Pr2qfk2ov9s/s1600/20-08-2012+10-05-48+AM.png" /></a></div><div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Box</span></h3><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="http://www.box.com/" target="_blank">Box</a>&nbsp;is a good backup solution for the small but important files, as it offers 5GB of storage space with the file size limit of 100MB.&nbsp;The free account also allows you to create file sharing links and provides secure transfer and storage of your data. You can access your data anywhere, anytime, on any device, such as a desktop computer, a laptop, an iPhone, an iPad, or an Android device.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Organize your files online using folders just like you would on your desktop PC. Edit your documents online and save them directly back into your Box account using your native desktop applications.&nbsp;Use Box to share large files easily, rather than trying to email big files, such as videos or presentations.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">If you need more than 5 GB of storage space, you can <a href="https://www.box.com/pricing/">upgrade your account</a> to 25 GB of space for $9.99 per month, or 50 GB of space for $19.99 per month. Both of these plans also increases the maximum file size to 1 GB. Business and Enterprise plans are also available.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-zAi1Hd63YG8/UDHSuhHtm0I/AAAAAAAABPc/gzy0f6a9Yo4/s1600/20-08-2012+10-20-16+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-zAi1Hd63YG8/UDHSuhHtm0I/AAAAAAAABPc/gzy0f6a9Yo4/s1600/20-08-2012+10-20-16+AM.png" /></a></div><div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">ADrive</span></h3><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="http://www.adrive.com/" target="_blank">ADrive</a> offers a personal basic plan that offers 50GB of free cloud storage and features allows you to&nbsp;backup, share, access, and edit your data from anywhere you have Internet access.&nbsp;</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Share large files with family and friends using ADrive’s File Sharing feature. You can get a unique link for a file you want to share in an email. Simply email that link to anyone with whom you want to share that file. If you don’t want to share a file anymore, you can “unshare” it as well.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">You can also edit your word processing documents, spreadsheets, and presentations online. Open, edit, and save your documents directly from within your ADrive account online.<br /><br />Use ADrive’s convenient search tool to find files you want to access or restore without having to browse through all your directories and files.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-RCP22X90_Uk/UDHS4THnIkI/AAAAAAAABPk/Fmq_OVvTJwE/s1600/20-08-2012+10-19-05+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-RCP22X90_Uk/UDHS4THnIkI/AAAAAAAABPk/Fmq_OVvTJwE/s1600/20-08-2012+10-19-05+AM.png" /></a></div><div><div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Comodo Backup</span></h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="http://backup.comodo.com/">Comodo Backup</a> offers 5 GB of free online backup space and a free, lifetime license. Backup your data to  Stream music and videos from and edit documents directly in your online account.<br /><br />Files you choose to backup are encrypted before they leave your computer and are stored encrypted on Comodo’s servers or other storage media you select. You can backup to a network drive, an external hard drive, CD or DVD, ISO file, .zip file, or online storage.<br /><br />Schedule any combination of full, incremental, differential, and synchronized backups to run at a time of your choosing using their flexible scheduler.<br /><br />Files in use are backed up using Volume Shadow Copy technology.<br /><br />Access your files from any computer with an internet connection using their web interface.<br /><br />If you need more storage space, you can <a href="http://backup.comodo.com/download-buy.php">purchase 250 GB</a> for $9.99 per month. You can get two months for free by purchasing one year in advance for $99.99.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-lhPvl2J431o/UDHTEdOLQRI/AAAAAAAABPs/9b76jzAVXJc/s1600/20-08-2012+11-07-57+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-lhPvl2J431o/UDHTEdOLQRI/AAAAAAAABPs/9b76jzAVXJc/s1600/20-08-2012+11-07-57+AM.png" /></a></div><div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">MyOtherDrive</span></h3><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="http://www.myotherdrive.com/" target="_blank">MyOtherDrive</a> offers 2 GB of free cloud storage. With a free account, you get unmetered bandwidth, unattended, or automatic, backup, and AES 128-bit encryption and HTTPS (SSL) connections.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-xYCgTzORlEM/UDHTSsMl8oI/AAAAAAAABP0/zR8hIE0j1H8/s1600/20-08-2012+11-09-22+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-xYCgTzORlEM/UDHTSsMl8oI/AAAAAAAABP0/zR8hIE0j1H8/s1600/20-08-2012+11-09-22+AM.png" /></a></div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">BuddyBackup</span></h3><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="http://www.buddybackup.com/" target="_blank">Buddy Backup</a> has an interesting concept. It allows you to&nbsp;backup your data to your friends, families, and colleague’s computers for free. All backed up files are encrypted locally before they are sent to your buddies’ machines and only you have the encryption keys. So, your buddies can’t read your files.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">You don’t have to worry about your backups staying on your buddies’ computers. You can setup BuddyBackup to backup multiple copies of your files, so you’re sure you have backups. Two copies of your data are spread among your buddies by default. BuddyBackup also regularly checks that your buddies still have your backups. If there is a problem on a buddy’s computer, BuddyBackup automatically backs up your files to a different buddy instead. So, if one of your buddies uninstalls BuddyBackup or their computer fails, your data is still safe</span><span style="color: #333333; font-family: Verdana;"><span style="font-size: 14px; line-height: 17px;">.</span></span><br /><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">You can also backup your data offline to your own external hard drives.<br /><br />If your computer crashes and you have to restore your data to a new computer, you can easily do so by running BuddyBackup on your new computer. You can also recover your files from a friend’s computer, if you haven’t replaced your computer yet, using the Guest Mode. In Guest Mode, you can’t add to backups; you can only restore files from existing backups.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-EJGH6RQiPcM/UDHTf24_H6I/AAAAAAAABP8/_XQN8FSazLY/s1600/20-08-2012+11-11-28+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-EJGH6RQiPcM/UDHTf24_H6I/AAAAAAAABP8/_XQN8FSazLY/s1600/20-08-2012+11-11-28+AM.png" /></a></div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">DropBox</span></h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="https://www.dropbox.com/pricing">Dropbox</a> offers 2 GB of storage for free, and the ability to sync files and folders between your Windows, Mac, or Linux computer and the cloud. Use the desktop client or the web interface to add your files and folders to the Dropbox folder. Once in the Dropbox folder, the files are synced among the PC, the cloud, and any other devices enabled with Dropbox, including mobile devices like phones and tablets.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-P4h_lohISKo/UDHTpvYLUII/AAAAAAAABQE/IVvc5Fm7xEQ/s1600/20-08-2012+11-13-32+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-P4h_lohISKo/UDHTpvYLUII/AAAAAAAABQE/IVvc5Fm7xEQ/s1600/20-08-2012+11-13-32+AM.png" /></a></div><div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">SpiderOak</span></h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="https://spideroak.com/">SpiderOak</a> offers 2 GB of secure, free storage space for online backups, synchronization, sharing, remote access, and storage of your files from unlimited Windows, Mac OS X, and Linux (Ubuntu, Debian, Fedora, and openSUSE) computers and locations, such as USB flash drives, external hard drives, and network drives.</span></div><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">ShareRooms are password-protected locations on SpiderOak’s servers that allow you to securely share files gathered from multiple machines with others. Any data in a ShareRoom is updated automatically when changes are made, and a notification of the changes is sent out as an RSS feed.<br /><br />Apps for Android and iOS devices are provided that allow you to access your data from anywhere. You can view, watch, or listen to any file in your SpiderOak account, visit ShareRooms, share files, and download files to your device for offline access.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-aa2-7qqRkMQ/UDHTzlDPrRI/AAAAAAAABQM/1NWG4PvKTks/s1600/20-08-2012+11-14-43+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-aa2-7qqRkMQ/UDHTzlDPrRI/AAAAAAAABQM/1NWG4PvKTks/s1600/20-08-2012+11-14-43+AM.png" /></a></div><div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">MozyHome Free</span></h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="http://mozy.com/home/free">MozyHome Free</a> offers 2 GB of storage for free along with the option to add more storage space through a paid subscription. Clients for PC and Mac are available for download that you can set up to perform fully automated backups. Select folders to be backed up, set a schedule, and Mozy will keep a backup of these folders online, regularly syncing them without interaction from you. Mozy also provides military-grade encryption prior to transfer using a secure SSL connection.<br /><br />Once you perform your initial backup of your files, Mozy saves bandwidth by only backing up new or changed portions of files, helping to speed up future backups. Mozy also backs up all open and locked files, such as Outlook PST files. You can schedule backups to happen while your computer is on but not in use. Backups can occur daily or weekly at a specific time of day.<br /><br />When you need to restore your data, you can choose to do so using the software client, on the web, or by ordering a DVD to restore. If you’re using Windows, you can also restore your data using the right-click context menu or through the Mozy Virtual Drive. You can restore file versions up to 30 days into the past.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-rwA86PAdYmY/UDHT_OQKyMI/AAAAAAAABQU/Yi9i8FTs1j8/s1600/20-08-2012+11-16-36+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-rwA86PAdYmY/UDHT_OQKyMI/AAAAAAAABQU/Yi9i8FTs1j8/s1600/20-08-2012+11-16-36+AM.png" /></a></div><div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">MiMedia</span></h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="http://www.mimedia.com/">MiMedia</a> offers 7 GB of storage space for free, and features such as secure, automatic online backup and cloud sync. Access your files from anywhere and stream your music and videos and view your photos using MiMedia’s free iPhone and iPad apps. Easily share your photos, videos, and files and post to your favorite social networks.<br /><br />Unlike some other online backup services, MiMedia allows you to backup from any number of computers and devices, such as a laptop, desktop computer, external hard drives, network drives, and more.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-alF-agGJ1sY/UDHULrgcJmI/AAAAAAAABQc/UARiR_BIDOU/s1600/20-08-2012+11-17-55+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-alF-agGJ1sY/UDHULrgcJmI/AAAAAAAABQc/UARiR_BIDOU/s1600/20-08-2012+11-17-55+AM.png" /></a></div><div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Google Drive</span></h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="https://drive.google.com/start?authuser=0#home">Google Drive</a> offers 5 GB of storage for free. Store files online, share them with family and friends, and edit your documents online using Google Docs from your PC or Mac, iPhone, iPad, Android device, and from Chrome OS. View any of over 30 file types on your PC using your browser, without having the program installed on your computer.<br /><br />There are special apps on the Chrome Web Store that allow you to create, open, and share files directly in Google Drive.<br /><br />Search for your files on Google Drive by keyword, and filter by file type, owner, and more. Google Drive’s search feature can even find text in scanned documents and objects in images.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-DmyqP6ugLQQ/UDHUXrp-arI/AAAAAAAABQk/Vs1xakCbvzc/s1600/20-08-2012+11-19-13+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-DmyqP6ugLQQ/UDHUXrp-arI/AAAAAAAABQk/Vs1xakCbvzc/s1600/20-08-2012+11-19-13+AM.png" /></a></div><div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">SugarSync</span></h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="https://www.sugarsync.com/">SugarSync</a> also offers 5 GB of storage space for free. You can use SugarSync not only as an online backup service, but also as a way to sync your files, such as music and photos, among your computers and other devices, such as your Android device, iPhone, iPad, BlackBerry, and Kindle Fire. SugarSync can be handy if you need to transfer files between a PC and a Mac.<br /><br />Just like Mozy, you can backup your data from any folders on your hard drive. You can also select folders to share with your friends and family. You can edit files on your computer while it’s offline, and the changed files are quietly synced with SugarSync the next time your computer is online without interfering with your productivity.<br /><br />SugarSync keeps the previous five versions of all your files so you can reference or restore them in the future. Only the most recent version of each file counts against your storage limit.<br /><br />If you just want to backup a set of files without automatically syncing them or updating them, you can use SugarSync’s Web Archive feature. Everything stored in the Web Archive is accessible from the web and your mobile devices.<br /><br />SugarSync offers mobile apps for devices such as Android, iPad, iPhone, iPod Touch, BlackBerry, and Windows Mobile. You can access files backed up to your SugarSync account from any of your other computers, share photos, upload files and photos of any size from your mobile device to your computer (even if it’s turned off), and even edit documents, depending upon the capabilities of your device.<br /><br />Data uploaded to and retrieved from SugarSync’s servers are sent over the Internet using TLS (SSL 3.3) encryption. Every piece of information moved between your computers, mobile devices, and SugarSync’s servers is verified as a secure communication, whether you are backing up files to their servers or restoring files from them. You can also protect folders you share with other people, such as clients or coworkers.<br /><br />SugarSync offers some handy features for transferring music and photos between your mobile devices and your computers. You can also stream music to your mobile device. For Android devices and iPhones, you can sync your music to your phone so you can listen to it offline. Share a large video file by sending a link to the file rather than sending an email with a large attachment.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-DKUPEZuvOu4/UDHUit9xr7I/AAAAAAAABQs/B6M5dmFB0ek/s1600/20-08-2012+11-20-46+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-DKUPEZuvOu4/UDHUit9xr7I/AAAAAAAABQs/B6M5dmFB0ek/s1600/20-08-2012+11-20-46+AM.png" /></a></div><div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">ElephantDrive</span></h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="http://home.elephantdrive.com/plans-and-pricing/free-plans/">ElephantDrive’s Lite Edition</a> plan offers 2 GB of free online backup space and has all the features of ElephantDrive’s premium plans, including automatic online storage and backup, military-grade encryption, and support for up to three computers or devices. You can also access your data from any internet-enabled device and share files and photos with a single click.<br /><br />One advantage of ElephantDrive’s service is their “Web Explorer.” It allows you to access and upload files using a web browser anywhere you have internet access. You do not have to wait until you have access to an approve device using proprietary software.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-uf9dsPkRSac/UDHUui3tU6I/AAAAAAAABQ0/iNSoCpLnRdw/s1600/20-08-2012+11-23-30+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-uf9dsPkRSac/UDHUui3tU6I/AAAAAAAABQ0/iNSoCpLnRdw/s1600/20-08-2012+11-23-30+AM.png" /></a></div><div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">CrashPlan</span></h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="http://www.crashplan.com/">CrashPlan</a> offers the ability to backup your data to multiple destinations for free (for personal backup). You can backup using your own computers and external hard drives for onsite backups, as well as backup your data to computers belonging to your friends and family for offsite backup.<br /><br />CrashPlan’s backup software runs on PCs, Macs, Linux, and Solaris and backs up data from any combination of these operating systems and from attached hard drives, as well. Backups happen automatically so you don’t have to remember to backup your data or get annoyed from popup dialogs reminding you to perform a backup. You can schedule your backups if you want to control when they are performed. If a backup is interrupted, it is resumed the next time the computers become available again.<br /><br />When you backup data to multiple destinations, your data is sent to one destination one at a time. To make sure you have a full backup as soon as possible, the order of your backups is based on which destination will complete first.<br /><br />With the free version of CrashPlan, your files are secured before they are transferred to CrashPlan’s servers using enterprise-grade, 128-bit encryption. Paid plans provide 448-bit encryption.<br /><br />There are no limitations on the size of files you can backup.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-m8Op9OAwbC4/UDHU9LdRdZI/AAAAAAAABQ8/t1vwlLVwGXg/s1600/20-08-2012+11-25-23+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-m8Op9OAwbC4/UDHU9LdRdZI/AAAAAAAABQ8/t1vwlLVwGXg/s1600/20-08-2012+11-25-23+AM.png" /></a></div><div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Ubuntu One</span></h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="https://one.ubuntu.com/">Ubuntu One</a> allows you to sync up to 5 GB of files to the cloud for free and access it anywhere. It may seem like it’s only for Ubuntu Linux machines, but you can also sync your Windows computer to Ubuntu One account. They offer apps for Android and iOS devices that let you manage your files and photos directly from your mobile device.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-7OGgbbnea9g/UDHVL7nnnLI/AAAAAAAABRE/WHNLOq0LfwQ/s1600/20-08-2012+11-27-11+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-7OGgbbnea9g/UDHVL7nnnLI/AAAAAAAABRE/WHNLOq0LfwQ/s1600/20-08-2012+11-27-11+AM.png" /></a></div><div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">If you don't want to shell out any money on paid cloud storage, then you always can sign up on the multiple websites above to have yourself a decent amount of cloud storage to go with for free. If you sign up for all the above mentioned cloud storage websites, you'll avail yourself as good as 100GB (approx) of cloud storage, which is&nbsp;humongous indeed! However, you must not forget which file is stored at which place, otherwise it can be a headache!!</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif; font-size: xx-small;">Top Image Courtesy : <a href="http://www.savageio.com/page/cloud-storage-backup-services" target="_blank">Savageio.com</a></span></div><div><br /></div></div></div></div>
	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>All you want to know about Hard Drive Partitions</title>
	  <link>/TechnoTravel-in/all-you-want-to-know-about-hard-drive</link>
		
				
						<author>Rajat Patel</author>
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
	  <pubDate>2011-10-11T12:56:00+05:30</pubDate>
	  <guid>/TechnoTravel-in/all-you-want-to-know-about-hard-drive</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-KGSOS6dgNPI/TpPX2ZV5IcI/AAAAAAAAARU/W7Q3xlCkjNs/s1600/11-10-2011+11-13-03.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img alt="Disk Partitions" border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-KGSOS6dgNPI/TpPX2ZV5IcI/AAAAAAAAARU/W7Q3xlCkjNs/s1600/11-10-2011+11-13-03.png" /></a></div><span class="Apple-style-span" style="background-color: white; line-height: 19px;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><b><br /></b></span></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="background-color: white; line-height: 19px;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><b>Disk partitioning</b>&nbsp;is the act of dividing a&nbsp;hard disk drive&nbsp;into multiple logical storage units referred to as&nbsp;<i>partitions</i>, to treat one physical disk drive as if it were multiple disks. Partitions are also termed "slices" for operating systems based on&nbsp;BSD,&nbsp;Solaris&nbsp;or&nbsp;GNU Hurd. A&nbsp;partition editor&nbsp;software program can be used to create, resize, delete, and manipulate these partitions on the hard disk.</span></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="background-color: white; line-height: 19px;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="background-color: white;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="line-height: 19px;">Nowadays, when the hard drive sizes are increasing&nbsp;unbelievably, every user needs to partition the Hard Disk Drive(HDD) into some partitions according to their needs. All those, who don't know about disk partitioning or the particular disk partitioning method, here is a step-by-step guide divided in several parts to make your mind clear about pros and cons about disk partitioning, for what purposes disk partitioning should be implemented, Disk partition strategies and partitioning the drives with and without third party softwares and much more....</span></span></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="background-color: white;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="line-height: 19px;"><br /></span></span></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="background-color: white;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="line-height: 19px;"><b>What is Disk Partitioning?</b></span></span></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="background-color: white; line-height: 19px;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Disk partitioning is a method used to divide the external or internal Hard Disk Drives (HDDs), to use a single hard drive as multiple drives. As they are shown as a independent drive on the File explorer of your Operating System, after partitioning. All the leading Operating Systems has the native&nbsp;functionality to partition a hard drive. Partitions can also be created and manipulated easily by Third-party partition manager softwares.</span></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="background-color: white;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="line-height: 19px;"><br /></span></span></span><br /><br /><div style="text-align: left;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="background-color: white;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="line-height: 24px;"><b>In which cases I need to partition my Hard Drive?</b></span></span></span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="background-color: white;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="line-height: 24px;">This is a very common question in a computer user that "Do I really need to partition my Hard Drive?". The answer is "Ask yourself that what you gonna do with this Hard Drive or how you gonna use it."</span></span></span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="background-color: white;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="line-height: 24px;"><br /></span></span></span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="background-color: white;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="line-height: 24px;">If you are a computer enthusiast and want to have more than one Operating System (OS) on a single computer, in short, if you want to setup a multi-boot system, then you got to partition your hard drive. Though there exist some other ways like Virtual Hard Drive (VHD), Using Virtual Box, etc. But the&nbsp;simplest&nbsp;and the safest as well as the classical way to setup a multi-boot system is to partition a hard drive into several partitions according to your need of storage and number of partitions you want to setup on a system.</span></span></span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="background-color: white;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="line-height: 24px;"><br /></span></span></span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="background-color: white;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="line-height: 24px;"><b>In which cases I need not to partition my hard drive?</b></span></span></span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="background-color: white;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="line-height: 24px;">If you are not a power user or you just don't want to tweaking your system and if you are happy with the single OS setup, then there is no need to partitioning your hard drive. Even if you have purchased the external hard drive mainly for the backup purposes, then don't bother about partitioning it. Just do what you want, as a single partition will be more efficient and&nbsp;convenient for your needs.&nbsp;</span></span></span></div><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="background-color: white;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="line-height: 19px;"><br /></span></span></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="background-color: white;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="line-height: 19px;"><b>Benefits of Multiple Partitions</b></span></span></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="background-color: white; line-height: 24px;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Creating more than one partition has the following advantages:</span></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="background-color: white; line-height: 19px;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"></span></span><br /><ul style="line-height: 1.5em; list-style-type: square; margin-bottom: 0.5em; margin-left: 1.5em; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0.3em; padding-bottom: 0px; padding-left: 0px; padding-right: 0px; padding-top: 0px;"><li style="margin-bottom: 0.1em;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Separation of the&nbsp;operating system&nbsp;(OS) and program files from user files. This allows&nbsp;image&nbsp;backups&nbsp;(or&nbsp;clones) to be made of only the operating system and installed software.</span></li><li style="margin-bottom: 0.1em;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Having a separate area for operating system&nbsp;virtual memory&nbsp;swapping/paging.</span></li><li style="margin-bottom: 0.1em;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Keeping frequently used programs and data near each other.</span></li><li style="margin-bottom: 0.1em;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Having cache and log files separate from other files. These can change size dynamically and rapidly, potentially making a file system full.</span></li><li style="margin-bottom: 0.1em;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Use of&nbsp;multi-boot&nbsp;setups, which allow users to have more than one operating system on a single computer. For example, one could install&nbsp;Linux,&nbsp;BSD, Mac OS X, Microsoft Windows or other operating systems on different partitions of the same hard disk and have a choice of booting into any compatible operating system at power-up.</span></li><li style="margin-bottom: 0.1em;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Protecting or isolating files, to make it easier to recover a corrupted file system or operating system installation. If one partition is corrupted, other file systems may not be affected.</span></li></ul><ul style="line-height: 1.5em; list-style-type: square; margin-bottom: 0.5em; margin-left: 1.5em; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0.3em; padding-bottom: 0px; padding-left: 0px; padding-right: 0px; padding-top: 0px;"><li style="margin-bottom: 0.1em;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Raising overall computer performance on systems where smaller file systems are more efficient. For instance, large hard drives with only one&nbsp;NTFS&nbsp;file system typically have a very largesequentially accessed&nbsp;Master File Table&nbsp;(MFT) and it generally takes more time to read this MFT than the smaller MFTs of smaller partitions.</span></li><li style="margin-bottom: 0.1em;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">"Short Stroking", which aims to minimize performance-eating head repositioning delays by reducing the number of tracks used per hard drive.&nbsp;The basic idea is that you make one partition approx. 20-25% of the total size of the drive. This partition is expected to: occupy the outer tracks of the hard drive, and offer more than double the throughput — less than half the access time. If you limit capacity with short stroking, the minimum throughput stays much closer to the maximum. This technique, however, is not related to creating multiple partitions, but generally just creating a partition lesser size than available on the disk.</span></li></ul><dl style="margin-bottom: 0.5em; margin-top: 0.2em;"><dd style="line-height: 1.5em; margin-bottom: 0.1em; margin-left: 1.6em;"><ul style="line-height: 1.5em; list-style-type: square; margin-bottom: 0.5em; margin-left: 1.5em; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0.3em; padding-bottom: 0px; padding-left: 0px; padding-right: 0px; padding-top: 0px;"><li style="margin-bottom: 0.1em;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">For example a 1 TB disk might have an access time of 12 ms at 200&nbsp;IOPS&nbsp;(at a limited queue depth) with an average throughput of 100 MB/s. When it is partitioned to 100 GB (and the rest left unallocated) you&nbsp;<i><b>might</b></i>&nbsp;end up with an access time of 6 ms at 300 IOPS (with a bigger queue depth) with an average throughput of 200 MB/s.</span></li></ul></dd></dl><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="background-color: white;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="line-height: 19px;"><br /></span></span></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="background-color: white;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="line-height: 19px;"><b>Disadvantages of multiple partitions</b></span></span></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="background-color: white; line-height: 24px;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Creating more than one partition has the following disadvantages, as compared to having a single partition spanning the same disk area:</span></span><br /><div style="text-align: left;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="background-color: white;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"></span></span></div><ul style="list-style-type: square; margin-bottom: 0.5em; margin-left: 1.5em; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0.3em; padding-bottom: 0px; padding-left: 0px; padding-right: 0px; padding-top: 0px;"><li style="line-height: 1.5em; margin-bottom: 0.1em;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Reduces the total space available for user storage on the disk, as it forces the operating system to duplicate certain file system administration areas on the disk for each partition.</span></li><li style="margin-bottom: 0.1em;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="line-height: 1.5em;">Reduces overall disk performance on systems where data is accessed regularly and in parallel on multiple partitions, because it forces the disk's read/write head to move back and forth on the disk to access data on each partition</span><span class="Apple-style-span" style="line-height: 13px;">&nbsp;</span><span class="Apple-style-span" style="line-height: 1.5em;">and to maintain and update file system administration areas on each partition. It also prevents disk optimizers from moving all frequently accessed files closer to each other on the disk, which could reduce the number and distance of required head movements. Files can still be moved closer to each other on each partition, but those areas themselves will still be far apart on the disk. (See "short stroking" considerations above.) This issue does not apply to SSD drives as access times on those isn't affected by and dependant on relative sector positions.</span></span></li><li style="line-height: 1.5em; margin-bottom: 0.1em;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Increases disk fragmentation because it lowers the average size of continuous free blocks on each partition - as compared to a single partition of the same overall size - after the same amount of data has been written to them.</span></li><li style="line-height: 1.5em; margin-bottom: 0.1em;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">May prevent using the whole disk capacity, because it may break free capacities apart. For example, if you have a disk with two partitions, each with 3 GBs free (hence 6GBs in total), you can't copy a 4GB DVD image file on that disk, because none of the partitions will actually provide enough space for that - even though you have more than enough free capacity in total on the disk. If the same files on those two partitions would have been stored on a single partition spanning the whole disk, then the 4GB file could be easily stored in the 6GB of free space.</span></li><li style="line-height: 1.5em; margin-bottom: 0.1em;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Slows down moving data between different parts of the same physical disk. When moving data from one partition to other, the operating system actually has to copy the contents of the data file, even though it still remains on the same device in a single copy/instance. When using a single partition, moving data between directories will only require altering the file system administration areas, and the actual contents of the file will not be copied or moved inside the disk/device, thus resulting in an indefinitely faster completion of the operation.</span></li><li style="line-height: 1.5em; margin-bottom: 0.1em;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Hurts portability and might impose constraints on how entities might be linked together inside the file system. For ex. the NTFS file system allows&nbsp;hard links&nbsp;to be created only as long as both the link and the referenced file reside inside the same volume/partition. Also under Windows if you're referencing a file on another partition, you can do that only by specifying the partition's assigned drive letter - which, however, might change with time and depending on the drives installed. This renders references invalid and dependent on actual drive letter assignment, which is not an issue if you have to reference files/directories only on the same partition, as in this case you can use directory-relative or root-relative references, without including the drive/partition letter.<br /></span></li></ul><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="line-height: 24px;"><div style="text-align: left;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="background-color: white;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="line-height: 24px;"><br /></span></span></span></div>After reading this article, if you have decided to partition your hard drive, then you may need some assistance on how to partition a hard drive and what are the sizes of the partitions you should keep to match all of your needs (Multi-needs, I should say!). Don't worry, here is the help you may need.</span></span><br /><div style="text-align: left;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="background-color: white;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="line-height: 24px;"><br /></span></span></span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="line-height: 24px;"><a href="http://www.technotravel.in/2011/10/how-to-determine-sizes-of-partitions-of.html">How to determine the sizes of the partitions of Hard Drive [Partitioning Strategy]</a></span></span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="background-color: white;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="line-height: 24px;"><br /></span></span></span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="line-height: 24px;"><a href="http://www.technotravel.in/2011/10/how-to-partition-hard-disk-drive-in.html">[How-To] Partition a Hard Disk Drive in Windows without any software</a></span></span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="line-height: 24px;"><br /></span></span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="line-height: 24px;"><a href="http://www.technotravel.in/2011/10/easeus-partition-master-is-great-free.html">EASEUS Partition Master is a great free to use Disk Partitioning Utility</a></span></span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="background-color: white;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="line-height: 24px;"><br /></span></span></span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="background-color: white;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="line-height: 24px;"><br /></span></span></span></div></div>
	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>How to determine the sizes of the partitions of Hard Drive [Partitioning Strategy]</title>
	  <link>/TechnoTravel-in/how-to-determine-sizes-of-partitions-of</link>
		
				
						<author>Rajat Patel</author>
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
	  <pubDate>2011-10-11T12:56:00+05:30</pubDate>
	  <guid>/TechnoTravel-in/how-to-determine-sizes-of-partitions-of</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-V-zUnJvbVlw/TpPh-L33QPI/AAAAAAAAARk/HL93gLExABA/s1600/640px-Hard_disk_platters_and_head.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img alt="Hard Disk"border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-V-zUnJvbVlw/TpPh-L33QPI/AAAAAAAAARk/HL93gLExABA/s1600/640px-Hard_disk_platters_and_head.jpg" /></a></div><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">If you have finally decided to partition your hard drive into several partitions after reading&nbsp;All you want to know about Hard Drive Partitions, then you are at the right place.&nbsp;</span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">After deciding to partition your hard drive according to your needs, you must have the basic knowledge about the type of partitions as they are very&nbsp;crucial in setting up a multi-boot system, create a back up of your system and for your any other needs.</span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><b>Partition Types of PC&nbsp;</b></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="background-color: white; line-height: 19px;"></span><br /><div style="line-height: 1.5em; margin-bottom: 0.5em; margin-top: 0.4em;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">This section describes the&nbsp;master boot record&nbsp;(MBR) partitioning scheme, as used in&nbsp;DOS,&nbsp;Microsoft Windows&nbsp;and&nbsp;Linux&nbsp;among others on&nbsp;PC compatible&nbsp;computer systems. For examples of partitioning schemes used in other operating systems, see the general article on&nbsp;partition tables.</span></div><div style="line-height: 1.5em; margin-bottom: 0.5em; margin-top: 0.4em;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">The total data storage space of a PC hard disk can be divided into at most four&nbsp;<i>primary partitions</i>, or alternatively three primary partitions and an&nbsp;<i>extended partition</i>. These partitions are described by 16-byte entries that constitute the&nbsp;<i>Partition Table</i>, located in the master boot record.</span></div><div style="line-height: 1.5em; margin-bottom: 0.5em; margin-top: 0.4em;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">The&nbsp;<i>partition type</i>&nbsp;is identified by a 1-byte code found in its partition table entry. Some of these codes (such as&nbsp;<tt>0x05</tt>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<tt>0x0F</tt>) may be used to indicate the presence of an&nbsp;extended partition. Most are used by an operating system's bootloader (that examines partition tables) to decide if a partition contains a file system that can be used to&nbsp;<i>mount / access</i>&nbsp;for reading or writing data.</span></div><h3 style="background-attachment: initial; background-clip: initial; background-color: initial; background-image: none; background-origin: initial; border-bottom-color: initial; border-bottom-style: none; border-bottom-width: initial; color: black; margin-bottom: 0.3em; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px; overflow-x: hidden; overflow-y: hidden; padding-bottom: 0.17em; padding-top: 0.5em; width: auto;"><span class="mw-headline" id="Primary_partition" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif; font-size: small;"><ul style="text-align: left;"><li>Primary Partition<br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-weight: normal; line-height: 24px;">A primary partition contains one file system. In&nbsp;DOS&nbsp;and earlier versions of&nbsp;Microsoft Windows&nbsp;systems, the&nbsp;system partition&nbsp;was required to be the first partition. More recent Windows operating systems (Win7, XP, etc.) can be located on any partition, but the boot files (bootmgr, ntldr, etc.) must be on a primary partition. However, other factors, such as a PC's&nbsp;BIOS&nbsp;(see&nbsp;Boot sequence on standard PC) may also impart specific requirements as to which partition must contain the primary OS.&nbsp;</span><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-weight: normal; line-height: 24px;">The partition type&nbsp;<i>code</i>&nbsp;for a primary partition can either correspond to a file system contained within (e.g.&nbsp;<tt>0x07</tt>&nbsp;means either an&nbsp;NTFS&nbsp;or an OS/2&nbsp;HPFS&nbsp;file system) or indicate that the partition has a special use (e.g. code&nbsp;<tt>0x82</tt>&nbsp;usually indicates a Linux&nbsp;<i>swap</i>&nbsp;partition). The&nbsp;FAT16 and FAT32&nbsp;file systems have made use of a number of partition type codes due to the limits of various DOS and Windows OS versions. Though a Linux operating system may recognize a number of different file systems (ext4,&nbsp;ext3,&nbsp;ext2,&nbsp;ReiserFS, etc.), they have all consistently used the same partition type code:&nbsp;<tt>0x83</tt>&nbsp;(Linux native file system).</span></li></ul></span></h3><dl style="margin-bottom: 0.5em; margin-top: 0.2em; text-align: left;"><ul><dd style="line-height: 1.5em; margin-bottom: 0.1em; margin-left: 1.6em;"><div class="rellink" style="font-style: italic; margin-bottom: 0.5em; padding-left: 2em;"></div></dd><li><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><b>Extended partition</b><span class="Apple-style-span" style="line-height: 24px;">A hard disk may contain only one extended partition; the extended partition can be subdivided into multiple&nbsp;<i>logical partitions</i>. In DOS/Windows systems, each logical partition may then be assigned an additional drive letter.</span></span></li></ul></dl><div style="margin-bottom: 0.5em; margin-top: 0.4em;"><div style="line-height: 1.5em;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="background-color: white; line-height: 19px;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="background-attachment: initial; background-clip: initial; background-color: initial; background-image: none; background-origin: initial; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><b>Partitions' Sizes [Partitioning Strategy]</b></span></span></div><div style="line-height: 1.5em;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="background-color: white; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif; line-height: 19px;">This is the most important part in the process of partitioning to determine the suitable sizes of the partitions. These sizes should be chosen with great care, as it can be very difficult to change in the future, when the data is already stored in it.</span></div><div style="line-height: 1.5em;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="background-color: white; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif; line-height: 19px;"><br /></span></div><div style="line-height: 1.5em;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="background-color: white; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif; line-height: 19px;">It can be illustrated by a simple useful example.</span></div><div style="line-height: 1.5em;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="background-color: white; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif; line-height: 19px;"><br /></span></div><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="line-height: 19px;"><b>Question:</b> I have a 1TB (931 GB) hard drive to play with. And my needs are as following:</span></span><br /><br /><ol style="text-align: left;"><li><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="line-height: 19px;">To setup a dual-boot system. (Windows and Linux)<br />&nbsp;</span></span></li><li><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="line-height: 19px;">To back up my data. (Max 250GB)<br />&nbsp;</span></span></li><li><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="line-height: 19px;">To store movies and media.</span></span></li></ol><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif; line-height: 19px;">These are the basic need of mine. What is the partition strategy?</span></div><div style="margin-bottom: 0.5em; margin-top: 0.4em;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif; line-height: 19px;"><b>Answer: </b>You can partition your hard drive as following:</span></div><div style="margin-bottom: 0.5em; margin-top: 0.4em;"><ol style="text-align: left;"><li><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="line-height: 19px;">150GB partition for Windows<br />&nbsp;</span></span></li><li><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="line-height: 19px;">150GB partition for Linux<br />&nbsp;</span></span></li><li><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="line-height: 19px;">400GB partition for Movies and Media<br />&nbsp;</span></span></li><li><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="line-height: 19px;">Remaining 231GB for Backup &amp; Restore operations</span></span></li></ol><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="line-height: 19px;">If you want to have more data on the Movies &amp; Media section, you may consider it to have 500 or 600 GBs, cutting the size of linux and/or Windows partition to 50GBs, as 50 to 80 GB is enough to have a OS on it!</span></span></div><div style="margin-bottom: 0.5em; margin-top: 0.4em;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="line-height: 19px;"><br /></span></span></div><div style="margin-bottom: 0.5em; margin-top: 0.4em;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="line-height: 19px;">So, after this assistance, if you have decided about the partitions' size and types, you may proceed further to actually partitioning your Hard drive.</span></span></div><div style="margin-bottom: 0.5em; margin-top: 0.4em;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="line-height: 19px;"><br /></span></span></div><div style="margin-bottom: 0.5em; margin-top: 0.4em;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif; line-height: 24px;"><a href="http://www.technotravel.in/2011/10/how-to-partition-hard-disk-drive-in.html">[How To] Partition a Hard Disk Drive in Windows without any software</a></span></div><div style="margin-bottom: 0.5em; margin-top: 0.4em;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif; line-height: 24px;"><br /></span></div><div style="margin-bottom: 0.5em; margin-top: 0.4em;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif; line-height: 24px;"><a href="http://www.technotravel.in/2011/10/easeus-partition-master-is-great-free.html">EASEUS Partition Master is a great free-to-use Disk Partitioning Utility</a></span></div><dl style="margin-bottom: 0.5em; margin-top: 0.2em;"><dd style="line-height: 1.5em; margin-bottom: 0.1em; margin-left: 1.6em;"><div class="rellink" style="font-style: italic; margin-bottom: 0.5em; padding-left: 2em;"><br /><div style="text-align: left;"><br /></div></div></dd></dl></div>
	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>EASEUS Partition Master is a great free-to-use Disk Partitioning Utility</title>
	  <link>/TechnoTravel-in/easeus-partition-master-is-great-free</link>
		
				
						<author>Rajat Patel</author>
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
	  <pubDate>2011-10-11T12:55:00+05:30</pubDate>
	  <guid>/TechnoTravel-in/easeus-partition-master-is-great-free</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-CmKwOU2znQY/TpPsGLFpDzI/AAAAAAAAATM/5oqrgUDGJcg/s1600/09-10-2011+09-32-16.png" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img alt="EASEUS Partition Master : Welcome Screen" border="0" height="400" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-CmKwOU2znQY/TpPsGLFpDzI/AAAAAAAAATM/5oqrgUDGJcg/s640/09-10-2011+09-32-16.png" width="640" /></a></div><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">We have earlier discussed on&nbsp;<a href="http://www.technotravel.in/2011/10/how-to-partition-hard-disk-drive-in.html">[How To] Partition a Hard Disk Drive in Windows without any software</a>. But, if you are not interested in these Geeky stuff, EASEUS Partition Master is a FREE software utility which provides very good partition creation and manipulation&nbsp;functionality to easily manage your partitions.</span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Here is a screenshot of this wonderful and highly user friendly free software.</span><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-3N61gVdXMd8/TpPtKElVyAI/AAAAAAAAATU/Sfe2qr3LJbA/s1600/11-10-2011+12-45-14.png" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img alt="EASEUS Partition Master : Main Screen"border="0" height="475" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-3N61gVdXMd8/TpPtKElVyAI/AAAAAAAAATU/Sfe2qr3LJbA/s640/11-10-2011+12-45-14.png" width="640" /></a></div><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">As the software is so user friendly, that we see no need to explain about it's features. But the one feature that I personally like is the one called "Merge Partitions", It actually merges the partitions without the loss of any data in 99% cases!...It's a great software and I personally use it and surely&nbsp;recommend our readers to use it!</span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Here is the download link:</span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="http://download.cnet.com/Easeus-Partition-Manager-Home-Edition/3000-2248_4-10863346.html">EASEUS Partition Master (Download.com Link)</a></span><br /><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="http://www.partition-tool.com/">Official Site link</a></span><br /><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><b>ALSO SEE [RECOMMENDED]</b></span><br /><ul style="text-align: left;"><li><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="http://www.technotravel.in/2011/10/all-you-want-to-know-about-hard-drive.html">All you want to know about Hard Drive Partitions</a></span></li><li><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif; line-height: 24px;"><a href="http://www.technotravel.in/2011/10/how-to-determine-sizes-of-partitions-of.html">How to determine the sizes of the partitions of Hard Drive [Partitioning Strategy]</a></span></li><li><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif; line-height: 24px;"><a href="http://www.technotravel.in/2011/10/how-to-partition-hard-disk-drive-in.html">[How-To] Partition a Hard Disk Drive in Windows without any software</a></span></li></ul><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-3N61gVdXMd8/TpPtKElVyAI/AAAAAAAAATU/Sfe2qr3LJbA/s1600/11-10-2011+12-45-14.png" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;"><br /></a></div></div>
	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>[How To] Partition a Hard Disk Drive in Windows without any software</title>
	  <link>/TechnoTravel-in/how-to-partition-hard-disk-drive-in</link>
		
				
						<author>Rajat Patel</author>
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
	  <pubDate>2011-10-11T12:35:00+05:30</pubDate>
	  <guid>/TechnoTravel-in/how-to-partition-hard-disk-drive-in</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">We have discussed a lot about Partitioning a hard drive and the partitioning the hard drives in the following posts:</span><br /><br /><ul style="text-align: left;"><li><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="http://www.technotravel.in/2011/10/all-you-want-to-know-about-hard-drive.html">All you want to know about Hard Drive Partitions</a><br />&nbsp;</span></li><li><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="http://www.technotravel.in/2011/10/how-to-determine-sizes-of-partitions-of.html">How to determine the sizes of the partitions of Hard Drive [Partitioning Strategy]</a><br />&nbsp;</span></li><li><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="line-height: 24px;"><a href="http://www.technotravel.in/2011/10/easeus-partition-master-is-great-free.html">EASEUS Partition Master is a great free-to-use Disk Partitioning Utility</a></span></span></li></ul><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="line-height: 24px;">But if you are wondering how to partition a Hard Drive in windows without any third party software, than you are at the right place. Here we are going to discuss on using Windows' native Disk Management utility to partition a Hard drive into your desired partitions.&nbsp;</span></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="line-height: 24px;"><br /></span></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="line-height: 24px;">First of all open "Run" by pressing Windows Key + R (You may use any other method, it will be better to explain it later!). In the run box type "diskmgmt.msc" without quotes. (See the image)</span></span><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-uyhdCmxNKxQ/TpPlBw6eTLI/AAAAAAAAARs/M6yaR6nIJfQ/s1600/11-10-2011+12-10-50.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img alt="diskmgmt.msc" border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-uyhdCmxNKxQ/TpPlBw6eTLI/AAAAAAAAARs/M6yaR6nIJfQ/s1600/11-10-2011+12-10-50.png" /></a></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><br /></div><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="line-height: 24px;">After hitting "OK" you can watch the "Disk Management" window.</span></span><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-N_rMub1WTBM/TpPlk4ca3ZI/AAAAAAAAAR0/z4yKo6kT0Tc/s1600/11-10-2011+12-12-52.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img alt="Disk Management" border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-N_rMub1WTBM/TpPlk4ca3ZI/AAAAAAAAAR0/z4yKo6kT0Tc/s1600/11-10-2011+12-12-52.png" /></a></div><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="line-height: 24px;"><br /></span></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="line-height: 24px;">Now if you have brand new hard drive, you may have a default partition in it. Just right click on it and select "Shrink Volume".</span></span><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-cwjClVtQM4k/TpPnDtxPW9I/AAAAAAAAASE/40S92noTcqw/s1600/10-10-2011+00-08-23.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img alt="Shrink volume" border="0" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-cwjClVtQM4k/TpPnDtxPW9I/AAAAAAAAASE/40S92noTcqw/s1600/10-10-2011+00-08-23.png" /></a></div><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="line-height: 24px;">After clicking "Shrink Volume", you may have to wait for 2-3 minutes, then you will be prompted with this window.</span></span><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-sliybyk-huU/TpPnVk4CZxI/AAAAAAAAASM/Fsqs5ngWt08/s1600/10-10-2011+00-09-50.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img alt="Determine the size" border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-sliybyk-huU/TpPnVk4CZxI/AAAAAAAAASM/Fsqs5ngWt08/s1600/10-10-2011+00-09-50.png" /></a></div><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="line-height: 24px;">Now select the size of the partition and enter in the text box. You cannot shrink volume grater than the available shrink volume size. (To convert GBs into MBs, just multiply it with 1024. E.g, for 50GB, I will enter 50x1024=51200MB).</span></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="line-height: 24px;">After entering the value, click shrink and wait. Now you will see the unallocated space after the drive you want to partition.</span></span><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-bzZjWDGa-7o/TpPodHggISI/AAAAAAAAASU/NYKtjcXGUG0/s1600/10-10-2011+00-11-09.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img alt="Unallocated space" border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-bzZjWDGa-7o/TpPodHggISI/AAAAAAAAASU/NYKtjcXGUG0/s1600/10-10-2011+00-11-09.png" /></a></div><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="line-height: 24px;">Now, right click on that unallocated space and select "New Simple Volume"</span></span><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-lYlO-AVhxd8/TpPotGlNG8I/AAAAAAAAASc/bj3kM5y9jDg/s1600/10-10-2011+00-11-40.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img alt="New simple volume" border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-lYlO-AVhxd8/TpPotGlNG8I/AAAAAAAAASc/bj3kM5y9jDg/s1600/10-10-2011+00-11-40.png" /></a></div><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="line-height: 24px;">Now, you will see the following window.</span></span><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-C_X5pPz1-mI/TpPo6DNN52I/AAAAAAAAASk/1BCMe9SmRzE/s1600/10-10-2011+00-12-20.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img alt="Simple volume wizard" border="0" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-C_X5pPz1-mI/TpPo6DNN52I/AAAAAAAAASk/1BCMe9SmRzE/s1600/10-10-2011+00-12-20.png" /></a></div><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="line-height: 24px;">Click next and assign the desired drive letter from the drop down menu.</span></span><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-kg24cS65SoE/TpPpEWmPZKI/AAAAAAAAASs/gg0ccGDH2u4/s1600/10-10-2011+00-15-00.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img alt="Assign letter" border="0" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-kg24cS65SoE/TpPpEWmPZKI/AAAAAAAAASs/gg0ccGDH2u4/s1600/10-10-2011+00-15-00.png" /></a></div><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="line-height: 24px;">Now click next,&nbsp;</span></span><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-uyGDrCA2NTY/TpPpT9ZbeTI/AAAAAAAAAS0/RSsJS1hrxnU/s1600/10-10-2011+00-15-46.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img alt="Assign label" border="0" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-uyGDrCA2NTY/TpPpT9ZbeTI/AAAAAAAAAS0/RSsJS1hrxnU/s1600/10-10-2011+00-15-46.png" /></a></div><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="line-height: 24px;">Now, without changing anything, click next.</span></span><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-4RCxA_f8hUg/TpPphuKgWTI/AAAAAAAAAS8/vFwy7J7wJ-g/s1600/10-10-2011+00-16-23.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img alt="Click Finish" border="0" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-4RCxA_f8hUg/TpPphuKgWTI/AAAAAAAAAS8/vFwy7J7wJ-g/s1600/10-10-2011+00-16-23.png" /></a></div><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="line-height: 24px;">Now click finish, and you are done! Now autoplay will run that partition, you can also see it in a disk management window....You are done!</span></span><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-kXRhNkDOMTY/TpPqATdzTvI/AAAAAAAAATE/y_JrRDn8X_0/s1600/10-10-2011+00-17-05.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img alt="Newly created partition" border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-kXRhNkDOMTY/TpPqATdzTvI/AAAAAAAAATE/y_JrRDn8X_0/s1600/10-10-2011+00-17-05.png" /></a></div><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="line-height: 24px;">Enjoy Computing!</span></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="line-height: 24px;"><br /></span></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="line-height: 24px;">Also see&nbsp;EASEUS Partition Master is a great free-to-use Disk Partitioning Utility</span></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="line-height: 24px;"><br /></span></span></div>
	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>[Gizmo Gallery] Smart way to charge up your SmartPhone</title>
	  <link>/TechnoTravel-in/gizmo-gallery-smart-way-to-charge-up</link>
		
				
						<author>Rajat Patel</author>
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
	  <pubDate>2011-09-07T12:40:00+05:30</pubDate>
	  <guid>/TechnoTravel-in/gizmo-gallery-smart-way-to-charge-up</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><i>If you are a <span7099324>smartphone</span7099324> user, you might have experienced your mobile battery running out of power while surfing the internet on 3G networks, Wi-Fi or streaming content on the device. In such situations you will need a <span class="IL_AD" id="IL_AD12"><span7099324>backup battery</span7099324></span>, more so if you carry a touch screen 3G device. However, you should make sure that you get one to charge multiple devices. To find out how many times a phone can be charged up with the portable <span7099324>charger</span7099324>, you would need to divide the mAh of the charger to the mAh of your phone. Here are few portable chargers that are available online as well as in the store to provide the seamless experience when you face battery woes next time.</i></span><br /><br /><b><i><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">MIFLIP  ll  Price: Rs.2,500 ($55.50)</span></i></b><br /><b><i><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></i></b><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-j4X_lBxkh_E/TmcW4u0zWtI/AAAAAAAAAP0/vgYtemHc1sw/s1600/MiFlip.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img alt="MIFLIP" border="0" height="139" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-j4X_lBxkh_E/TmcW4u0zWtI/AAAAAAAAAP0/vgYtemHc1sw/s400/MiFlip.jpg" width="400" /></a></div><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">MILI power's MiFlip is a smartphone charger, backup battery pack and viewing stand. It eliminates clutters as it combines three accessories into one lightweight and portable device. MiFlip is compatible with <span7099324>Apple iPhones</span7099324>, <span class="IL_AD" id="IL_AD5"><span7099324>iPod Touch</span7099324></span> and Blackberry. It can charge your device for eight hours of talk time, 15 hours of video or 80 hours of music streaming. If you don't get a one for you in stores, you can get it at <a href="http://www.milipower.com/">www.MiLiPower.com</a></span><br /><br /><b><i><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></i></b><div><b><i><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">PEBBLE CHARGER  ll  Price: Rs.4,000 ($34.49)</span></i></b><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"></div><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-ceO9Yf8z84Q/TmcYFrhroII/AAAAAAAAAP4/YVOQ76IV3EE/s1600/pebble-portable-battery-charger-for-mobile-phone-mp3-player-gadgets.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img alt="Pebble Charger" border="0" height="247" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-ceO9Yf8z84Q/TmcYFrhroII/AAAAAAAAAP4/YVOQ76IV3EE/s400/pebble-portable-battery-charger-for-mobile-phone-mp3-player-gadgets.jpg" width="400" /></a></div><div><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">The palm-sized Pebble Charger has a 5000mAh battery inside it. That is around four times size of your smartphone battery. The device takes little under five hours to fully charge but is worth the time since this portable charger can fill an <span7099324>iPhone</span7099324> for up to eight hours. Apart from iPhone, it is compatible with other MP3 devices, Nokia and <span class="IL_AD" id="IL_AD8">Sony Ericsson handsets</span>, and devices that can be recharged using a mini USB. A rubbery finish ensures that it would not slide off a smooth surface while you are on the move. A handy blue LED charge indicator makes sure that you charge your smartphone completly. Order here <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Veho-Pebble-portable-battery-charger/dp/B003YNT3TO?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=widgetsamazon-20&amp;link_code=btl&amp;camp=213689&amp;creative=392969" target="_blank">Veho Pebble XT portable battery pack charger - External battery pack 5000 mAh</a><img  border="0" height="1" src="http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=widgetsamazon-20&amp;l=btl&amp;camp=213689&amp;creative=392969&amp;o=1&amp;a=B003YNT3TO" style="border: currentColor !important; margin: 0px !important; padding: 0px !important;" width="1" /><br /><br /><b><i><br /></i></b></span></div><div><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><b><i>ETO 3800  ll  Price: Starts at Rs.2,450 ($54.39)</i></b></span><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"></div><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-k0JzUufI8Cs/TmcYNHk7UDI/AAAAAAAAAP8/GG4vgrkSNvE/s1600/ETO+Lets+you+Power+your+Mobile+Devices+on+the+Go.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;"><img alt="ETO 3800" border="0" height="400" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-k0JzUufI8Cs/TmcYNHk7UDI/AAAAAAAAAP8/GG4vgrkSNvE/s400/ETO+Lets+you+Power+your+Mobile+Devices+on+the+Go.jpg" width="308" /></a></div><div><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Green Powercell Technology's Eto portable charger comes with multiple connectors to charge all brands of mobile phones, smartphones, iPods &amp; <span class="IL_AD" id="IL_AD9">MP3 players</span> and portable gaming consoles, among others. It can also be used to charge <span class="IL_AD" id="IL_AD6">digital cameras</span> and camcorders. We are able to charge three smartphones- from zero battery to full and an <span7099324>iPod player</span7099324> with a single charge from Eto 3800. The time taken to charge the device to its full capacity is 2.5-3 hours. With a <span7099324>Lithium ion Battery</span7099324> and capacity of 3800mAh, the output voltage of the device is 5.5V/16V/19V. An LED charge indicator tells you how much the device is charged. It also comes with an auto cut-off feature and overcharging protection circuit. Eto 3800 comes with 12 months replacement gurantee and is available at Spice HotSpot stores, leading mobile outlets and can also be ordered on <a href="http://www.letsbuy.com/">www.letsbuy.com</a><br /><br /><b><br /></b><br /><b><i>POWERSTICK ll  Price: Rs.3,000 ($30.95)</i></b></span><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-luSNLT1o49M/TgqzIjFJWGI/AAAAAAAAAWU/L39HMWzoqe8/s1600/powerstick_charge_iphone.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"></span></a></div><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-KI_GGOnxEXQ/TmcYTihLmgI/AAAAAAAAAQA/hkZfVA1NbSc/s1600/powerstick_charge_iphone.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img alt="Powerstick" border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-KI_GGOnxEXQ/TmcYTihLmgI/AAAAAAAAAQA/hkZfVA1NbSc/s1600/powerstick_charge_iphone.jpg" /></a></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><br /></div><div><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">The Powerstik is a portable charger that allows it to charge a variety of devices. It looks very similar to a large <span class="IL_AD" id="IL_AD7">USB drive</span>. The device has a USB plug at one end and on other a connector that allows you to plug i a variety of devices for charging. The PowerStick include a micro-controlled processor, so when the device is charged, it switches off. While it may look like an extra beefy <span class="IL_AD" id="IL_AD3">USB flash drive</span>, this handy little device actually packs in 750mAh battery within and can provide an emergency boost to your mobile phone, BlackBerry, or <span class="IL_AD" id="IL_AD2">portable music player</span>. To charge powerstick, it has to be connected to any HSB port including <span class="IL_AD" id="IL_AD4">computers and laptops</span> and takes up to 90 minutes. You can order it on <a href="http://www.amazon.com/PowerStick-P1V2-Universal-Portable-Charger/dp/B001JRN8AW?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=widgetsamazon-20&amp;link_code=btl&amp;camp=213689&amp;creative=392969" target="_blank">PowerStick P1V2 Universal USB Portable Charger</a><img alt="" border="0" height="1" src="http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=widgetsamazon-20&amp;l=btl&amp;camp=213689&amp;creative=392969&amp;o=1&amp;a=B001JRN8AW" style="border: currentColor !important; margin: 0px !important; padding: 0px !important;" width="1" /></span><br /></div></div><div><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">&nbsp;&nbsp;</span></div></div>
	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Awesome Dolphin Browser is now available for iOS</title>
	  <link>/TechnoTravel-in/awesome-dolphin-browser-is-now</link>
		
				
						<author>Rajat Patel</author>
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
	  <pubDate>2011-09-02T00:16:00+05:30</pubDate>
	  <guid>/TechnoTravel-in/awesome-dolphin-browser-is-now</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><iframe allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="390" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/rUIGOcQMaSE" width="560"></iframe><br /><div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Very popular and previously only Android based awesome Dolphin Browser is now available for iOS users also.&nbsp;Dolphin is now available for the iPhone and iPad with a laundry list of awesome features to share.</span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">One of the highly recommended and highly downloaded browser on Android-market is now available for Apple iPhone's native OS - iOS.&nbsp;Dolphin Browser has long wowed Android users with smart gestures, Google Chrome like tabbed  browsing, great Mozilla like add-ons, and the “web zine” a slick mobile news  interface, among other features.&nbsp;Now all those features are available for the iOS ecosystem; both iPhone  and iPad users can enjoy the great gesture recognition, speedy sidebar,  and other awesome features previously available only to Android users.</span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Watch the video above to see the browser in action and then hit up the  link below for additional information and to download a copy for your  iOS device. Dolphin Browser is a free browser Android/iOS only.</span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Download <a href="http://itunes.apple.com/app/dolphin-browser/id452204407?mt=8" target="_blank&quot;">Dolphin Browser from itunes.apple.com</a></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div></div>
	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
