<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>/TechnoTravel-in/</title>
   
   <link>/TechnoTravel-in/</link>
   <description>The daily source of digital inspirations</description>
   <language>en-in</language>
   
   <title>
   <![CDATA[ TechnoTravel.in ]]>
   </title>
   <description>
   <![CDATA[ The daily source of digital inspirations ]]>
   </description>
   <link>/TechnoTravel-in/</link>
   <image>
   <url>/TechnoTravel-in/assets/images/favicon.ico</url>
   <title>TechnoTravel.in</title>
   <link>/TechnoTravel-in/</link>
   </image>
   <generator>Jekyll 3.6.2</generator>
   <lastBuildDate></lastBuildDate>
   <atom:link href="/TechnoTravel-in/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
   <ttl>60</ttl>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>What is OpenDNS? Why You Absolutely Need It To Stay Secure and Protected?</title>
	  <link>/TechnoTravel-in/2012/08/what-is-opendns-why-you-absolutely-need-it-to-stay-secure-and-protected</link>
		
				
						<author>Rajat Patel</author>
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
	  <pubDate>2012-08-14T06:36:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/TechnoTravel-in/2012/08/what-is-opendns-why-you-absolutely-need-it-to-stay-secure-and-protected</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-z7mYAXIUzTA/UCnwYrCBqFI/AAAAAAAABNo/0OtquudE6pg/s1600/common-sprite+(1).png" imageanchor="1" style="clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-z7mYAXIUzTA/UCnwYrCBqFI/AAAAAAAABNo/0OtquudE6pg/s1600/common-sprite+(1).png" /></a></div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Well, instead of diving into OpenDNS thing&nbsp;straight&nbsp;away, we believe you might want to have a look at what DNS actually is? DNS is the abbreviated form of the term "Domain Name Server" (You can actually replace Server with Service or System as well!).</span><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">The primary job of the DNS server is providing the ip address of the different websites to your computer. Which means, when you type www.google.com or www.yahoo.com in your browser address bar, your computer actually queries the DNS server which it is configured to use. In response to that query DNS server returns the ip address of that queried website, in this case say www.google.com. Thus DNS server will return the ip address of www.google.com's server. With the help of this ip address, your computer can finally reach to Google.com. Thus there is an important role of DNS server to let you access the internet from your PC.</span><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">No matter what operating system you use, say <a href="http://www.technotravel.in/search/label/windows">Windows</a>, <a href="http://www.technotravel.in/search/label/Linux">Linux</a> or <a href="http://www.technotravel.in/search/label/iOS">Mac</a>, your computer have to have DNS server configured to be able to access the Internet. Now, by default, your ISP (Internet Service Provider) has their own DNS server in most cases. Thus up till now, if you haven't changed your DNS server ever, then you surely are running your ISP's DNS server.</span><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Unfortunately, your DNS server can be the weakest link in the entire Internet Workflow. In a easy language, no matter how speedy or robust your internet link is, if the DNS server of your ISP is faulty or say tad slow, it can ruin your browsing experience. If the DNS server of your ISP is slow, it takes more time to reply to the query sent by your computer, resulting in the slowness of the rendering of the webpage. And in India, ISPs seems not to be too concerned about having a robust DNS server. Which means, even if your ISP provides you the speed of 2Mbps, it can feel like 1Mbps if your DNS server is running slow!</span><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">To solve this problem,</span><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">We can always opt for any other DNS server which is faster and equipped with more robust features than your ISP's DNS server. There are plenty of fast DNS servers to choose from to use for your computer, but we like OpenDNS the most.</span><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="http://www.opendns.com/" target="_blank">OpenDNS</a> is a dedicated DNS servers. Which directly means that the developer staff at OpenDNS is only focused on making their DNS server faster and more reliable, nothing else. OpenDNS dramatically speeds up your internet connection and also enhances your overall internet experience as you'll get this after reading the full post.</span><br /><h3 style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">How To Get Started?</span></h3><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">There is no need of any software or registration to avail yourself the benefits of OpenDNS. All you need to do is to change your computer's DNS servers with the following ip addresses:</span></div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><ul><li>208.67.222.222&nbsp;</li><li>208.67.220.220</li></ul>Don't know how to change your computer's DNS server? <a href="http://www.technotravel.in/2011/08/how-to-change-dns-servers-for-fast.html" target="">Here</a> is the guide that might help you! <a href="http://www.technotravel.in/2011/08/how-to-change-dns-servers-for-fast.html" target="">How To Change DNS Server in Windows</a></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">The whole process takes a few seconds but with this single step alone, you just made your computer safer and increased the overall browsing speed. Here's why: </span><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Unlike the DNS servers of your less reliable ISP, OpenDNS servers store the IP addresses of millions of websites in their cache so it would take less time to resolve your requests. So if you have asked for an IP address of a website that has been previously requested by another OpenDNS user, you will get the reply instantly.</span><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-oaBfZRblaSg/UCnxP8vAgUI/AAAAAAAABNw/6HbthGSKPuQ/s1600/opendns.gif" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-oaBfZRblaSg/UCnxP8vAgUI/AAAAAAAABNw/6HbthGSKPuQ/s1600/opendns.gif" /></a></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Another huge advantage of OpenDNS is that it prevents phishing sites that has ability to steal your important passwords from loading in your computer. Thus OpenDNS does the job which your normal antivirus can't do.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">The another very good&nbsp;feature&nbsp;is Parental Control. If you enable this, you can actually prevent your kids from accessing porn sites using OpenDNS shield! There are another plenty of features included in the OpenDNS like Solving Typo Errors, Shortcuts for your favorite sites and many more.</span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-s3RfsaRLXqM/UCnxeNMyVYI/AAAAAAAABN4/O6GX8lE3mD0/s1600/14-08-2012+11-37-25+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-s3RfsaRLXqM/UCnxeNMyVYI/AAAAAAAABN4/O6GX8lE3mD0/s1600/14-08-2012+11-37-25+AM.png" /></a></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Thus in many ways, OpenDNS is a very useful and easy to set-up DNS server to enhance your overall internet browsing experience.</span></div><div><br /></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">So why wait? Get started here&nbsp;<a href="http://www.opendns.com/">www.opendns.com</a></span></div><div><br /></div></div>
	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>How To Use Internet Explorer Inside Google Chrome with IE Tab Extension</title>
	  <link>/TechnoTravel-in/2012/08/how-to-use-internet-explorer-in-google-chrome-with-ie-tab-extension</link>
		
				
						<author>Rajat Patel</author>
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
	  <pubDate>2012-08-09T16:53:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/TechnoTravel-in/2012/08/how-to-use-internet-explorer-in-google-chrome-with-ie-tab-extension</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-q57Wi6nJKZg/UCPo45TDzpI/AAAAAAAABIY/RaOBWtF1kZE/s1600/chrome-logo-2011-04-27.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-q57Wi6nJKZg/UCPo45TDzpI/AAAAAAAABIY/RaOBWtF1kZE/s1600/chrome-logo-2011-04-27.jpg" /></a></div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Though the Internet Explorer domination from the browser market is over, we still need it to view some Internet Explorer only sites that doesn't support the&nbsp;modern and crowd favorite browsers like <a href="http://www.technotravel.in/search/label/Google%20Chrome" target="_blank">Chrome</a>, <a href="http://www.technotravel.in/search/label/Mozilla%20Firefox" target="_blank">Firefox</a> or Opera. So even Chrome users may have to head over to Internet Explorer to open such Internet Explorer Friendly websites&nbsp;sometimes. To solve this issue, here we've found a very useful extension named IE Tab, which virtually opens up the Internet Explorer inside the Chrome window.</span><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">IE Tab for Chrome is actually invented by the makers of IE Tab for Firefox, which actually emulates the Internet Explorer window in Google Chrome. It can be configured to launch IE based websites directly from the extension that you won't need to even think about heading over to actual Internet Explorer installation on your PC. Though you can't remove Internet Explorer because this extension uses the resources of Internet Explorer installed on your machine. So, don't forget to keep your Internet Explorer up-to-date so that we can be assured of full-proof security.</span><br /><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">What Are The Uses Of It?</span></h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">As mentioned earlier, The IE Tab uses the resources from the actual Internet Explorer installation that resides in your Windows. So if you are using the OS other than Windows, say MacOS or Linux, this extension will not work. If we ignore this limitation, it has many usages:</span><br /><ul><li><b><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Web Development</span></b><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">&nbsp;– View web pages in IE 7, IE 8, or IE 9 mode.</span></li><li><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><b>IE-Only Websites</b> – Load IE-only websites within Google Chrome.</span></li><li><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><b>Outlook Web Access &amp; Sharepoint</b> – Use features that only work in IE.</span></li><li><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><b>ActiveX Controls</b> – Run ActiveX Controls, which is an IE-only technology</span></li></ul><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">How To Use IE Tab</span></h3><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Well, installation is very simple. It is same as any other chrome extension installation. Just head over to <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/hehijbfgiekmjfkfjpbkbammjbdenadd" target="_blank">IE Tab Page of Chrome Web Store</a> and install the extension by clicking "Add to Chrome". It will download and install automatically. When the installation is finished, you'll see the logo containing Internet Explorer at the Extension Bar beside the Wrench Menu of <a href="http://www.technotravel.in/search/label/Google%20Chrome" target="_blank">Google Chrome</a>. Click it to open the Internet Explorer inside Chrome.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-OE2Sv0_lVB8/UCPqE_uT7NI/AAAAAAAABIg/wZ-lQPRg0VM/s1600/09-08-2012+10-12-02+PM.png" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-OE2Sv0_lVB8/UCPqE_uT7NI/AAAAAAAABIg/wZ-lQPRg0VM/s1600/09-08-2012+10-12-02+PM.png" /></a></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">It will open up the currently open tab in the IE Mode. In this screenshot, I had <a href="http://google.com/">google.com</a> already opened, so it opened <a href="http://google.com/">google.com</a> in IE mode. You can browse normally as you would from Internet Explorer. Just enter the URL in the newly created address bar and it will open as if it is opening in the Internet Explorer.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">IE Tab doesn’t integrate perfectly with Chrome – each IE tab frame has its own address bar. To bookmark a page, click the bookmark icon on the IE Tab toolbar. IE Tab will create a bookmark and save it to the “IE Tab” folder on your bookmarks toolbar. When clicked, the bookmark will load the current page in an IE Tab.</span><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">You can tell it’s using Internet Explorer because it isn’t rendering TechnoTravel.in properly. (To be fair, the drop-down menu works properly when IE Tab is set to IE 9 mode, but it uses IE 7 compatibility mode by default.</span><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Advanced Features</span></h3><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">The IE Tab is feature-rich in terms of emulating the Internet Explorer. Just click on the Settings button of the IE Tab Bar to go to the settings page that will let you configure your IE Tab. It is fill with lot of features. Here are the details.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">First of all there are some General Options that needs no&nbsp;explanations!</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-8rGP01QuWrY/UCPqYOq8RgI/AAAAAAAABIo/dQFRpiFEJgA/s1600/09-08-2012+09-53-11+PM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-8rGP01QuWrY/UCPqYOq8RgI/AAAAAAAABIo/dQFRpiFEJgA/s1600/09-08-2012+09-53-11+PM.png" /></a></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Then there is the Auto URL feature. As the name suggest, you can configure to render particular website or link directly from IE Tab, so that you won't need to care to reload that particular website in the IE Tab. It will get captured by the IE Tab automatically.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-6IxUHvyc3cg/UCPqfla69KI/AAAAAAAABIw/0gVBSLm3mds/s1600/09-08-2012+09-53-37+PM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-6IxUHvyc3cg/UCPqfla69KI/AAAAAAAABIw/0gVBSLm3mds/s1600/09-08-2012+09-53-37+PM.png" /></a></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">If there exist some URLs from the Auto URLs that you still want to load via chrome, then you can do that as well. Just add that particular URL in&nbsp;</span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Auto URL Exceptions to serve your cause.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-n2AEZrf-RAs/UCPqmZUDQ3I/AAAAAAAABI4/sUSDgDi-TFM/s1600/09-08-2012+09-53-56+PM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-n2AEZrf-RAs/UCPqmZUDQ3I/AAAAAAAABI4/sUSDgDi-TFM/s1600/09-08-2012+09-53-56+PM.png" /></a></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">There is another interesting feature called IE Compatibility Mode that will load the pages with the IE mode that you want to emulate from. It supports variety of IE modes. By default, IE mode 7 is&nbsp;chosen.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-U7nsRqaumCw/UCPqsKJbo0I/AAAAAAAABJA/_rshrXPW8YA/s1600/09-08-2012+09-54-10+PM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-U7nsRqaumCw/UCPqsKJbo0I/AAAAAAAABJA/_rshrXPW8YA/s1600/09-08-2012+09-54-10+PM.png" /></a></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Do you still wanna use the Internet Explorer instead of this extension? Or have you find any bug that bothers you to do so? Then comment it out to let us know what you feel.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div></div>
	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>How To Access Folders Of Your Android On Your PC via FTP</title>
	  <link>/TechnoTravel-in/2012/08/how-to-access-folders-of-your-android-on-your-pc-via-ftp</link>
		
				
						<author>Rajat Patel</author>
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
	  <pubDate>2012-08-06T06:20:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/TechnoTravel-in/2012/08/how-to-access-folders-of-your-android-on-your-pc-via-ftp</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-c5lXw4qx5nk/UB9eBBYQi6I/AAAAAAAABCY/IlQgcbvqFQc/s1600/06-08-2012+10-48-30+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-c5lXw4qx5nk/UB9eBBYQi6I/AAAAAAAABCY/IlQgcbvqFQc/s1600/06-08-2012+10-48-30+AM.png" /></a></div><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">You can always access the folders of your Android phone on your PC via third party app named <a href="http://www.technotravel.in/2012/06/wirelessly-operate-your-android-from.html" target="_blank">AirDroid</a> from your browser. But what if you want to access these folders in the Windows Explorer wirelessly? You can always connect your Android to your PC via USB cable, but here we're more focused on the use of Wi-Fi to prevent you from the&nbsp;hassle of carrying USB cable wherever you might go.&nbsp;</span><br /><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">In this scenario, all we need is a wireless protocol to access them. We've earlier talked about&nbsp;</span><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="http://www.technotravel.in/2012/08/how-to-access-folders-from-your-windows-pc-and-stream-videos-over-wifi-on-your-android.html">How To Access Folders From Your Windows PC and Stream Videos Over Wi-Fi On Your Android</a>&nbsp;which uses SMB (Samba) protocol to access the folders, and moreover it's a reverse process of what we're gonna discuss here. So, the only famous protocol left for our cause is the File Transfer Protocol or FTP. Via FTP you can easily access the folders of your Android onto your PC irrespective of operating system on your machine as we believe FTP is supported by most Operating Systems.</span><br /><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><b>Start FTP Server On Your Android</b></span><br /><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">To serve this purpose we'll use the popular, user-friendly, free and feature-rich <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.estrongs.android.pop" target="_blank">ES File Explorer</a>. If you haven't tested it yet then click the link to <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.estrongs.android.pop" target="_blank">download it from Google Play</a>. According to me, it's a must have app for each and every Android user.</span><br /><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">After the installation, open up ES File Explorer and goto Settings. Scroll down until you find a menu called Remote Access.</span><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-DFY8YR2eqlg/UB9fwav_lhI/AAAAAAAABCg/mztjLUMNfLg/s1600/Screenshot_2012-08-06-10-44-48.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-DFY8YR2eqlg/UB9fwav_lhI/AAAAAAAABCg/mztjLUMNfLg/s1600/Screenshot_2012-08-06-10-44-48.png" /></a></div><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Click on it as you'll see a checkbox named Remote Manage. Just check it as you'll find the ftp address of your newly made FTP server which is hosted on your Android. There is a link with the port address in the comment area of that menu entry. Just remember it or type it on a notepad. Thus your FTP server on Android is up and running.</span><br /><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><b>How To Access Folders via Windows Explorer</b></span><br /><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">It's pretty easy over here. Make sure your PC and Android are connected over Wi-Fi. Now just open Windows Explorer window and click the address bar to type the address of the ftp server. E.g <i>ftp://ip address:port</i> which is in my case <i>ftp://192.168.43.1:3127/</i>. Just type this and hit Enter.</span><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-laF8vGYf0wM/UB9g4NBD68I/AAAAAAAABCo/szsy881ojTA/s1600/06-08-2012+11-38-56+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-laF8vGYf0wM/UB9g4NBD68I/AAAAAAAABCo/szsy881ojTA/s1600/06-08-2012+11-38-56+AM.png" /></a></div><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Now you can see the folders of your phone on your PC as if it is connected via USB cable.</span><br /><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><b>How To Access Folders via Browser</b></span><br /><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">If your browser supports FTP (Most browser does!), then just type the link ftp://192.168.x.x:xxxx into the address bar of the browser and you can access folders of your phone on your browser.</span><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-hwtzNyN9m9Q/UB9hhehPaMI/AAAAAAAABCw/Uiwc3_sQn5g/s1600/06-08-2012+10-54-39+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-hwtzNyN9m9Q/UB9hhehPaMI/AAAAAAAABCw/Uiwc3_sQn5g/s1600/06-08-2012+10-54-39+AM.png" /></a></div><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">We've used our favorite Chrome for this purpose. But you are free to use the browser of your choice. Just make sure it supports FTP.</span><br /><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div>
	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Wirelessly Operate Your Android From Your Favorite Browser with AirDroid</title>
	  <link>/TechnoTravel-in/2012/06/wirelessly-operate-your-android-from</link>
		
				
						<author>Rajat Patel</author>
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
	  <pubDate>2012-06-26T05:38:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/TechnoTravel-in/2012/06/wirelessly-operate-your-android-from</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-8eIApne_Tt4/T-lGR-O-QLI/AAAAAAAAAnM/zO3sj5ckm64/s1600/unnamed.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-8eIApne_Tt4/T-lGR-O-QLI/AAAAAAAAAnM/zO3sj5ckm64/s1600/unnamed.jpg" /></a></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">AirDroid is a fast, free app that lets you wirelessly manage your Android from your favorite browser. Especially, if you are a Nexus series phone, and don't like MTP (Which is an alternative to USB Mass Storage), then this app is for you! Also if you transfer a lot of stuff from your Android to your PC or vice-versa, this app will free you from plugging in the USB cable every time, as it wirelessly (and also tirelessly!), transfers the data back and forth between your PC and your Android.</span><br /><span style="background-color: white; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><br /><span style="background-color: white; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">You can almost control all essential features of your phone via your browser. Ya, you read it right, your browser. This app works over WiFi Teathering or HotSpot, so you can manage this app via browser, thus no need to install yet another program on your PC. Just download AirDroid from </span><a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.sand.airdroid" style="background-color: white; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;" target="_blank">Play Store</a><span style="background-color: white; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"> and you are good to go.</span><br /><span style="background-color: white; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-zkeDPWjSabk/T-lJEHzT92I/AAAAAAAAAnk/NrpVyPBKIRE/s1600/Screenshot_2012-06-26-10-09-33.png" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-zkeDPWjSabk/T-lJEHzT92I/AAAAAAAAAnk/NrpVyPBKIRE/s1600/Screenshot_2012-06-26-10-09-33.png" /></a></div><span style="background-color: white; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><br /><div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"></div><div><span style="background-color: white; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Now lets briefly discuss about it's features, and there are tons of them in this app. You can send, receive, forward SMSes, Manage (Install/Uninstall) your Apps from browser, preview, manage your photos, videos....in short, you can manage your phone right away from your browser.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">If you are a Root user of your Android, then there is a one&nbsp;exciting feature waiting for you. You can actually view your Android's screen in your browser, take a screenshot and can record a screencast, too!</span><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-wDaeOSPs1qY/T-lKRTkv8MI/AAAAAAAAAns/HeKWB8SyCu4/s1600/26-06-2012+10-12-43+AM.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-wDaeOSPs1qY/T-lKRTkv8MI/AAAAAAAAAns/HeKWB8SyCu4/s1600/26-06-2012+10-12-43+AM.jpg" /></a></div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Enjoy below features after installation from the comfort of your favorite web browser on Windows/Mac/Linux computer or other devices:</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /><i><b>Files</b></i><br />Transfer files between Android devices and computers. Now with drag &amp; drop support.<br />Cut, copy, paste, search, rename or delete files on the SD card.<br /><br /><b><i>SMS</i></b><br />Receive, send, forward or delete SMS messages.<br /><br /><b><i>Apps</i></b><br />Install, uninstall, backup, search apps and do batch processing.<br /><br /><b><i>Photos</i></b><br />Preview, delete, upload, download, set as wallpaper and photos slide show from desktop.<br /><br /><b><i>Clipboard</i></b><br />Share clipboard text between desktop and device.<br /><br /><b><i>Contacts</i></b><br />Group, search, create contacts, check and delete call logs.<br /><br /><b><i>Ringtones</i></b><br />Search, preview, upload, download, delete and customize ringtones for phone calls, notifications and alarms.<br /><br /><b><i>Music</i></b><br />Play, search, upload, download, delete, or set as phone call, notification and alarm ringtones.</span><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-hWZAQefBHU4/T-lKb27reOI/AAAAAAAAAn0/NeZR0sYBq5M/s1600/26-06-2012+10-14-56+AM.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-hWZAQefBHU4/T-lKb27reOI/AAAAAAAAAn0/NeZR0sYBq5M/s1600/26-06-2012+10-14-56+AM.jpg" /></a></div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /><br /><b><i>**New features added in v.1.0.5**</i></b><br /><br /><b><i>QR code login via web.airdroid.com</i></b><br />Tired of the long IP address 192.168.xxx.xxx? <br />Scan the QR code on web.airdroid.com and you are all set.<br /><br /><b><i>Https connection</i></b><br />Stay safe even on a public Wi-Fi network.<br /><br /><b><i>Realtime Android screen</i></b> <i>(experimental feature, root permission required)</i><br />View your Android's screen, take a screenshot, or even record a screencast.<br /><br /><b><i>Multiple virtual desktops</i></b><br />AirDroid is designed for multitasking. Move apps between desktops to better organize your work.<br /><br /><b><i>Video </i></b><i>(Quick Time plugin required)</i><br />Mobile devices are great for videos shooting, but big screen computer may be better for viewing these clips, isn't it?<br /><br /><b><i>More features</i></b><br />Device photo match for most devices, various widgets (calendar, weather, url transfer, clipboard, etc.), frequent contacts...</span><span style="background-color: white; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">AirDroid also comes with the following inbuilt features:</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /><b><i>Device Status</i></b><br />Real-time ROM, SD Card, Battery, CPU and RAM status report &amp; monitor with charts to demonstrate available/used/total resources, and one-tap memory boost.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /><b><i>Tasks Manager</i></b><br />Kill or uninstall running apps, batch operation supported.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /><b><i>Apps Manager</i></b><br />Uninstall, share or check details of user and system apps.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /><b><i>Files</i></b><br />Control Cut, copy, rename, send/share, delete, sort and create visible or hidden folders and files.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><b><i>What's the requirements to run AirDroid?</i></b></span><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><b><i><br /></i></b>AirDroid should be compatible with most Android devices running Android 2.1 or later. The Web Desktop should be compatible with most modern web browsers, including Chrome 12 or later, Firefox 3.6 or later, Safari 5.0 or later (For best performance IE is not recommended).</span><br /><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><b><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Video Guide</span>&nbsp;</b></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><object class="BLOGGER-youtube-video" classid="clsid:D27CDB6E-AE6D-11cf-96B8-444553540000" codebase="http://download.macromedia.com/pub/shockwave/cabs/flash/swflash.cab#version=6,0,40,0" data-thumbnail-src="http://0.gvt0.com/vi/WfNnQxpw7Uw/0.jpg" height="266" width="320"><param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/WfNnQxpw7Uw&fs=1&source=uds" /> <param name="bgcolor" value="#FFFFFF" /> <param name="allowFullScreen" value="true" /> <embed width="320" height="266"  src="http://www.youtube.com/v/WfNnQxpw7Uw&fs=1&source=uds" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" allowfullscreen="true"></embed></object></div><div><br /><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.sand.airdroid" target="_blank">Download AirDroid From Play Store</a></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Or point your phone camera towards QR code to get the link.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.sand.airdroid" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;" target="_blank"><img border="0" height="200" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-jemBsL_xHVg/T-lFgINDsWI/AAAAAAAAAnE/-8fkVR4JuYs/s200/img.png" width="200" /></a></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div></div></div></div>
	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>How To Solve The Conflict Between Google Chrome and Adobe Shockwave Flash Player</title>
	  <link>/TechnoTravel-in/2012/01/how-to-solve-conflict-between-google</link>
		
				
						<author>Rajat Patel</author>
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
	  <pubDate>2012-01-19T15:28:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/TechnoTravel-in/2012/01/how-to-solve-conflict-between-google</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-kdkTMa8a2nQ/Txg2MBdfDmI/AAAAAAAAAiA/66kvEXU5ajs/s1600/Chrome-logo-2011-03-16.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-kdkTMa8a2nQ/Txg2MBdfDmI/AAAAAAAAAiA/66kvEXU5ajs/s1600/Chrome-logo-2011-03-16.jpg" /></a></div><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">This is now a known issue Google Chrome is suffering from, when it comes to displaying the Flash content on the web pages. You might be a victim too! By posting this, I am no way in a mood to&nbsp;criticize Chrome over the other browsers. (In fact, I'm a big fan of it!)&nbsp;But as it's our job to solve the minor "BUGS", we will continue to focus on this sought of bugs even if they are from the best software/apps around!</span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><br /><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-kggBljxatEI/Txg2Ge2LbxI/AAAAAAAAAh4/i-ikxJmKG-g/s1600/19-01-2012+08-51-34+PM.png" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-kggBljxatEI/Txg2Ge2LbxI/AAAAAAAAAh4/i-ikxJmKG-g/s1600/19-01-2012+08-51-34+PM.png" /></a><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">In fact, Chrome browser uses a different technique to display Flash contents on the web pages from the other browsers, say Mozilla Firefox. The other browsers use the Flash Player installation which is installed&nbsp;separately on the machine which is your computer. But, this is not the case in Google Chrome. Instead of using the native Flash Player installation that resides on your machine, Chrome uses the Flash Player which resides in it's own installation or directory.</span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">So when something somehow go wrong, Chrome confuses itself as it can't&nbsp;decide which installation to use to display the Flash content on the web pages, whether to use it's own installation or to use the general installation which all the other browsers are using. And if this type of conflict occurs, chrome comes up with the following annoying message.</span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">In the worst case scenario, it might hang up the browser that you may have to restart it to get it solved for a particular instant of time!</span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">So, here is the&nbsp;permanent&nbsp;solution.</span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">If you ever face the issue, follow the following steps.</span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">First of all, move your cursor to address bar (or Omni Bar) and type <b>chrome://plugins</b>&nbsp;</span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-X5rQG-46LrM/Txgx3eRlYZI/AAAAAAAAAhY/8l_jORjl0j0/s1600/19-01-2012+08-28-40+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-X5rQG-46LrM/Txgx3eRlYZI/AAAAAAAAAhY/8l_jORjl0j0/s1600/19-01-2012+08-28-40+AM.png" /></a></div><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">You will get the following window.</span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-S80SF6fNMQM/TxgyNB7emsI/AAAAAAAAAhg/BWkIq4mTUrM/s1600/19-01-2012+08-39-22+PM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-S80SF6fNMQM/TxgyNB7emsI/AAAAAAAAAhg/BWkIq4mTUrM/s1600/19-01-2012+08-39-22+PM.png" /></a></div><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Now scroll down to the text where it is written "Flash (2 Files)".</span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Now from the top right corner, click on the "Details" button to expand the details.</span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">As you click Details, you would see the detailed information of the two Flash Player&nbsp;</span><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">variants with their installation location. Now, to resolve the conflict, we will disable the Chrome's internal Flash Player, and thus we are rather forcing Chrome to use the general Flash Player installation on your machine. This will, in most cases, will resolve the conflict.</span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-FNWYs2QMtxI/TxgyX3TN7tI/AAAAAAAAAho/U2lrL5K0f3g/s1600/19-01-2012+08-25-45+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-FNWYs2QMtxI/TxgyX3TN7tI/AAAAAAAAAho/U2lrL5K0f3g/s1600/19-01-2012+08-25-45+AM.png" /></a></div><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">To disable the Chrome's own installation, disable the Flash variant which is installed on Chrome's AppData directory, which can be diagnosed by the locan of the installation, which is already marked in the image.</span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-657f6H91xLE/TxgzE3R4vqI/AAAAAAAAAhw/fskd-XkgrRI/s1600/19-01-2012+08-34-13+PM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-657f6H91xLE/TxgzE3R4vqI/AAAAAAAAAhw/fskd-XkgrRI/s1600/19-01-2012+08-34-13+PM.png" /></a></div><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">In this entire process, as you are pointing Chrome to the general installation, the general installation of the Flash Player is expected to be of the latest version for the smooth feel of the web.</span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">In general conditions, when the Chrome uses its&nbsp;separate Flash, it gets updated with every Google Chrome update. But in this method, as we are pointing Chrome to the general installation, Google Chrome update will no longer include the Flash updates, so the only drawback of the solution is that you need to update Flash manually.&nbsp;</span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">To check and download the latest version of the Adobe Flash Player just go to the site <a href="http://get.adobe.com/flashplayer" target="_blank">get.adobe.com/flashplayer</a></span></div>
	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Awesome Dolphin Browser is now available for iOS</title>
	  <link>/TechnoTravel-in/2011/09/awesome-dolphin-browser-is-now</link>
		
				
						<author>Rajat Patel</author>
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
	  <pubDate>2011-09-01T18:46:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/TechnoTravel-in/2011/09/awesome-dolphin-browser-is-now</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><iframe allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="390" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/rUIGOcQMaSE" width="560"></iframe><br /><div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Very popular and previously only Android based awesome Dolphin Browser is now available for iOS users also.&nbsp;Dolphin is now available for the iPhone and iPad with a laundry list of awesome features to share.</span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">One of the highly recommended and highly downloaded browser on Android-market is now available for Apple iPhone's native OS - iOS.&nbsp;Dolphin Browser has long wowed Android users with smart gestures, Google Chrome like tabbed  browsing, great Mozilla like add-ons, and the “web zine” a slick mobile news  interface, among other features.&nbsp;Now all those features are available for the iOS ecosystem; both iPhone  and iPad users can enjoy the great gesture recognition, speedy sidebar,  and other awesome features previously available only to Android users.</span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Watch the video above to see the browser in action and then hit up the  link below for additional information and to download a copy for your  iOS device. Dolphin Browser is a free browser Android/iOS only.</span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Download <a href="http://itunes.apple.com/app/dolphin-browser/id452204407?mt=8" target="_blank&quot;">Dolphin Browser from itunes.apple.com</a></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div></div>
	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>[Extension] Use Facebook Chat Bully to keep Facebook Chat Sidebar in Shape</title>
	  <link>/TechnoTravel-in/2011/08/extension-use-facebook-chat-bully-to</link>
		
				
						<author>Rajat Patel</author>
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
	  <pubDate>2011-08-18T06:43:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/TechnoTravel-in/2011/08/extension-use-facebook-chat-bully-to</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">If you’re underwhelmed by the kludgy interface of Facebook’s native chat client, FB Chat Bully will help you tweak it, hide offline users, and more. Facebook's new interface of chat sidebar is found tricky by most of the users as they are massed up between Online friends and Offline friends. Also Idle friends are adding to the trouble.</span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">In this euphoria of migration to Google+, if you still like Facebook, or you don't want to loose friends by migrating to Google+ and yet want to change the Facebook sidebar look, here is the browser extension that may help you to sort out this confusion.</span><br /><div><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">The extension that we will take a look is named "FB Chat Bully". This is a simple extension that will help you to figure out the Facebook sidebar the way you like. It has plenty customization options to help you out like Minimize the chat sidebar on page load, Hide left column chat panel, Hide Offline users, Hide Idle users, Hide Avatars, Hide status icon etc.</span></div><div><br /><blockquote><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">This useful extension is available for the two most popular browsers Google Chrome and Mozilla Firefox.</span></blockquote><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br />It has very easy to use user interface which will ease the things up. This is what the all extensions are for!</span><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">It will look like below in Google Chrome.</span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="color: #333333; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: 14px;"><br /></span></span><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-vyRGuBj4IbU/Tkyxe8qImYI/AAAAAAAAAL0/kme38J8XLO8/s1600/18-08-2011+11-29-31.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-vyRGuBj4IbU/Tkyxe8qImYI/AAAAAAAAAL0/kme38J8XLO8/s1600/18-08-2011+11-29-31.png" /></a></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><br /></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: left;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">And in Mozilla Firefox, it will look like this.</span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: left;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-qsUzr5IzaHQ/TkyyGFrSHDI/AAAAAAAAAL4/U2n6435pQLI/s1600/18-08-2011+11-44-18.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-qsUzr5IzaHQ/TkyyGFrSHDI/AAAAAAAAAL4/U2n6435pQLI/s1600/18-08-2011+11-44-18.png" /></a></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><br /></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: left;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">After the&nbsp;customizations, the Facebook Sidebar may look like below image.</span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: left;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-THEmUpCim1g/Tkyy7n-IlYI/AAAAAAAAAL8/XLP_CmgbNUE/s1600/18-08-2011+11-39-10.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-THEmUpCim1g/Tkyy7n-IlYI/AAAAAAAAAL8/XLP_CmgbNUE/s1600/18-08-2011+11-39-10.png" /></a></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><br /></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: left;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Chat names are not shown in the above image to keep privacy, but in real time it will&nbsp;definitely appear.&nbsp;</span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: left;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: left;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Download this extension here&nbsp;</span><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><i><a href="http://fbchatbully.csurl.eu/" target="_blank&quot;">fbchatbully.csurl.eu</a></i></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: left;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: left;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div></div></div>
	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
