<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>/TechnoTravel-in/</title>
   
   <link>/TechnoTravel-in/</link>
   <description>The daily source of digital inspirations</description>
   <language>en-in</language>
   
   <title>
   <![CDATA[ TechnoTravel.in ]]>
   </title>
   <description>
   <![CDATA[ The daily source of digital inspirations ]]>
   </description>
   <link>/TechnoTravel-in/</link>
   <image>
   <url>/TechnoTravel-in/assets/images/favicon.ico</url>
   <title>TechnoTravel.in</title>
   <link>/TechnoTravel-in/</link>
   </image>
   <generator>Jekyll 3.6.2</generator>
   <lastBuildDate></lastBuildDate>
   <atom:link href="/TechnoTravel-in/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
   <ttl>60</ttl>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Remotely Flash Files onto Your Android via RemoteFlash [App]</title>
	  <link>/TechnoTravel-in/remotely-flash-files-onto-your-android</link>
		
				
						<author>Rajat Patel</author>
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
	  <pubDate>2013-06-09T08:16:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/TechnoTravel-in/remotely-flash-files-onto-your-android</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on">As a frequent flasher or ROMs, Mods and Kernels, I know the pain of losing out the USB cable only a couple minutes ago before Flashing "commence"!!&nbsp;Then there’s the trial and error process that comes with testing new themes, mods, and ROMs. However, this can all be avoided simply with&nbsp;RemoteFlash. The remote flashing app developed by XDA-Developers member <a href="http://forum.xda-developers.com/showthread.php?t=2307677" target="_blank">Prl91</a>.<br /><br />RemoteFlash allows you to flash ROMS, Mods, and Updates directly from your computer, over WiFi. As of the moment it only allows one file to be flashed at a time. The limit will be raised as the development goes on, but for the time being, RemoteFlash just about serves our purpose.&nbsp;<div><br /></div><div>Though one "downside" you might consider here is that this app uses "OpenRecoveryScript". So that if you have TWRP [TeamWin Recovery Project], then you are good to go, but the users with CWM [ClockWorkMod] Recovery installed might not have the smooth ride. Though&nbsp;CWM may be usable depending on the build installed.</div><div><br />To use RemoteFlash simply download two files at the end of this post. One is a standalone Java application that you run on your computer. The other file is the RemoteFlash apk. After downloading and installing both programs, run the RemoteFlash apk. You will only need to run the app once. After opening RemoteFlash the first time just reboot your device.</div><div><br /></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-FDAheKADpmQ/UbQ4fAYMWZI/AAAAAAAAB1w/-E6qFGpUehU/s1600/Screenshot_2013-06-09-13-02-40.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="400" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-FDAheKADpmQ/UbQ4fAYMWZI/AAAAAAAAB1w/-E6qFGpUehU/s400/Screenshot_2013-06-09-13-02-40.png" width="225" /></a></div><div><br /></div><div>As soon as your device boots back up, RemoteFlash service will be running in background. You can then open the PC client and click "Auto-Scan"(It may take anywhere between a second and two minutes to find your device), check/uncheck "Wipe Data/Cache", and click "Go".&nbsp;</div><div><br /></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-KBwarw_gwWU/UbQ4tlFd0CI/AAAAAAAAB14/1ygf5ozM1Ms/s1600/09-06-2013+01-13-59+PM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-KBwarw_gwWU/UbQ4tlFd0CI/AAAAAAAAB14/1ygf5ozM1Ms/s1600/09-06-2013+01-13-59+PM.png" /></a></div><div><br /></div><div><br /></div><div>You will then be prompted to select a file, and it will be flashed directly to your device.</div><div><br /></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-J3jKOoG06a4/UbQ4y4ojtLI/AAAAAAAAB2A/EtNBroUHJJY/s1600/09-06-2013+01-27-46+PM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-J3jKOoG06a4/UbQ4y4ojtLI/AAAAAAAAB2A/EtNBroUHJJY/s1600/09-06-2013+01-27-46+PM.png" /></a></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><br /></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: left;">After the flashing starts, the file will be downloaded and flashed automatically onto your device!!</div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: left;"><br /></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-XJns2qWqFlY/UbQ5tJGi3SI/AAAAAAAAB2Q/iH9d929YOe8/s1600/Screenshot_2013-06-09-13-24-55%5B1%5D.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="400" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-XJns2qWqFlY/UbQ5tJGi3SI/AAAAAAAAB2Q/iH9d929YOe8/s400/Screenshot_2013-06-09-13-24-55%5B1%5D.png" width="225" /></a></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: left;"><br /></div><h3 style="text-align: left;">Downloads</h3><div style="text-align: left;"><ul style="text-align: left;"><li><a href="https://www.box.net/shared/9p4srm7e4wodsoal4dkb" target="_blank">RemoteFlashPC-V0.3.jar</a></li><li><a href="https://www.box.net/s/8tg94szvm6aywz1o5oyv" target="_blank">RemoteFlashV0.7.apk</a></li></ul>[Source : <a href="http://forum.xda-developers.com/showthread.php?t=2307677" target="_blank">xda-developers</a>]</div></div>
	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Task Killers Are Bad For Android. Here Is The Reason Why You Shouldn't Use Them</title>
	  <link>/TechnoTravel-in/task-killers-are-bad-for-android-here-is-the-reason-why-you-shoudnt-use-them</link>
		
				
						<author>Rajat Patel</author>
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
	  <pubDate>2012-11-09T16:53:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/TechnoTravel-in/task-killers-are-bad-for-android-here-is-the-reason-why-you-shoudnt-use-them</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-cdkpuL-Vjlo/UJ0y65yLHII/AAAAAAAABX4/9StKfDXJySk/s1600/Screenshot_2012-11-09-22-01-08.png" imageanchor="1" style="clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;"><img border="0" height="320" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-cdkpuL-Vjlo/UJ0y65yLHII/AAAAAAAABX4/9StKfDXJySk/s320/Screenshot_2012-11-09-22-01-08.png" width="180" /></a></div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Most of Android fans generally use Task Manager to kill the Apps that are consuming RAM which results in the slow performance and poor battery life.&nbsp;By closing apps running in the background,&nbsp;you'll&nbsp;get improved performance and battery life – that’s the idea, anyway. But in reality, task killers can reduce your phone's performance and battery life. Here we're explaining the reason.</span><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Basically, the Task Killers kills the particular app that is residing in the memory, thus freeing up your phone's memory. But in fact, Android's own memory management is so powerful that you don't need to use any Task Killer. In fact, doing so disturbs the automatic process which is rather bad thing.</span><br /><h3 style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></h3><h3 style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></h3><h3 style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Process Management In Android Is Different From Windows</span></h3><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Most of Android users are very much familiar and used to Windows.&nbsp;On Windows, many programs running at one time – whether they’re windows on your desktop or applications in your system tray – can decrease your computer’s performance. Closing applications when&nbsp;you're&nbsp;not using them can help speed up your Windows computer.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-uKq_rLL9O9o/UJ0zWYgvnKI/AAAAAAAABYA/WZKGiKbkVxw/s1600/Screenshot_2012-11-09-22-04-33.png" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="360" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-uKq_rLL9O9o/UJ0zWYgvnKI/AAAAAAAABYA/WZKGiKbkVxw/s640/Screenshot_2012-11-09-22-04-33.png" width="640" /></a></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">However, Android is&nbsp;altogether&nbsp;a different scenario than Windows. In Windows, there is an obvious way to "close" an application, whereas, this is not the case with Android. You won't find any convincing way to actually "close" an app in Android. Some user might see this as a problem. But in fact, it's in design and not a problem by any means.&nbsp;When you leave an Android app, going back to your home screen or switching to another app, the app stays “running” in the background. In most cases, the app will be paused in the background, taking up no CPU or network resources. Some apps will continue using CPU and network resources in the background, of course – for example, music players, file-downloading programs, or apps that sync in the background.<br /><br />When you go back to an app you were recently using, Android “unpauses” that app and you resume where you left off. This is fast because the app is still stored in your RAM and ready to be used again.</span></div><h3 style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Task Killers Are Bad</span></h3><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-YpqN2yeXblE/UJ00AGAB3lI/AAAAAAAABYI/InVyW6Gd0Tc/s1600/Screenshot_2012-11-09-22-01-52.png" imageanchor="1" style="clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;"><img border="0" height="400" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-YpqN2yeXblE/UJ00AGAB3lI/AAAAAAAABYI/InVyW6Gd0Tc/s400/Screenshot_2012-11-09-22-01-52.png" width="225" /></a></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Most task killers notice that Android uses a lot of memory - in fact, Android stores running or recently used apps into memory which fills up the RAM. But this, by no means, a bad practice. Apps that are stored in the RAM can be quickly switched back to when needed rather than retrieving it from the storage, which is a very slow process compared to&nbsp;retrieval time from RAM.&nbsp;</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">And moreover, the freed up RAM is of no use and it doesn't saves the battery either. We all live in a myth that more free the RAM is, the less power it consumes. But this doesn't holds the truth. The totally full RAM consumes the same amount of power the half-full RAM consumes. So killing tasks or apps will save the battery power holds no truth. And in case of the RAM is full and more memory is needed to run the app than available, Android is smart enough to kill the app automatically which is not used for a while and free up the RAM for the new app. No task killers are&nbsp;required&nbsp;for this purpose.</span></div><div><br /></div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Task killers think they know better than Android. They run in the background, automatically quitting apps and removing them from Android’s memory. They may also allow you to force-quit apps on your own, but you&nbsp;shouldn't&nbsp;have to do this.<br /><br />Task killers&nbsp;aren't&nbsp;just useless – they can reduce performance as well. If a task killer removes an app from your RAM and you open that app again, the app will be slower to load as Android is forced to load it from your device’s storage. This will also use more battery power than if you just left the app in your RAM in the first place. Some apps will automatically restart after the task killer quits them, using more CPU and battery resources. Thus reducing the battery life.</span><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Though Task Killers Can Help Sometime</span></h3><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-7DAGQ716Srk/UJ00WUzw7MI/AAAAAAAABYQ/jzEhsAuUsaM/s1600/Screenshot_2012-11-09-22-02-27.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="640" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-7DAGQ716Srk/UJ00WUzw7MI/AAAAAAAABYQ/jzEhsAuUsaM/s640/Screenshot_2012-11-09-22-02-27.png" width="360" /></a></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">At this point of time while you are reading this article, some users won't agree with the fact that are presented to them before. Because they might have noticed a performance boost and increased battery life after using Task Killer.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">This might hold truth by the way! But only in case you have a badly compiled app installed on your phone.&nbsp;If you have a bad app that’s using CPU and other resources in the background, a task killer that closes the misbehaving app can improve your battery life and make your phone faster.</span></div><div><span style="background-color: white; color: #333333; font-family: Verdana; font-size: 14px; line-height: 17px;"><br /></span></div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">However, using a task killer to deal with a misbehaving app is like using a shotgun to kill a fly – you may fix your problem, but&nbsp;you're&nbsp;inflicting a lot of other damage in the process.<br /><br />Instead of using a task killer in this situation, you should identify the bad app and uninstall it, replacing it with an app that works properly. To pin down the app that’s misbehaving, you can try the <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.zomut.watchdoglite">Watchdog Task Manager</a> app – it will show you which apps are actually using CPU in the background, not which apps are harmlessly being stored in memory.</span><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Conclusion</span></h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Task killers can also cause other problems by killing applications that you want running in the background — for example, if you use an alarm clock app, you may find that your task killer forced the alarm clock app to quit, preventing the alarm from going off.<br /><br />CyanogenMod, the popular community-developed Android Custom ROM,&nbsp;won't&nbsp;even accept bug reports from users using task killers, saying that they cause more problems than they solve.<br /><br />In summary, you&nbsp;shouldn't&nbsp;use a task killer – if you have a misbehaving app wasting resources in the background, you should identify it and uninstall it. But&nbsp;don't&nbsp;just remove apps from your phone or tablet’s RAM – that&nbsp;doesn't&nbsp;help speed anything up.</span><br /><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div></div>
	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>15 Top Free Websites To Backup And Share Your Data On The Cloud</title>
	  <link>/TechnoTravel-in/15-top-free-websites-to-backup-and-share-your-data-on-the-cloud</link>
		
				
						<author>Rajat Patel</author>
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
	  <pubDate>2012-08-20T06:18:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/TechnoTravel-in/15-top-free-websites-to-backup-and-share-your-data-on-the-cloud</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-McsYNYawaME/UDHWAUhyBqI/AAAAAAAABRM/LYhX9HRxYaU/s1600/cloud_storage_2_web_0.png" imageanchor="1" style="clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-McsYNYawaME/UDHWAUhyBqI/AAAAAAAABRM/LYhX9HRxYaU/s1600/cloud_storage_2_web_0.png" /></a></div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Well, backups are essential and we've been told many times how important they are, although we may not pay attention to it until it's too late and we lose all our data! Though you can always backup your important data on your external physical hard drive,&nbsp;but free online backup services provide useful redundancy that could save your data big time!</span><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">If you are a regular TechnoTravel.in reader, you may get this now that we're fan of <a href="http://www.technotravel.in/2012/08/pros-and-cons-of-cloud-basedonline-antivirus.html">cloud computing</a> and we will be writing numerous articles in coming future to let the world understand it's pros and cons. So, as a part of that effort, here we're mentioning out some useful and FREE websites, 15 to be precise, that offer free cloud storage space to let you backup, share or synchronize your data. Each of these services offers a free plan, most also having options for paid subscriptions that offer more storage space, and possibly additional features. Most of these services offer useful backup features such as automatic backups, scheduling, versioning, and restore features. Some services offer other useful features, such as the ability to access your backed up files anywhere using a browser or mobile apps and the ability to stream your media files to your mobile device.</span><br /><h3 style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Microsoft SkyDrive</span></h3><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="http://windows.microsoft.com/en-US/skydrive/home" target="_blank">Microsoft SkyDrive</a> offers 7GB of free data for the new subscribers. It used to offer 25GB in its initial stages, but now it's reduced down to 7GB. Though 7GB is also a good cloud storage space. The old subscribers, like me, are allowed to keep their 25GBs for free.</span></div><div><br /></div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Store your files on SkyDrive and you can access them from your Android phone, iPhone, iPad, Windows phone in addition to your PC or Mac.&nbsp;Use SkyDrive to share large files and photos with your friends and family. They only need a web browser to access the files and photos.</span><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Though there are some drawbacks of SkyDrive that are worth mentioning here. Firstly, it&nbsp;doesn't&nbsp;offer any considerable security to the files you upload, so if you are about to upload your sensitive data on SkyDrive, stop here. The other drawback is that it offers only one folder named SkyDrive, thus if you have data sorted out in many folders, you might find it difficult to upload it on SkyDrive.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">With 7 GB of free storage, SkyDrive is a good place to store your photos and other non-sensitive documents. Use other free backup services for your sensitive and private files. We mention which ones provide encryption for files uploaded to and retrieved from their service.</span><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-9Eick34xGX4/UDHSVClEmVI/AAAAAAAABPU/Pr2qfk2ov9s/s1600/20-08-2012+10-05-48+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-9Eick34xGX4/UDHSVClEmVI/AAAAAAAABPU/Pr2qfk2ov9s/s1600/20-08-2012+10-05-48+AM.png" /></a></div><div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Box</span></h3><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="http://www.box.com/" target="_blank">Box</a>&nbsp;is a good backup solution for the small but important files, as it offers 5GB of storage space with the file size limit of 100MB.&nbsp;The free account also allows you to create file sharing links and provides secure transfer and storage of your data. You can access your data anywhere, anytime, on any device, such as a desktop computer, a laptop, an iPhone, an iPad, or an Android device.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Organize your files online using folders just like you would on your desktop PC. Edit your documents online and save them directly back into your Box account using your native desktop applications.&nbsp;Use Box to share large files easily, rather than trying to email big files, such as videos or presentations.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">If you need more than 5 GB of storage space, you can <a href="https://www.box.com/pricing/">upgrade your account</a> to 25 GB of space for $9.99 per month, or 50 GB of space for $19.99 per month. Both of these plans also increases the maximum file size to 1 GB. Business and Enterprise plans are also available.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-zAi1Hd63YG8/UDHSuhHtm0I/AAAAAAAABPc/gzy0f6a9Yo4/s1600/20-08-2012+10-20-16+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-zAi1Hd63YG8/UDHSuhHtm0I/AAAAAAAABPc/gzy0f6a9Yo4/s1600/20-08-2012+10-20-16+AM.png" /></a></div><div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">ADrive</span></h3><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="http://www.adrive.com/" target="_blank">ADrive</a> offers a personal basic plan that offers 50GB of free cloud storage and features allows you to&nbsp;backup, share, access, and edit your data from anywhere you have Internet access.&nbsp;</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Share large files with family and friends using ADrive’s File Sharing feature. You can get a unique link for a file you want to share in an email. Simply email that link to anyone with whom you want to share that file. If you don’t want to share a file anymore, you can “unshare” it as well.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">You can also edit your word processing documents, spreadsheets, and presentations online. Open, edit, and save your documents directly from within your ADrive account online.<br /><br />Use ADrive’s convenient search tool to find files you want to access or restore without having to browse through all your directories and files.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-RCP22X90_Uk/UDHS4THnIkI/AAAAAAAABPk/Fmq_OVvTJwE/s1600/20-08-2012+10-19-05+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-RCP22X90_Uk/UDHS4THnIkI/AAAAAAAABPk/Fmq_OVvTJwE/s1600/20-08-2012+10-19-05+AM.png" /></a></div><div><div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Comodo Backup</span></h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="http://backup.comodo.com/">Comodo Backup</a> offers 5 GB of free online backup space and a free, lifetime license. Backup your data to  Stream music and videos from and edit documents directly in your online account.<br /><br />Files you choose to backup are encrypted before they leave your computer and are stored encrypted on Comodo’s servers or other storage media you select. You can backup to a network drive, an external hard drive, CD or DVD, ISO file, .zip file, or online storage.<br /><br />Schedule any combination of full, incremental, differential, and synchronized backups to run at a time of your choosing using their flexible scheduler.<br /><br />Files in use are backed up using Volume Shadow Copy technology.<br /><br />Access your files from any computer with an internet connection using their web interface.<br /><br />If you need more storage space, you can <a href="http://backup.comodo.com/download-buy.php">purchase 250 GB</a> for $9.99 per month. You can get two months for free by purchasing one year in advance for $99.99.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-lhPvl2J431o/UDHTEdOLQRI/AAAAAAAABPs/9b76jzAVXJc/s1600/20-08-2012+11-07-57+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-lhPvl2J431o/UDHTEdOLQRI/AAAAAAAABPs/9b76jzAVXJc/s1600/20-08-2012+11-07-57+AM.png" /></a></div><div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">MyOtherDrive</span></h3><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="http://www.myotherdrive.com/" target="_blank">MyOtherDrive</a> offers 2 GB of free cloud storage. With a free account, you get unmetered bandwidth, unattended, or automatic, backup, and AES 128-bit encryption and HTTPS (SSL) connections.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-xYCgTzORlEM/UDHTSsMl8oI/AAAAAAAABP0/zR8hIE0j1H8/s1600/20-08-2012+11-09-22+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-xYCgTzORlEM/UDHTSsMl8oI/AAAAAAAABP0/zR8hIE0j1H8/s1600/20-08-2012+11-09-22+AM.png" /></a></div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">BuddyBackup</span></h3><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="http://www.buddybackup.com/" target="_blank">Buddy Backup</a> has an interesting concept. It allows you to&nbsp;backup your data to your friends, families, and colleague’s computers for free. All backed up files are encrypted locally before they are sent to your buddies’ machines and only you have the encryption keys. So, your buddies can’t read your files.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">You don’t have to worry about your backups staying on your buddies’ computers. You can setup BuddyBackup to backup multiple copies of your files, so you’re sure you have backups. Two copies of your data are spread among your buddies by default. BuddyBackup also regularly checks that your buddies still have your backups. If there is a problem on a buddy’s computer, BuddyBackup automatically backs up your files to a different buddy instead. So, if one of your buddies uninstalls BuddyBackup or their computer fails, your data is still safe</span><span style="color: #333333; font-family: Verdana;"><span style="font-size: 14px; line-height: 17px;">.</span></span><br /><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">You can also backup your data offline to your own external hard drives.<br /><br />If your computer crashes and you have to restore your data to a new computer, you can easily do so by running BuddyBackup on your new computer. You can also recover your files from a friend’s computer, if you haven’t replaced your computer yet, using the Guest Mode. In Guest Mode, you can’t add to backups; you can only restore files from existing backups.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-EJGH6RQiPcM/UDHTf24_H6I/AAAAAAAABP8/_XQN8FSazLY/s1600/20-08-2012+11-11-28+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-EJGH6RQiPcM/UDHTf24_H6I/AAAAAAAABP8/_XQN8FSazLY/s1600/20-08-2012+11-11-28+AM.png" /></a></div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">DropBox</span></h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="https://www.dropbox.com/pricing">Dropbox</a> offers 2 GB of storage for free, and the ability to sync files and folders between your Windows, Mac, or Linux computer and the cloud. Use the desktop client or the web interface to add your files and folders to the Dropbox folder. Once in the Dropbox folder, the files are synced among the PC, the cloud, and any other devices enabled with Dropbox, including mobile devices like phones and tablets.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-P4h_lohISKo/UDHTpvYLUII/AAAAAAAABQE/IVvc5Fm7xEQ/s1600/20-08-2012+11-13-32+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-P4h_lohISKo/UDHTpvYLUII/AAAAAAAABQE/IVvc5Fm7xEQ/s1600/20-08-2012+11-13-32+AM.png" /></a></div><div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">SpiderOak</span></h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="https://spideroak.com/">SpiderOak</a> offers 2 GB of secure, free storage space for online backups, synchronization, sharing, remote access, and storage of your files from unlimited Windows, Mac OS X, and Linux (Ubuntu, Debian, Fedora, and openSUSE) computers and locations, such as USB flash drives, external hard drives, and network drives.</span></div><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">ShareRooms are password-protected locations on SpiderOak’s servers that allow you to securely share files gathered from multiple machines with others. Any data in a ShareRoom is updated automatically when changes are made, and a notification of the changes is sent out as an RSS feed.<br /><br />Apps for Android and iOS devices are provided that allow you to access your data from anywhere. You can view, watch, or listen to any file in your SpiderOak account, visit ShareRooms, share files, and download files to your device for offline access.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-aa2-7qqRkMQ/UDHTzlDPrRI/AAAAAAAABQM/1NWG4PvKTks/s1600/20-08-2012+11-14-43+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-aa2-7qqRkMQ/UDHTzlDPrRI/AAAAAAAABQM/1NWG4PvKTks/s1600/20-08-2012+11-14-43+AM.png" /></a></div><div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">MozyHome Free</span></h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="http://mozy.com/home/free">MozyHome Free</a> offers 2 GB of storage for free along with the option to add more storage space through a paid subscription. Clients for PC and Mac are available for download that you can set up to perform fully automated backups. Select folders to be backed up, set a schedule, and Mozy will keep a backup of these folders online, regularly syncing them without interaction from you. Mozy also provides military-grade encryption prior to transfer using a secure SSL connection.<br /><br />Once you perform your initial backup of your files, Mozy saves bandwidth by only backing up new or changed portions of files, helping to speed up future backups. Mozy also backs up all open and locked files, such as Outlook PST files. You can schedule backups to happen while your computer is on but not in use. Backups can occur daily or weekly at a specific time of day.<br /><br />When you need to restore your data, you can choose to do so using the software client, on the web, or by ordering a DVD to restore. If you’re using Windows, you can also restore your data using the right-click context menu or through the Mozy Virtual Drive. You can restore file versions up to 30 days into the past.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-rwA86PAdYmY/UDHT_OQKyMI/AAAAAAAABQU/Yi9i8FTs1j8/s1600/20-08-2012+11-16-36+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-rwA86PAdYmY/UDHT_OQKyMI/AAAAAAAABQU/Yi9i8FTs1j8/s1600/20-08-2012+11-16-36+AM.png" /></a></div><div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">MiMedia</span></h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="http://www.mimedia.com/">MiMedia</a> offers 7 GB of storage space for free, and features such as secure, automatic online backup and cloud sync. Access your files from anywhere and stream your music and videos and view your photos using MiMedia’s free iPhone and iPad apps. Easily share your photos, videos, and files and post to your favorite social networks.<br /><br />Unlike some other online backup services, MiMedia allows you to backup from any number of computers and devices, such as a laptop, desktop computer, external hard drives, network drives, and more.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-alF-agGJ1sY/UDHULrgcJmI/AAAAAAAABQc/UARiR_BIDOU/s1600/20-08-2012+11-17-55+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-alF-agGJ1sY/UDHULrgcJmI/AAAAAAAABQc/UARiR_BIDOU/s1600/20-08-2012+11-17-55+AM.png" /></a></div><div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Google Drive</span></h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="https://drive.google.com/start?authuser=0#home">Google Drive</a> offers 5 GB of storage for free. Store files online, share them with family and friends, and edit your documents online using Google Docs from your PC or Mac, iPhone, iPad, Android device, and from Chrome OS. View any of over 30 file types on your PC using your browser, without having the program installed on your computer.<br /><br />There are special apps on the Chrome Web Store that allow you to create, open, and share files directly in Google Drive.<br /><br />Search for your files on Google Drive by keyword, and filter by file type, owner, and more. Google Drive’s search feature can even find text in scanned documents and objects in images.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-DmyqP6ugLQQ/UDHUXrp-arI/AAAAAAAABQk/Vs1xakCbvzc/s1600/20-08-2012+11-19-13+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-DmyqP6ugLQQ/UDHUXrp-arI/AAAAAAAABQk/Vs1xakCbvzc/s1600/20-08-2012+11-19-13+AM.png" /></a></div><div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">SugarSync</span></h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="https://www.sugarsync.com/">SugarSync</a> also offers 5 GB of storage space for free. You can use SugarSync not only as an online backup service, but also as a way to sync your files, such as music and photos, among your computers and other devices, such as your Android device, iPhone, iPad, BlackBerry, and Kindle Fire. SugarSync can be handy if you need to transfer files between a PC and a Mac.<br /><br />Just like Mozy, you can backup your data from any folders on your hard drive. You can also select folders to share with your friends and family. You can edit files on your computer while it’s offline, and the changed files are quietly synced with SugarSync the next time your computer is online without interfering with your productivity.<br /><br />SugarSync keeps the previous five versions of all your files so you can reference or restore them in the future. Only the most recent version of each file counts against your storage limit.<br /><br />If you just want to backup a set of files without automatically syncing them or updating them, you can use SugarSync’s Web Archive feature. Everything stored in the Web Archive is accessible from the web and your mobile devices.<br /><br />SugarSync offers mobile apps for devices such as Android, iPad, iPhone, iPod Touch, BlackBerry, and Windows Mobile. You can access files backed up to your SugarSync account from any of your other computers, share photos, upload files and photos of any size from your mobile device to your computer (even if it’s turned off), and even edit documents, depending upon the capabilities of your device.<br /><br />Data uploaded to and retrieved from SugarSync’s servers are sent over the Internet using TLS (SSL 3.3) encryption. Every piece of information moved between your computers, mobile devices, and SugarSync’s servers is verified as a secure communication, whether you are backing up files to their servers or restoring files from them. You can also protect folders you share with other people, such as clients or coworkers.<br /><br />SugarSync offers some handy features for transferring music and photos between your mobile devices and your computers. You can also stream music to your mobile device. For Android devices and iPhones, you can sync your music to your phone so you can listen to it offline. Share a large video file by sending a link to the file rather than sending an email with a large attachment.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-DKUPEZuvOu4/UDHUit9xr7I/AAAAAAAABQs/B6M5dmFB0ek/s1600/20-08-2012+11-20-46+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-DKUPEZuvOu4/UDHUit9xr7I/AAAAAAAABQs/B6M5dmFB0ek/s1600/20-08-2012+11-20-46+AM.png" /></a></div><div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">ElephantDrive</span></h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="http://home.elephantdrive.com/plans-and-pricing/free-plans/">ElephantDrive’s Lite Edition</a> plan offers 2 GB of free online backup space and has all the features of ElephantDrive’s premium plans, including automatic online storage and backup, military-grade encryption, and support for up to three computers or devices. You can also access your data from any internet-enabled device and share files and photos with a single click.<br /><br />One advantage of ElephantDrive’s service is their “Web Explorer.” It allows you to access and upload files using a web browser anywhere you have internet access. You do not have to wait until you have access to an approve device using proprietary software.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-uf9dsPkRSac/UDHUui3tU6I/AAAAAAAABQ0/iNSoCpLnRdw/s1600/20-08-2012+11-23-30+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-uf9dsPkRSac/UDHUui3tU6I/AAAAAAAABQ0/iNSoCpLnRdw/s1600/20-08-2012+11-23-30+AM.png" /></a></div><div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">CrashPlan</span></h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="http://www.crashplan.com/">CrashPlan</a> offers the ability to backup your data to multiple destinations for free (for personal backup). You can backup using your own computers and external hard drives for onsite backups, as well as backup your data to computers belonging to your friends and family for offsite backup.<br /><br />CrashPlan’s backup software runs on PCs, Macs, Linux, and Solaris and backs up data from any combination of these operating systems and from attached hard drives, as well. Backups happen automatically so you don’t have to remember to backup your data or get annoyed from popup dialogs reminding you to perform a backup. You can schedule your backups if you want to control when they are performed. If a backup is interrupted, it is resumed the next time the computers become available again.<br /><br />When you backup data to multiple destinations, your data is sent to one destination one at a time. To make sure you have a full backup as soon as possible, the order of your backups is based on which destination will complete first.<br /><br />With the free version of CrashPlan, your files are secured before they are transferred to CrashPlan’s servers using enterprise-grade, 128-bit encryption. Paid plans provide 448-bit encryption.<br /><br />There are no limitations on the size of files you can backup.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-m8Op9OAwbC4/UDHU9LdRdZI/AAAAAAAABQ8/t1vwlLVwGXg/s1600/20-08-2012+11-25-23+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-m8Op9OAwbC4/UDHU9LdRdZI/AAAAAAAABQ8/t1vwlLVwGXg/s1600/20-08-2012+11-25-23+AM.png" /></a></div><div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Ubuntu One</span></h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="https://one.ubuntu.com/">Ubuntu One</a> allows you to sync up to 5 GB of files to the cloud for free and access it anywhere. It may seem like it’s only for Ubuntu Linux machines, but you can also sync your Windows computer to Ubuntu One account. They offer apps for Android and iOS devices that let you manage your files and photos directly from your mobile device.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-7OGgbbnea9g/UDHVL7nnnLI/AAAAAAAABRE/WHNLOq0LfwQ/s1600/20-08-2012+11-27-11+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-7OGgbbnea9g/UDHVL7nnnLI/AAAAAAAABRE/WHNLOq0LfwQ/s1600/20-08-2012+11-27-11+AM.png" /></a></div><div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">If you don't want to shell out any money on paid cloud storage, then you always can sign up on the multiple websites above to have yourself a decent amount of cloud storage to go with for free. If you sign up for all the above mentioned cloud storage websites, you'll avail yourself as good as 100GB (approx) of cloud storage, which is&nbsp;humongous indeed! However, you must not forget which file is stored at which place, otherwise it can be a headache!!</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif; font-size: xx-small;">Top Image Courtesy : <a href="http://www.savageio.com/page/cloud-storage-backup-services" target="_blank">Savageio.com</a></span></div><div><br /></div></div></div></div>
	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Shoot Multiple Photos in Seconds On Any Android Device With Fast Burst Camera App</title>
	  <link>/TechnoTravel-in/shoot-multiple-photos-in-seconds-on-any-android-device-with-fast-burst-camera-app</link>
		
				
						<author>Rajat Patel</author>
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
	  <pubDate>2012-08-14T12:45:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/TechnoTravel-in/shoot-multiple-photos-in-seconds-on-any-android-device-with-fast-burst-camera-app</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><br /><iframe allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" frameborder="0" height="360" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/DWsm7ADk8Q4?feature=player_embedded" width="550"></iframe>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;<span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Fast Burst Camera App for Android allows your device to capture rapid-fire shots in a quick succession - similar to the Burst Camera Mode of the higher end phones like Galaxy S3 or HTC One X - with the support to capture as fast as 30 frames per second if your Android allows it! So, just capture multiple shots of your playing kid or flying bird with this Fast Burst Camera App and later choose the best one among them to have a perfect capture!</span><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><br /><div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-jRcvt1t2s6o/UCpGsWH8h4I/AAAAAAAABOo/hVPYgvNM5Ps/s1600/FBC+play.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="125" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-jRcvt1t2s6o/UCpGsWH8h4I/AAAAAAAABOo/hVPYgvNM5Ps/s200/FBC+play.jpg" width="200" /></a></div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">The app actually comes in two versions - Free and Paid ($4). The free version is ad-supported and comes with the basic features, whereas the paid version is of course ad-free version with some additional features like auto-focus, zoom, and disabling the shutter (Shutter sound can be annoying at time, I tell you!). Though you'll need to shell out $4 to get the full&nbsp;featured app, but it's worth buying. So, just test the free version and if it satisfies you, then you can opt for buying it to help the developer.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-1Ku1H88ryHU/UCpGWFetzwI/AAAAAAAABOg/O8EfCrQd4j4/s1600/FBC+app.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;"><img border="0" height="200" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-1Ku1H88ryHU/UCpGWFetzwI/AAAAAAAABOg/O8EfCrQd4j4/s200/FBC+app.jpg" width="119" /></a></div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">The working of the Fast Burst Camera app is pretty simple. It stores the quickly captured pics in the memory for the later processing and once you're done capturing in the burst mode, it quickly transfers to the SD card. Thus the maximum number of pics you can take are unlimited&nbsp;theoretically but practically it depends on how much memory your Android allots to the app. Though there is no limit on the number of pics to be captured at once, obviously high number of pics will require more memory and will acquire more time to get saved in your gallery, which can be quite cumbersome at times!</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">The app also provides some settings to get configured by the user like choosing the resolution of the photos and control over memory allocation to this app. Though one thing should be noticed here is, higher the resolution of photos, more time it takes to get saved in your SD card. When we tested this app on our 1.2GHz dual-core Galaxy Nexus, it did a fantastic job to become my favorite camera app, and above all, it's free folks!</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">So, if your Android is not yet equipped with a third party camera app that does this, this app is&nbsp;definitely&nbsp;worth trying!</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.spritefish.fastburstcameralite">Download Fast Burst Camera (free)</a>&nbsp;[Google Play Link]</span><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.spritefish.fastburstcamera&amp;feature=more_from_developer#?t=W251bGwsMSwxLDEwMiwiY29tLnNwcml0ZWZpc2guZmFzdGJ1cnN0Y2FtZXJhIl0">Download Fast Burst Camera (Paid $4)</a> [Google Play Link]</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Originally From : <a href="http://forum.xda-developers.com/showthread.php?t=1709506">xda-developers</a></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div></div>
	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Google Translate Gets Updated For Android, Now Supports Translating Photos</title>
	  <link>/TechnoTravel-in/google-translate-gets-updated-for-android-now-supports-translating-photos</link>
		
				
						<author>Rajat Patel</author>
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
	  <pubDate>2012-08-10T16:46:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/TechnoTravel-in/google-translate-gets-updated-for-android-now-supports-translating-photos</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">The <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.google.android.apps.translate">Google Translate</a> App is now updated on Android as it supports translating photos as well. Which means, in real world, if you see any poster written in any other language which is unknown to you, just point your Android's camera towards it, take a snap and Google Translate will translate the contents of that pic. Though you'll need to highlight the text you want to translate.</span><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">For now, only <a href="http://www.technotravel.in/search/label/Android">Android</a> users can take advantage of this feature.&nbsp;It works with most of the languages that are supported by Google Translate.  The app doesn’t have the ability to automatically detect what language is captured in an image, so the user needs to know the language they’re looking at, but the feature otherwise works on any high-contrast text. Stylized or low-contrast text might trip it up.&nbsp;</span><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-FaF3q8VqeXw/UCU6E1acUKI/AAAAAAAABKw/DCT2m6hNOlo/s1600/translate.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-FaF3q8VqeXw/UCU6E1acUKI/AAAAAAAABKw/DCT2m6hNOlo/s1600/translate.jpg" /></a></div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Users will also need to make sure that the text they want to translate must fit in the single photograph. So, it will not be useful for the big posters or the big&nbsp;length&nbsp;text. Thus, as of now, it'll only work on the smaller images where the text is clear and all in one image. Though, as a popular Google product, it will only get better!</span><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Even though there exists some limitations, it is still a very major leap forward from Google.&nbsp;Typing in a phrase from a foreign language can take some time and is subject to typos. Taking a photograph is quicker and more accurate.</span><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">This app will work on the Android versions 2.3(Gingerbread) and above. So why wait, just download or update your Google Translate on your Android.</span><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.google.android.apps.translate">Download or Update Google Translate</a>&nbsp;from <a href="https://play.google.com/store">Google Play</a></span><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div>
	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
