<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>/TechnoTravel-in/</title>
   
   <link>/TechnoTravel-in/</link>
   <description>The daily source of digital inspirations</description>
   <language>en-in</language>
   
   <title>
   <![CDATA[ TechnoTravel.in ]]>
   </title>
   <description>
   <![CDATA[ The daily source of digital inspirations ]]>
   </description>
   <link>/TechnoTravel-in/</link>
   <image>
   <url>/TechnoTravel-in/assets/images/favicon.ico</url>
   <title>TechnoTravel.in</title>
   <link>/TechnoTravel-in/</link>
   </image>
   <generator>Jekyll 3.6.2</generator>
   <lastBuildDate></lastBuildDate>
   <atom:link href="/TechnoTravel-in/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
   <ttl>60</ttl>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>[Infographic] Enterprise Mobility – Apps, Platforms and Devices</title>
	  <link>/TechnoTravel-in/infographic-enterprise-mobility-apps</link>
		
				
						<author>Rajat Patel</author>
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
	  <pubDate>2012-01-12T10:35:00+05:30</pubDate>
	  <guid>/TechnoTravel-in/infographic-enterprise-mobility-apps</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">The enterprises are witnessing a transformation led by smartphones and Tablets. Mobility is slowly becoming a critical part of IT strategy. As employees and business processes go mobile, we tried to decode enterprise mobility, crunch numbers to present before you an informative infographic detailing out the technology used in enterprise mobility, industry verticals that are at the forefront of mobilizing its operations and why enterprises are adopting mobility solutions. Our enterprise mobility infographic also takes a look at the state of enterprise applications, the smartphone deployment approach by industries and how big brands are increasingly deploying apps.</span><div><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><a href="http://www.xcubelabs.com/enterprise-mobile-apps.php"><img alt="Enterprise Mobile Applications" border="0" src="http://www.xcubelabs.com/images/Enterprise-Mobility-Apps-small.png" /></a><br />Infographic by <a href="http://www.xcubelabs.com/enterprise-mobile-apps.php">Enterprise mobile consultants at [x]cube LABS</a><br /><br /></div></div>
	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Google acquires Motorola Mobility - What Next?</title>
	  <link>/TechnoTravel-in/google-acquires-motorola-mobility-what</link>
		
				
						<author>Rajat Patel</author>
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
	  <pubDate>2011-08-16T00:16:00+05:30</pubDate>
	  <guid>/TechnoTravel-in/google-acquires-motorola-mobility-what</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-d71fb-srCL8/Tklo87edzNI/AAAAAAAAALw/F80ztphfny0/s1600/google-motorola.top.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-d71fb-srCL8/Tklo87edzNI/AAAAAAAAALw/F80ztphfny0/s1600/google-motorola.top.jpg" /></a></div><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana,sans-serif;">Since its launch in November 2007, Android has not only dramatically  increased consumer choice but also improved the entire mobile experience  for users. Today, more than 150 million Android devices have been  activated worldwide—with over 550,000 devices now lit up every  day—through a network of about 39 manufacturers and 231 carriers in 123  countries. Given Android’s phenomenal success, we are always looking for  new ways to supercharge the Android ecosystem. That is why I am so  excited today to announce that we have agreed to acquire Motorola.</span><br /><br /><blockquote><span style="font-family: Verdana,sans-serif;"><span style="font-size: small;">The above words are said by Larry Page</span></span>, <span style="font-family: Verdana,sans-serif;">CEO of Google Inc while announcing the breaking news of Google acquiring Motorola at the rate of $40 per share of Motorola Mobility. The deal sets around $12.5 billion (About Rs.54000 Crore).</span></blockquote><br /><div style="font-family: Verdana,sans-serif;">He also said, "Motorola has a history of over 80 years of innovation in communications  technology and products, and in the development of intellectual  property, which have helped drive the remarkable revolution in mobile  computing we are all enjoying today. Its many industry milestones  include the introduction of the world’s first portable cell phone nearly  30 years ago, and the StarTAC—the smallest and lightest phone on earth  at time of launch. In 2007, Motorola was a founding member of the Open Handset Alliance  that worked to make Android the first truly open and comprehensive  platform for mobile devices. I have loved my Motorola phones from the  StarTAC era up to the current DROIDs."</div><div style="font-family: Verdana,sans-serif;"><br /></div><div style="font-family: Verdana,sans-serif;">"The combination of Google and Motorola will not only supercharge  Android, but will also enhance competition and offer consumers  accelerating innovation, greater choice, and wonderful user experiences.  I am confident that these great experiences will create huge value for  shareholders."<br /><br />So, after hearing this news, the obvious question that strikes through head "What Next?".&nbsp; So, here are some topics to be thinked about this Google-Motorola combination.<br /><br /><b>A Big Turn in Smartphone market</b><br /><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana,sans-serif;">The </span>Smartphone market biggies like Samsung, HTC, and 39 others, who are in partnership with Google for their Android Operating System, are expected to be more concerned over this Google surprise move then Apple or Microsoft. Well, no one knows what Google gonna do now, but for now, by acquiring the Hardware manufacturer, it's clear that Google wants to turn up heat in the fastest growing Smartphone market with their arch rivels, Apple and Microsoft. Moreover, it seems like a move to give wings to the expansion plans of the projects like <a href="http://www.technotravel.in/2011/07/preview-google-tv-where-television.html" target="_blank&quot;">Google TV</a>. <br /><br /><b>A Manufacturing Spin Out?</b><br /><br />According to <a href="http://saulhansell.blogspot.com/2011/08/six-thoughts-on-goog-moto.html" target="_blank&quot;">Saul Hansell</a>, I also believe that within the decade — if not much sooner — Google will likely spin-out  Motorola’s manufacturing business. As Hansell says, “It’s just not what  [Google does], and it’s not what they need in the long run.”<br /><br /><div><b>Google Strategy</b> </div><div></div><div>This deal is not an endorsement of the Steve  Jobs doctrine that the best way to make software is to control the  hardware that runs it.</div>I think Google believes that, but only  really for the hardware that runs its data centers. Google is to its  core a cloud computing company. It sees hardware as little more than  devices to run browsers of various sorts, which is a way to describe  Android.</div><div style="font-family: Verdana,sans-serif;"><br /><b>Patent Issues</b><br /><br />Google says that they are in this deal mainly because of the patent issues with the counterparts. They are Microsoft, Apple and Oracle. They see themselves in a patent war. So, why buy patents when they can buy a whole company?<br /><br /><b>Will Google TV be benefited?&nbsp; </b><br /><br />For me, the answer is a big "Yes". Given the fact that Motorola is a very large cable box maker, Google would definitely have thought about Google TV expansion with some Moto touch.<br /><br />So, for now we can only wait and watch for the time to come as it is gonna be interesting talking point in the coming future.<br /><br />Also See : <a href="http://www.technotravel.in/2011/08/infographic-android-story-history-of.html"target=_blank">[Infographic] The Android Story - History of Android</a><br /><br />&nbsp; </div></div>
	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>[How-To] Reset Nokia S40 / S60 v3 mobile phones</title>
	  <link>/TechnoTravel-in/how-to-reset-nokia-s40-s60-v3-mobile</link>
		
				
						<author>Rajat Patel</author>
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
	  <pubDate>2011-07-20T10:36:00+05:30</pubDate>
	  <guid>/TechnoTravel-in/how-to-reset-nokia-s40-s60-v3-mobile</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-U4y4WPUf7h4/TiZe6wNDMPI/AAAAAAAAACU/BjspdzH587E/s1600/nokia-5800-xpressmusic.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="240" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-U4y4WPUf7h4/TiZe6wNDMPI/AAAAAAAAACU/BjspdzH587E/s320/nokia-5800-xpressmusic.jpg" width="320" /></a></div><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Hi friends, while attempting to install some useful software, any useful system related program or any game to your s40 or s60 phones, sometimes it goes wrong and your phone hangs up!!!! It's such an embarrassing situation for all of us. So, to solve this problem and to prevent yourselves from such embarrassment, Here I've come up with some tricks to reset your Symbian phone.......</span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><br /><b><u><span class="Apple-style-span" style="color: #cc0000; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Tricks to reset your Symbian s40 or s60 phone</span></u></b><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Here, first two tricks are common for all symbian phones.</span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><b>Soft Reset:</b> With this trick, mobile settings are restored to the factory settings. But it keeps the games &amp; applications which are pre-installed. To do this press *#7780#</span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><b><br /></b></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><b>Deep Reset:</b> It is the mostly used and the safest way to remove all the infected files and to fix all the bugs that are caused by some virus affected applications. To do this reset, press *#7370#</span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><b>Hard Reset (Touch Screen or When the display is not active)</b></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">The Procedure to reset your touch screen phone is way different from the keypad phones.</span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">If the problem is big and if you are not able to dial above mentioned numbers then you have to follow the following procedure.</span><br /><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><br /><br /><ul><li><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><u>For mobiles other than N97 or Nokia 5800</u>, keep pressed the following keys and restart your phone while still pressing the keys. The keys are * and 3 and (Call Button).</span></li><li><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><u>For Nokia 5800</u>: Press the keys Red(End Call) + Green(Start Call) + Photocamera Button and switch on your mobile holding this keys.</span></li><li><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><u>For Nokia N97</u>: Press both the Shift Keys + Space Bar + Backshift, Hold this keys and turn on your phone.</span></li></ul><br /><div><br /></div>
	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
