<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>/TechnoTravel-in/</title>
   
   <link>/TechnoTravel-in/</link>
   <description>The daily source of digital inspirations</description>
   <language>en-in</language>
   
   <title>
   <![CDATA[ TechnoTravel.in ]]>
   </title>
   <description>
   <![CDATA[ The daily source of digital inspirations ]]>
   </description>
   <link>/TechnoTravel-in/</link>
   <image>
   <url>/TechnoTravel-in/assets/images/favicon.ico</url>
   <title>TechnoTravel.in</title>
   <link>/TechnoTravel-in/</link>
   </image>
   <generator>Jekyll 3.6.2</generator>
   <lastBuildDate></lastBuildDate>
   <atom:link href="/TechnoTravel-in/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
   <ttl>60</ttl>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Remotely Flash Files onto Your Android via RemoteFlash [App]</title>
	  <link>/TechnoTravel-in/2013/06/remotely-flash-files-onto-your-android</link>
		
				
						<author>Rajat Patel</author>
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
	  <pubDate>2013-06-09T08:16:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/TechnoTravel-in/2013/06/remotely-flash-files-onto-your-android</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on">As a frequent flasher or ROMs, Mods and Kernels, I know the pain of losing out the USB cable only a couple minutes ago before Flashing "commence"!!&nbsp;Then there’s the trial and error process that comes with testing new themes, mods, and ROMs. However, this can all be avoided simply with&nbsp;RemoteFlash. The remote flashing app developed by XDA-Developers member <a href="http://forum.xda-developers.com/showthread.php?t=2307677" target="_blank">Prl91</a>.<br /><br />RemoteFlash allows you to flash ROMS, Mods, and Updates directly from your computer, over WiFi. As of the moment it only allows one file to be flashed at a time. The limit will be raised as the development goes on, but for the time being, RemoteFlash just about serves our purpose.&nbsp;<div><br /></div><div>Though one "downside" you might consider here is that this app uses "OpenRecoveryScript". So that if you have TWRP [TeamWin Recovery Project], then you are good to go, but the users with CWM [ClockWorkMod] Recovery installed might not have the smooth ride. Though&nbsp;CWM may be usable depending on the build installed.</div><div><br />To use RemoteFlash simply download two files at the end of this post. One is a standalone Java application that you run on your computer. The other file is the RemoteFlash apk. After downloading and installing both programs, run the RemoteFlash apk. You will only need to run the app once. After opening RemoteFlash the first time just reboot your device.</div><div><br /></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-FDAheKADpmQ/UbQ4fAYMWZI/AAAAAAAAB1w/-E6qFGpUehU/s1600/Screenshot_2013-06-09-13-02-40.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="400" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-FDAheKADpmQ/UbQ4fAYMWZI/AAAAAAAAB1w/-E6qFGpUehU/s400/Screenshot_2013-06-09-13-02-40.png" width="225" /></a></div><div><br /></div><div>As soon as your device boots back up, RemoteFlash service will be running in background. You can then open the PC client and click "Auto-Scan"(It may take anywhere between a second and two minutes to find your device), check/uncheck "Wipe Data/Cache", and click "Go".&nbsp;</div><div><br /></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-KBwarw_gwWU/UbQ4tlFd0CI/AAAAAAAAB14/1ygf5ozM1Ms/s1600/09-06-2013+01-13-59+PM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-KBwarw_gwWU/UbQ4tlFd0CI/AAAAAAAAB14/1ygf5ozM1Ms/s1600/09-06-2013+01-13-59+PM.png" /></a></div><div><br /></div><div><br /></div><div>You will then be prompted to select a file, and it will be flashed directly to your device.</div><div><br /></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-J3jKOoG06a4/UbQ4y4ojtLI/AAAAAAAAB2A/EtNBroUHJJY/s1600/09-06-2013+01-27-46+PM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-J3jKOoG06a4/UbQ4y4ojtLI/AAAAAAAAB2A/EtNBroUHJJY/s1600/09-06-2013+01-27-46+PM.png" /></a></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><br /></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: left;">After the flashing starts, the file will be downloaded and flashed automatically onto your device!!</div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: left;"><br /></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-XJns2qWqFlY/UbQ5tJGi3SI/AAAAAAAAB2Q/iH9d929YOe8/s1600/Screenshot_2013-06-09-13-24-55%5B1%5D.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="400" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-XJns2qWqFlY/UbQ5tJGi3SI/AAAAAAAAB2Q/iH9d929YOe8/s400/Screenshot_2013-06-09-13-24-55%5B1%5D.png" width="225" /></a></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: left;"><br /></div><h3 style="text-align: left;">Downloads</h3><div style="text-align: left;"><ul style="text-align: left;"><li><a href="https://www.box.net/shared/9p4srm7e4wodsoal4dkb" target="_blank">RemoteFlashPC-V0.3.jar</a></li><li><a href="https://www.box.net/s/8tg94szvm6aywz1o5oyv" target="_blank">RemoteFlashV0.7.apk</a></li></ul>[Source : <a href="http://forum.xda-developers.com/showthread.php?t=2307677" target="_blank">xda-developers</a>]</div></div>
	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Task Killers Are Bad For Android. Here Is The Reason Why You Shouldn't Use Them</title>
	  <link>/TechnoTravel-in/2012/11/task-killers-are-bad-for-android-here-is-the-reason-why-you-shoudnt-use-them</link>
		
				
						<author>Rajat Patel</author>
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
	  <pubDate>2012-11-09T16:53:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/TechnoTravel-in/2012/11/task-killers-are-bad-for-android-here-is-the-reason-why-you-shoudnt-use-them</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-cdkpuL-Vjlo/UJ0y65yLHII/AAAAAAAABX4/9StKfDXJySk/s1600/Screenshot_2012-11-09-22-01-08.png" imageanchor="1" style="clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;"><img border="0" height="320" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-cdkpuL-Vjlo/UJ0y65yLHII/AAAAAAAABX4/9StKfDXJySk/s320/Screenshot_2012-11-09-22-01-08.png" width="180" /></a></div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Most of Android fans generally use Task Manager to kill the Apps that are consuming RAM which results in the slow performance and poor battery life.&nbsp;By closing apps running in the background,&nbsp;you'll&nbsp;get improved performance and battery life – that’s the idea, anyway. But in reality, task killers can reduce your phone's performance and battery life. Here we're explaining the reason.</span><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Basically, the Task Killers kills the particular app that is residing in the memory, thus freeing up your phone's memory. But in fact, Android's own memory management is so powerful that you don't need to use any Task Killer. In fact, doing so disturbs the automatic process which is rather bad thing.</span><br /><h3 style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></h3><h3 style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></h3><h3 style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Process Management In Android Is Different From Windows</span></h3><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Most of Android users are very much familiar and used to Windows.&nbsp;On Windows, many programs running at one time – whether they’re windows on your desktop or applications in your system tray – can decrease your computer’s performance. Closing applications when&nbsp;you're&nbsp;not using them can help speed up your Windows computer.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-uKq_rLL9O9o/UJ0zWYgvnKI/AAAAAAAABYA/WZKGiKbkVxw/s1600/Screenshot_2012-11-09-22-04-33.png" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="360" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-uKq_rLL9O9o/UJ0zWYgvnKI/AAAAAAAABYA/WZKGiKbkVxw/s640/Screenshot_2012-11-09-22-04-33.png" width="640" /></a></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">However, Android is&nbsp;altogether&nbsp;a different scenario than Windows. In Windows, there is an obvious way to "close" an application, whereas, this is not the case with Android. You won't find any convincing way to actually "close" an app in Android. Some user might see this as a problem. But in fact, it's in design and not a problem by any means.&nbsp;When you leave an Android app, going back to your home screen or switching to another app, the app stays “running” in the background. In most cases, the app will be paused in the background, taking up no CPU or network resources. Some apps will continue using CPU and network resources in the background, of course – for example, music players, file-downloading programs, or apps that sync in the background.<br /><br />When you go back to an app you were recently using, Android “unpauses” that app and you resume where you left off. This is fast because the app is still stored in your RAM and ready to be used again.</span></div><h3 style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Task Killers Are Bad</span></h3><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-YpqN2yeXblE/UJ00AGAB3lI/AAAAAAAABYI/InVyW6Gd0Tc/s1600/Screenshot_2012-11-09-22-01-52.png" imageanchor="1" style="clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;"><img border="0" height="400" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-YpqN2yeXblE/UJ00AGAB3lI/AAAAAAAABYI/InVyW6Gd0Tc/s400/Screenshot_2012-11-09-22-01-52.png" width="225" /></a></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Most task killers notice that Android uses a lot of memory - in fact, Android stores running or recently used apps into memory which fills up the RAM. But this, by no means, a bad practice. Apps that are stored in the RAM can be quickly switched back to when needed rather than retrieving it from the storage, which is a very slow process compared to&nbsp;retrieval time from RAM.&nbsp;</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">And moreover, the freed up RAM is of no use and it doesn't saves the battery either. We all live in a myth that more free the RAM is, the less power it consumes. But this doesn't holds the truth. The totally full RAM consumes the same amount of power the half-full RAM consumes. So killing tasks or apps will save the battery power holds no truth. And in case of the RAM is full and more memory is needed to run the app than available, Android is smart enough to kill the app automatically which is not used for a while and free up the RAM for the new app. No task killers are&nbsp;required&nbsp;for this purpose.</span></div><div><br /></div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Task killers think they know better than Android. They run in the background, automatically quitting apps and removing them from Android’s memory. They may also allow you to force-quit apps on your own, but you&nbsp;shouldn't&nbsp;have to do this.<br /><br />Task killers&nbsp;aren't&nbsp;just useless – they can reduce performance as well. If a task killer removes an app from your RAM and you open that app again, the app will be slower to load as Android is forced to load it from your device’s storage. This will also use more battery power than if you just left the app in your RAM in the first place. Some apps will automatically restart after the task killer quits them, using more CPU and battery resources. Thus reducing the battery life.</span><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Though Task Killers Can Help Sometime</span></h3><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-7DAGQ716Srk/UJ00WUzw7MI/AAAAAAAABYQ/jzEhsAuUsaM/s1600/Screenshot_2012-11-09-22-02-27.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="640" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-7DAGQ716Srk/UJ00WUzw7MI/AAAAAAAABYQ/jzEhsAuUsaM/s640/Screenshot_2012-11-09-22-02-27.png" width="360" /></a></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">At this point of time while you are reading this article, some users won't agree with the fact that are presented to them before. Because they might have noticed a performance boost and increased battery life after using Task Killer.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">This might hold truth by the way! But only in case you have a badly compiled app installed on your phone.&nbsp;If you have a bad app that’s using CPU and other resources in the background, a task killer that closes the misbehaving app can improve your battery life and make your phone faster.</span></div><div><span style="background-color: white; color: #333333; font-family: Verdana; font-size: 14px; line-height: 17px;"><br /></span></div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">However, using a task killer to deal with a misbehaving app is like using a shotgun to kill a fly – you may fix your problem, but&nbsp;you're&nbsp;inflicting a lot of other damage in the process.<br /><br />Instead of using a task killer in this situation, you should identify the bad app and uninstall it, replacing it with an app that works properly. To pin down the app that’s misbehaving, you can try the <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.zomut.watchdoglite">Watchdog Task Manager</a> app – it will show you which apps are actually using CPU in the background, not which apps are harmlessly being stored in memory.</span><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Conclusion</span></h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Task killers can also cause other problems by killing applications that you want running in the background — for example, if you use an alarm clock app, you may find that your task killer forced the alarm clock app to quit, preventing the alarm from going off.<br /><br />CyanogenMod, the popular community-developed Android Custom ROM,&nbsp;won't&nbsp;even accept bug reports from users using task killers, saying that they cause more problems than they solve.<br /><br />In summary, you&nbsp;shouldn't&nbsp;use a task killer – if you have a misbehaving app wasting resources in the background, you should identify it and uninstall it. But&nbsp;don't&nbsp;just remove apps from your phone or tablet’s RAM – that&nbsp;doesn't&nbsp;help speed anything up.</span><br /><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div></div>
	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>6 Reasons Why Windows 8 Is More Secure Than Windows 7</title>
	  <link>/TechnoTravel-in/2012/11/6-reasons-why-windows-8-is-more-secure-than-windows-7</link>
		
				
						<author>Rajat Patel</author>
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
	  <pubDate>2012-11-09T08:01:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/TechnoTravel-in/2012/11/6-reasons-why-windows-8-is-more-secure-than-windows-7</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Official release of Windows 8 is a talk of the town right now. Some think it's just a new visual interface slapped on top of Windows 7, and if you think so, I'm afraid you are wrong!&nbsp;Windows 8 has seen a lot of security improvements, including an inbuilt antivirus, an application reputation system, and protection from boot-time rootkits and viruses/malwares.</span><br /><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">There are quite a few low-level security improvements under the hood as well. Microsoft&nbsp;hasn't&nbsp;spelled out all of them, but Windows 8 manages memory in a more secure way and includes features that make it more secure than Windows 7 and security vulnerabilities harder to exploit.</span><br /><div><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">So, here we're discussing the major security improvements that Windows has seen from transition to Windows 8 from Windows 7. There are 6 of them to be precise, so here we go.</span></div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Windows Defender (An Integrated Antivirus)</span></h3><div><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Finally, yeah finally, Microsoft has come up with an inbuilt or integrated Antivirus solution that ships with any edition of Windows 8. It's named Windows Defender - but it's just a rename of the popular free antivirus Microsoft Security Essentials. It's the same Microsoft Security Essential that you might be using on your Windows 7 PC (If not upgraded to Windows 8 yet!). Though you can any antivirus that you want on your Windows 8 machine. In such scenario, Windows Defender will disable itself automatically in order to avoid any conflicts with the third party antivirus. Though you need not to do so, as Windows Defender is a very capable product that you won't need any third party antivirus. Moreover, it's deeply integrated into the system that ensures that Windows users will finally have an integrated antivirus protection out-of-the-box.</span><br /><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-ZG-xWxl6RP4/UJy2qTWTGNI/AAAAAAAABWg/uk-Wlbno_jc/s1600/image34.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="288" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-ZG-xWxl6RP4/UJy2qTWTGNI/AAAAAAAABWg/uk-Wlbno_jc/s400/image34.png" width="400" /></a></div><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">There is an Anti-Malware Solution As Well</span></h3><div><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">In Windows 8, the booting priority of the antivirus is set higher than any other components. Which means that at boot time, first the antivirus will start and will check drivers for any&nbsp;suspicious malwares. This greatly protects the PC from the rootkit attack that starts before antivirus and hide from them.&nbsp;Windows Defender starts earlier in the boot process out-of-the-box, and third-party antivirus vendors can also add the Early-Launch Anti-Malware (ELAM) feature to their products. </span></div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Secure Boot</span></h3><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">On new Windows 8 computers that use the UEFI firmware instead of the old-style BIOS, Secure Boot guarantees that only specially signed and approved software can run at boot. On current computers, malware could install a malicious boot loader that loads before the Windows boot loader, starting a boot-level rootkit (or “bootkit”) before Windows even launches. The rootkit could then hide itself from Windows and antivirus software, pulling the strings in the background.<br /><br />On Intel x86 PCs, you’ll be able to add your own security keys to the UEFI firmware, so you could even have your system boot only secure Linux boot loaders that you’ve signed.</span><br /><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Improvements in Memory Management</span></h3><div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-hXu1m_mNCgI/UJy3KjfE5bI/AAAAAAAABWo/cLhFN3j_G_4/s1600/pile-of-ram.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="184" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-hXu1m_mNCgI/UJy3KjfE5bI/AAAAAAAABWo/cLhFN3j_G_4/s400/pile-of-ram.jpg" width="400" /></a></div><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">In this area, Microsoft has made many under-the-hood improvements compared to Windows 7 in Windows 8.&nbsp;</span><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">When a security hole is found, these improvements can make the security hole harder or even impossible to exploit. Some types of exploits that function on earlier versions of Windows wouldn’t function at all on Windows 8.</span></div><div><br /></div><span style="color: #444444;"><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Microsoft hasn’t spelled out all of these improvements, but they have mentioned a few:</span></span><br /><ul><li><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Mitigations that were once applied to Windows applications are now also applied to the Windows kernel.</span></li><li><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">ASLR (Address Space Layout Randomization) has been extended to more parts of Windows, randomly moving data and code around in memory to make it harder to exploit.</span></li><li><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Internet Explorer 10 includes improvements that make 75% of the security vulnerabilities reported over the last two years more difficult to exploit.</span></li><li><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">The Windows heap, where Windows applications receive their memory from, includes additional checks to defend against exploit techniques.</span></li></ul><div><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">If you're interested in exploring all the improvements, they <a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/b/b8/archive/2011/09/15/protecting-you-from-malware.aspx">can be found here</a>.</span></div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Sandboxing of The New Apps</span></h3><span style="color: #444444;"><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Apps for Windows 8’s new Modern interface (formerly known as Metro) are sandboxed and restricted in what they can do on your computer.<br /><br />On the Windows desktop, applications had full access to your system. If you downloaded and ran a Windows game, it could install drivers on your system, read files from everywhere on your hard drive, and install malware on your computer. Even if programs&nbsp;run with limited credentials thanks to UAC, they typically install with Administrator privileges and can do anything they want during installation.<br /><br />Windows 8 apps function more like web pages and mobile apps on other popular mobile platforms. When you install an app from the Windows Store, that app has limited access to your system. It can’t run in the background and monitor all your keystrokes, logging your credit card number and online banking passwords like applications on the traditional Windows desktop can. it doesn’t have access to every file on your system.<br /><br />Apps for Windows 8’s new Modern interface are also only available through the Windows Store, which is more controversial. However, users can’t install malicious Modern apps from outside the store. They’d have to go through the Windows Store, where Microsoft has the ability to pull them if they’re discovered to be malicious.</span></span><br /><span style="color: #444444;"><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></span><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-xDxx6SpC0Fc/UJy3rKzTpII/AAAAAAAABWw/wKRWCI-Hd-M/s1600/image35.png" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-xDxx6SpC0Fc/UJy3rKzTpII/AAAAAAAABWw/wKRWCI-Hd-M/s1600/image35.png" /></a></div><span style="color: #444444;"><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></span><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Smartscreen Filter</span></h3><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-L2bA2tQjdgA/UJy35z6TlKI/AAAAAAAABW4/uv-0m-xpI2o/s1600/image47.png" imageanchor="1" style="clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;"><img border="0" height="175" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-L2bA2tQjdgA/UJy35z6TlKI/AAAAAAAABW4/uv-0m-xpI2o/s400/image47.png" width="400" /></a></div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span style="color: #444444;">Previously used only in Internet Explorer, the SmartScreen filter is now implemented at the operating system-level. It will be used to scan EXE files you download from Internet Explorer, Mozilla Firefox, Google Chrome, and other programs. When you download and double-click an EXE file, Windows will scan the file and send its signature to Microsoft’s servers. If the application is known-good, such as the installer for iTunes, Photoshop, or another popular program, Windows will allow it to run. If it’s known-bad, perhaps if it contains malware, Windows will prevent it from running. If it’s new and Windows doesn’t know what it is, Windows will warn you and allow you to bypass the warning.</span><br /><br /><br /><span style="color: #444444;">This feature should help less-experienced users from downloading and running malicious programs from the Internet. Even new pieces of malware will be detected by the SmartScreen filter as an unknown new program that should be approached with caution.</span></span><br /><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span style="color: #444444;"><br /></span></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span style="color: #444444;">So, the conclusion is that Windows 8 is&nbsp;definitely&nbsp;more secure than Windows 7.&nbsp;An integrated antivirus and application reputation system, along with a tamed app ecosystem that replaces the wild-west nature of previous versions of Windows, will probably make the most difference for inexperienced users that may not have ran an antivirus or knew which applications were safe to install on previous versions of Windows. Low-level improvements to the way Windows manages memory will help everyone, even power users like us!</span></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><span style="color: #444444;"><br /></span></span></div></div>
	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Early Beta of Firefox OS for Smartphones Running On ZTE Smartphone [Video]</title>
	  <link>/TechnoTravel-in/2012/09/early-beta-of-firefox-os-for-smartphones-running-on-zte-smartphone-video</link>
		
				
						<author>Rajat Patel</author>
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
	  <pubDate>2012-09-23T02:59:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/TechnoTravel-in/2012/09/early-beta-of-firefox-os-for-smartphones-running-on-zte-smartphone-video</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Well, there has been a while when the Firefox OS came into light on <a href="http://forum.xda-developers.com/showthread.php?t=1805282">XDA-Developers forums</a> of Galaxy Nexus. And now it seems like the development is gathering the&nbsp;pace. As an indicator of this, we've found a video of an ZTE Developer Smartphone running the early beta of the brand new Firefox OS.&nbsp;</span><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">If you're curious about this brand new OS in the Smartphone Market, this video might satisfy your&nbsp;curiosity. Here it is,</span><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><iframe allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" frameborder="0" height="360" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/5MzuGWFIfio?feature=player_detailpage" width="600"></iframe><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Though it might look like a clone of Android, but it's way different than that. Android is built on Java whereas Firefox is being built on HTML5. So, it's all together a different technology, and we're excited about it's developments and keen to cover all the major development of Firefox OS on TechnoTravel.in. Stay tuned!!</span><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div>
	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>How To Check Disk For Errors In Windows [A Complete Guide]</title>
	  <link>/TechnoTravel-in/2012/08/how-to-check-disk-for-errors-in-windows-a-complete-guide</link>
		
				
						<author>Rajat Patel</author>
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
	  <pubDate>2012-08-26T06:57:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/TechnoTravel-in/2012/08/how-to-check-disk-for-errors-in-windows-a-complete-guide</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">The <a href="http://www.technotravel.in/2011/08/how-computer-hard-drive-actually-works.html">computer hard disk</a> is the mind of your system which memorize every data about your computer even if it is turned off. In day-to-day basis, we often doesn't take care of it more because it is less prone to errors than the other components of your machine and works almost flawlessly every time. But it is also a mechanical part of your system which might come under the "Error Attack". So here we're discussing about the hard disk errors and the ways to&nbsp;diagnose and prevent them from&nbsp;occurring as well.&nbsp;</span><br /><h3 style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">How Could You Know That Your Disk Is Suffering From Errors?</span></h3><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">There is a nominal reduce in performance which goes unnoticed many times if your disk is suffering from errors. If the amount of errors is large, the transfer speed of your hard drive reduces eventually as the time goes on. The slump in performance might get unnoticed if the your system is equipped with big memory and mighty processor. Which means that if your system is equipped with robust hardware, even a slight performance dip is worth considering!</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">The checking disk of errors is very easy and can be performed by a novice user as well. There are actually two methods to do that. One is for regular users which deals with windows' user interface using Windows Explorer and the other one is more robust but a bit harder (Not for geeky personalities though), using Command Line Interface.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">As the mass community is not-so geeky, we'll first discuss about the easier way using Windows Explorer.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">First of all open "Computer" in Windows Explorer. This will show the drives that are currently connected to your computer.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-vim9kv9iW2s/UDnGBekwRgI/AAAAAAAABR0/c6W0Wrob-O4/s1600/26-08-2012+11-30-34+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-vim9kv9iW2s/UDnGBekwRgI/AAAAAAAABR0/c6W0Wrob-O4/s1600/26-08-2012+11-30-34+AM.png" /></a></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Now Right Click on the drive that you want to check for errors. Click Properties.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-zaFvyNOgUac/UDnGKK3s4JI/AAAAAAAABR8/PDMQfiKfRJU/s1600/26-08-2012+11-33-11+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-zaFvyNOgUac/UDnGKK3s4JI/AAAAAAAABR8/PDMQfiKfRJU/s1600/26-08-2012+11-33-11+AM.png" /></a></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Navigate to Tools tab where you'll find the option to check disk for errors. Click on Check Now (Administrator privileges&nbsp;are required).</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/--Q09ZMHB35c/UDnGRmuyVBI/AAAAAAAABSE/aKixNdr_kfM/s1600/26-08-2012+11-33-38+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/--Q09ZMHB35c/UDnGRmuyVBI/AAAAAAAABSE/aKixNdr_kfM/s1600/26-08-2012+11-33-38+AM.png" /></a></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">The pop-up will come up with two options with the option already checked saying "Automatically fix file system errors" and the other one is "Scan for and attempt recovery of bad errors".</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">The "Automatically fix file system errors" attempts to solve the detected errors automatically on its own. If this option is left unchecked, the Disk Check utility will only check and display errors, but won't solve it.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">If both the options are checked, it will thoroughly check the disk for errors and will also attempt to solve any physical errors on your hard drive if there exists any. Due to such functionality, it is&nbsp;get-able&nbsp;that it will obviously take more time than the regular Disk Checking but it is more accurate as well.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">The time taken by this process depends upon the size of the file it is checking. Means, larger the size of file is, the more time it takes to check.</span></div><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><b>Note</b> If one or more of the files on the hard disk are open, you will receive the following message:</span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Chkdsk cannot run because the volume is in use by another process. Would you like to schedule this volume to be checked the next time the system restarts?</span></blockquote><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-vYUHvuaUmq8/UDnGbGiKZyI/AAAAAAAABSM/TkkPzUwzt1M/s1600/26-08-2012+11-33-59+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-vYUHvuaUmq8/UDnGbGiKZyI/AAAAAAAABSM/TkkPzUwzt1M/s1600/26-08-2012+11-33-59+AM.png" /></a></div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Click on schedule disk check to schedule it on the next reboot.</span><br /><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Using Command Line Interface</span>&nbsp;</h3><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">You can do this above mentioned processes and more with chkdsk.exe utility which runs via command line interface. The command that we'll use is CHKDSK.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><pre><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Syntax<br />      CHKDSK [drive:][[<i>path</i>]<i>filename</i>] [/F] [/V] [/R] [/L[:<i>size</i>]] <br /><br />Key<br />   [<i>drive</i>:]   The drive to check. <br />   <br />   <i>filename</i>   File(s) to check for fragmentation (FAT only). <br />   <br />   /F         Automatically Fix file system errors on the disk.<br /><br />   /X         Fix file system errors on the disk, (Win2003 and above)<br />              dismounts the volume first, closing all open file handles.<br />   <br />   /R         Scan for and attempt Recovery of bad sectors.<br />   <br />   /V         Display the full path and name of every file on the disk. <br />   <br />   /L:<i>size</i>    NTFS only: change the log file size to the specified number of kilobytes. <br />              If size is not specified, displays the current log size and the drive type<br />              (FAT or NTFS).<br /><br />   /C         Skip directory corruption checks. <br /><br />   /I         Skip corruption checks that compare directory entries to the<br />              file record segment (FRS) in the volume's master file table (MFT)</span></pre><pre></pre><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Example:</span></h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">CHKDSK C: /F</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-sfB1dXRmG8I/UDnHUuq8wPI/AAAAAAAABSU/kVxEAhqKxrY/s1600/26-08-2012+12-19-48+PM.png" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-sfB1dXRmG8I/UDnHUuq8wPI/AAAAAAAABSU/kVxEAhqKxrY/s1600/26-08-2012+12-19-48+PM.png" /></a></div><div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Fixing Errors /F</span></h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">If the drive is the boot partition, you will be prompted to run the check during the next boot<br /><br />If you specify the /f switch, chkdsk will show an error if open files are found on the disk.<br /><br />Chkdsk /f will lock the volume, making data unavailable until chkdsk is finished.<br /><br />If you use chkdsk /f on a disk with a very large number of files (millions), chkdsk may take a long time to complete.<br /><br />When you delete a file or folder that has 'custom' permissions, the ACL is not deleted, it is cached. Chkdsk /f will remove ACLs that are no longer used. This is often the cause of the rather worrying message: "Windows found problems with the file system. Run chkdsk with the /F (fix) option to correct these."<br /><br />It is normal for chkdsk /F to remove unused index entries and unused security descriptors every time you run it, these do not indicate a problem with the file system. </span><br /><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Scan only (without /f switch)</span></h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">If a file needs to be fixed chkdsk will alert you with a message but will not fix the error(s). </span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br />chkdsk may report lost allocation units on the disk - it will produce this report even if the files are in-use (open). If corruption is found, consider closing all files and repairing the disk with /F.<br /><br />Running chkdsk on a data volume that is in use by another program or process may incorrectly report errors when none are present. To avoid this, close all programs or processes that have open handles to the volume.</span><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-yibYpWDXuUs/UDnIR3thgjI/AAAAAAAABSk/4hQL2clJVsk/s1600/26-08-2012+12-20-27+PM.png" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em; text-align: center;"><img border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-yibYpWDXuUs/UDnIR3thgjI/AAAAAAAABSk/4hQL2clJVsk/s1600/26-08-2012+12-20-27+PM.png" /></a><br />&nbsp;<span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br />On computers running Windows 2003 SP1, chkdsk automatically creates a shadow copy, so you can check volumes that are 'in use' by another program or process. This enables an accurate report against a live file server. On earlier versions of Windows, chkdsk would always lock the volume, making data unavailable.</span><br /><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Run at Bootup</span></h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Running at bootup is often the easiest way to close all open file handles.<br /><br />Use the GUI, chkntfs or the FSUTIL dirty commands to set or query the volumes 'dirty' bit so that Windows will run chkdsk when the computer is restarted.</span><br /><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Event Logs</span></h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Chkdsk will log error messages in the Event Viewer - System Log. <br />Chkdsk /f removes ACLs that are no longer used and reports this in the Event Viewer - Application Log.</span><br /><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Cluster (or block) Size</span></h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">CHKDSK produces a report that shows the the block /cluster size<br />typically: "4096 bytes in each allocation unit." <br />When the cluster size is greater than 4 KB on an NTFS volume, none of the NTFS compression functions are available.</span><br /><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Exit codes</span></h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">0 No errors were found<br />1 Errors were found and fixed.<br />2 Could not check the disk, did not or could not fix errors.</span><br /><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Notes:</span></h3></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Consider the time required to run Chkdsk to repair any errors that occur. Chkdsk times are determined by the number of files on the volume and by the number of files in the largest folder. Chkdsk performance was improved by 30% under Windows 2003 and around 50% in 2008 R2. <br /><br />To issue chkdsk on a hard drive you must be a member of the Administrators group.<br /><br />When CHKDSK is set to run at boot-up there is a delay to allow the check to be cancelled - this can be configured in the registry:<br /><br />HKLM\System\CurrentControlSet\Control\Session Manager<br />REG_DWORD:AutoChkTimeOutData<br />The value is the time in seconds that you want CHKDSK to wait (0 = no delay) default is 10 seconds.<br /><br />Chkdsk is also available from the Recovery Console (with different parameters.)</span><br /><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Disk Errors</span></h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">"The file system structure on the disk is corrupt and unusable"<br /><br />If you have disk corruption, run the drive manufacturers diagnostics: <br /><a href="http://www3.toshiba.co.jp/storage/english/support/index.htm">Toshiba</a> | <a href="http://www.hitachigst.com/portal/site/en/support/">Hitachi</a> | <a href="http://www.pc.ibm.com/ww/hdd/hddredirect.html">ibm</a> | <a href="http://www.seagate.com/www/en-us/support/">Seagate/Maxtor/Freeagent</a> | <a href="http://support.wdc.com/">Western digital</a></span></div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">How To Prevent Disk Errors From Occurring</span></h3><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Well, to fully prevent disks from errors is quite hard task, but you always can take some precautionary measures to reduce the frequency of the&nbsp;occurrence of such errors.</span></div><div><ul><li><b style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Don't ever directly cut the power supply from hard disk.</b><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"> When the hard disk is on and under full operation, the sudden power cuts can hurt your hard disk big times! So prevent your PC from sudden power cuts, which is the only thing that is in our hands to reduce the frequency of error occurrence.</span></li><li><b style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Frequently check and fix disk for errors.</b><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"> Use any one of the above mentioned method at least one a month to let your disk operate smoothly.</span></li></ul></div><div><br /></div></div>
	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Google Translate Gets Updated For Android, Now Supports Translating Photos</title>
	  <link>/TechnoTravel-in/2012/08/google-translate-gets-updated-for-android-now-supports-translating-photos</link>
		
				
						<author>Rajat Patel</author>
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
	  <pubDate>2012-08-10T16:46:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/TechnoTravel-in/2012/08/google-translate-gets-updated-for-android-now-supports-translating-photos</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">The <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.google.android.apps.translate">Google Translate</a> App is now updated on Android as it supports translating photos as well. Which means, in real world, if you see any poster written in any other language which is unknown to you, just point your Android's camera towards it, take a snap and Google Translate will translate the contents of that pic. Though you'll need to highlight the text you want to translate.</span><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">For now, only <a href="http://www.technotravel.in/search/label/Android">Android</a> users can take advantage of this feature.&nbsp;It works with most of the languages that are supported by Google Translate.  The app doesn’t have the ability to automatically detect what language is captured in an image, so the user needs to know the language they’re looking at, but the feature otherwise works on any high-contrast text. Stylized or low-contrast text might trip it up.&nbsp;</span><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-FaF3q8VqeXw/UCU6E1acUKI/AAAAAAAABKw/DCT2m6hNOlo/s1600/translate.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-FaF3q8VqeXw/UCU6E1acUKI/AAAAAAAABKw/DCT2m6hNOlo/s1600/translate.jpg" /></a></div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Users will also need to make sure that the text they want to translate must fit in the single photograph. So, it will not be useful for the big posters or the big&nbsp;length&nbsp;text. Thus, as of now, it'll only work on the smaller images where the text is clear and all in one image. Though, as a popular Google product, it will only get better!</span><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Even though there exists some limitations, it is still a very major leap forward from Google.&nbsp;Typing in a phrase from a foreign language can take some time and is subject to typos. Taking a photograph is quicker and more accurate.</span><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">This app will work on the Android versions 2.3(Gingerbread) and above. So why wait, just download or update your Google Translate on your Android.</span><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.google.android.apps.translate">Download or Update Google Translate</a>&nbsp;from <a href="https://play.google.com/store">Google Play</a></span><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div>
	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Top 5 Android Web Browsers For Better Browsing Experience</title>
	  <link>/TechnoTravel-in/2012/08/top-5-android-web-browsers-for-better-browsing-experience</link>
		
				
						<author>Rajat Patel</author>
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
	  <pubDate>2012-08-09T09:54:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/TechnoTravel-in/2012/08/top-5-android-web-browsers-for-better-browsing-experience</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-1VPZWQEvEI8/UCOHFilduzI/AAAAAAAABHM/K50osSzpW5o/s1600/browsers.png" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-1VPZWQEvEI8/UCOHFilduzI/AAAAAAAABHM/K50osSzpW5o/s1600/browsers.png" /></a></div><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">There exist tons of web browsers on <a href="https://play.google.com/store/search?q=browser&amp;c=apps" target="_blank">Google's Play Store</a> to download from for the better web browsing experience, but which one to choose from them?, remains the ultimate question. So here we're discussing about the top 5 web browsers that will make your browsing experience a lot easier and a lot better.&nbsp;</span><br /><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Though choosing the best from the tons might be a difficult task as the choices of browsers may differ with each personality depending upon their browsing habits and likings. Some like more&nbsp;minimalist approach whereas some want a feature-rich browser with lot of customizations to choose from. So, getting all this in a one .apk will be quite uphill task. So, we've decided to bring you not one or two but five, best in their class, web browsers to choose from according to your requirements.</span><br /><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif; font-size: large;">Mozilla Firefox</span><br /><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-9LnMmwzVBGM/UCOHqAMyrWI/AAAAAAAABHs/cvsu3KWoN3o/s1600/firefox.png" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-9LnMmwzVBGM/UCOHqAMyrWI/AAAAAAAABHs/cvsu3KWoN3o/s1600/firefox.png" /></a></div><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">It has been a long journey for <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=org.mozilla.firefox" target="_blank">Firefox</a>, and it has improved a lot in its development time. Now the currently available version of Firefox is fast, it supports full sync, so if Firefox is your browser of choice in your PC, you can synchronize the open tabs right away to enjoy them on your Android.&nbsp;It's the first mobile browser to truly support Do Not Track, and the "Awesome Page" start screen that shows you all of your recently visited tabs helps you get right back to what you were doing if you had to put your phone down. It even supports add-ons and Personas, although there aren't too many of them yet. A few more options, and Firefox would be a good contender for our favorite, but it's clearly already one of yours, and for good reason.</span><br /><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif; font-size: large;">Google Chrome</span><br /><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-NfbBh3cQt3c/UCOHoEnrgVI/AAAAAAAABHc/kFUZqMr_usw/s1600/chrome.png" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-NfbBh3cQt3c/UCOHoEnrgVI/AAAAAAAABHc/kFUZqMr_usw/s1600/chrome.png" /></a></div><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Where Firefox goes, Chrome does follow. <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.android.chrome" target="_blank">Chrome</a> has finally left its beta state and it's now in more pleasing Stable state. As we see the "Stable" tag on Chrome state, we can anticipate it as the default browser on the next version of Android.&nbsp;If you are running ICS or Jelly Bean on your device, Chrome for Android is a must-download. It supports Incognito Mode browsing, bookmark syncing via Chrome Sync, and in its most recent updates, now supports search syncing, tab syncing, and more—anything that Chrome can sync on your desktop will be right there waiting for you on your Android device. Chrome for Android is also optimized for mobile, meaning it's blazing fast. The only drawback is that Google hasn't made it available for phones running Gingerbread or tablets stuck with Honeycomb.</span><br /><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif; font-size: large;">Dolphin Browser HD</span><br /><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-lf4ZkKZyD5E/UCOHpM_x0RI/AAAAAAAABHk/luPbWC6mMMM/s1600/dolphin.png" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-lf4ZkKZyD5E/UCOHpM_x0RI/AAAAAAAABHk/luPbWC6mMMM/s1600/dolphin.png" /></a></div><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">When the browser talk is going on, we can't miss the thirdparty - other than Mozilla or Google - browser, <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=mobi.mgeek.TunnyBrowser" target="_blank">The Dolphin Browser HD</a>. It was launched a long ago, before Firefox and Chrome of course, and has been the popular among the Android Lovers. It offers the desktop chrome like user interface and plenty&nbsp;customizations in the form of Add-ons. You can load as many add-ons as you need to customize it as per your needs and requirements. Its built in tools like Dolphin Sonar - speech-to-text converter - and on-screen gesture to open bookmarks are its standout features and serves you well. The higher end Android phones like Galaxy s2, Galaxy Nexus and Galaxy S3 can exert its HD screen features to maximum with their beautiful HD screens, but even though you need not to have those phones to get amazed by it! Your own Android will equally amaze you with its features. That's why it's my personal favorite to use on my beautiful Galaxy Nexus!</span><br /><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif; font-size: large;">Opera Mobile/Mini</span><br /><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-Ld0rJIcELXU/UCOHrK4phVI/AAAAAAAABH0/q7Hwj3PUzdQ/s1600/opera.png" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-Ld0rJIcELXU/UCOHrK4phVI/AAAAAAAABH0/q7Hwj3PUzdQ/s1600/opera.png" /></a></div><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Before Android came into spotlight, Opera Mini was the dominant force and the browser of choice for the dumb phones or say, not-so-smart phones. And even today that for that dumb phones, it is the best. But as we're talking about Android platform, I must mention that it lags behind the superior three - Dolphin Browser, Firefox and Chrome. Though, if you're a Opera fan on your PC, <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.opera.browser" target="_blank">Opera Mobile</a> is the perfect choice for you.&nbsp;Opera Mobile supports Opera Link, so you can sync your bookmarks, speed dial, and other user preferences with your desktop Opera install. Aside from that, Opera Mobile is fast, free, and goes out of its way to compress data in the background so you can browse your favorite sites without blowing past your wireless carrier's data caps. Opera even has its own mini-app store, full of third party add-ons that improve the browser or games that make it more fun to use. Have an older device? <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.opera.mini.android" target="_blank">Opera Mini</a> might be a better choice—you get most of the features, but even more speed.</span><br /><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif; font-size: large;">Stock Browser</span><br /><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-m3AGu-jRHfg/UCOHnM4nLlI/AAAAAAAABHU/9QTLdiAYbrU/s1600/boat.png" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-m3AGu-jRHfg/UCOHnM4nLlI/AAAAAAAABHU/9QTLdiAYbrU/s1600/boat.png" /></a></div><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Well, lets not forget this one, the native browser of your Android. Though it might not be feature rich as compared to its counterparts, but it still does the fair job to get featured in this list. I don't have knowledge about the earlier stock browsers, but the stock browsers on Ice Cream Sandwich and Jelly Bean are blazingly fast and supports flash as well. Though you'll need to do a tweak to watch flash content on Jelly Bean, but it still serves well. It's my first choice to view flash content, and I don't know why, but it seems faster than any other browser on my Galaxy Nexus running 4.1.1 Jelly Bean! So you can compromise customizations for speed, Stock Browser is a great choice!</span><br /><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">So, there we have it! Here are the 5 superior browsers for Android till now for you to choose from. If sync bothers you, go for Firefox or Chrome, if customizations and feature-rich browser is your first choice, go for Dolphin Browser HD. And if you can sacrifice anything for speed, Stock Browser and Opera Mobile are good choice. So, which is your favorite browser? Share your experince with your fav browser via comments below, and ya, it is not essential that you choose from the given list. If any other browser satisfies you more, you're the owner of your phone to use it, but don't forget to mention it into the comments form below!&nbsp;</span><br /><br /></div>
	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Pros And Cons Of Cloud Based/Online Anti-Virus</title>
	  <link>/TechnoTravel-in/2012/08/pros-and-cons-of-cloud-basedonline-antivirus</link>
		
				
						<author>Rajat Patel</author>
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
	  <pubDate>2012-08-07T17:09:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/TechnoTravel-in/2012/08/pros-and-cons-of-cloud-basedonline-antivirus</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><table cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="float: right; margin-left: 1em; text-align: right;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-3vdOaBcHcaI/UCFJvx5-udI/AAAAAAAABE8/tbS7jK8sPDA/s1600/7557181168_91f4af2d99_n.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="180" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-3vdOaBcHcaI/UCFJvx5-udI/AAAAAAAABE8/tbS7jK8sPDA/s320/7557181168_91f4af2d99_n.jpg" width="320" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">Image Courtesy : <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/61423903@N06/7557181168/" target="_blank">Flickr</a> by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/61423903@N06/" target="_blank">FutUndBeidl</a></td></tr></tbody></table><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">It seems like we're living in the cloud world as more and more apps that we use in a day-to-day life are migrating&nbsp;themselves&nbsp;to the cloud these days. Email, chatting, Office solutions, pictures - almost every thing is using cloud-based solutions these days. And even Antiviruses can't be excluded from this list. There are several online or cloud-based antivirus solutions available on the internet that can scan your computer from the internet browser. But, though online antiviruses are useful, they can't replace the Antivirus that resides in your computer hard drive.</span><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Nevertheless, cloud-based antivirus applications offer a number of benefits and can be very useful for quickly scanning a PC for malware. But just don’t make them your only form of protection!</span><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><b>What Are Cloud Based Antiviruses?</b></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">If you want to access these cloud based antiviruses, all you need is a browser window and a working internet connection. There are plenty antiviruses available like - <a href="http://quickscan.bitdefender.com/" target="_blank">BitDefender Quick Scan</a> and <a href="http://www.eset.com/us/online-scanner/" target="_blank">ESET Online Sacnner</a> - these are cloud based antiviruses that will serve you well. Some antiviruses will download small .exe files to your computer to run the scan and some will use ActiveX controls to run the virus scanner in the browser window right away.</span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-4DVGvNFhs9g/UCFJ-CVTYBI/AAAAAAAABFE/EaJAUn5lcP4/s1600/07-08-2012+10-17-30+PM.png" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="256" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-4DVGvNFhs9g/UCFJ-CVTYBI/AAAAAAAABFE/EaJAUn5lcP4/s320/07-08-2012+10-17-30+PM.png" width="320" /></a></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">In the case of ESET Online Scanner - it will prompt you to download the .exe file to carry out the quick scan on your PC.&nbsp;Bitdefender QuickScan installs a browser extension.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">After you launch the cloud-based antivirus, it will scan your system for potential threats and alert you to them. Depending on the cloud-based antivirus, it may not remove viruses it finds, or it may only perform a quick scan for viruses and other malware, not an in-depth one.</span><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><b><br /></b></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><b>Lack Of Real-Time Scanning</b></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">The biggest drawback of the online antivirus is its&nbsp;inability to monitor your PC in real-time. Though some people might feel that the online security is the one and only threat nowadays and preventing viruses penetrating in their PC through Internet will assure the full security to their computer, then I'm afraid you're wrong here. There are plenty different threats - Viruses, Trojans or Spywares - that have ability to penetrate through the USB drives and damage your computer big time. So it's always advisable to use a well-known native Antivirus on your PC that supports Real-time scanning to help you detect and prevent from such threats.&nbsp;</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">If you are thinking cloud antiviruses as the one and only protection method to&nbsp;prevent&nbsp;your computer from threats, then I advise you to think twice before making such decision only due to the reason explain above - Lack of Real-Time Scanning.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><b>Some Other Limitations of Cloud Antiviruses</b></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Some online antiviruses don’t even perform the functions you might expect from an antivirus. For example, ESET Online Scanner can scan your entire system for malware and quarantine it. However, Bitdefender QuickScan just scans your system’s startup files and memory for viruses – it doesn’t look for dormant viruses hiding elsewhere on your system. If Bitdefender QuickScan finds a virus, it won’t remove it for you – it will recommend you download a full Bitdefender product to remove the virus.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><b>Though There are Some Benefits Too!</b></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Even though Online Virus Scanning Tools might not fancy their chance to be your primary antivirus, there lies some benefits of them that are worth mentioning here.</span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-sbeLK3iJpY4/UCFKQXHf9dI/AAAAAAAABFM/9i3Qg36wftQ/s1600/07-08-2012+10-23-28+PM.png" imageanchor="1" style="clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;"><img border="0" height="197" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-sbeLK3iJpY4/UCFKQXHf9dI/AAAAAAAABFM/9i3Qg36wftQ/s320/07-08-2012+10-23-28+PM.png" width="320" /></a></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><ul><li><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><b>Quick Scanning</b> : Even though it's named as "Quick Scan", the Quick Scan from our native antivirus can take ages if you've lot of stuff loaded on your computer. The Online Antiviruses wins the race here as they scans quickly using the shared Cloud resources that uses robust hardware. So the scan time will always remain low compared to the native Antivirus.</span></li><li><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><b>Great Second Option</b> : As they are speedy, when we've hardly any time to perform a quick scan on our PC, these Online Antiviruses comes in handy. As they are lightening quick, it'll definitely respond quicker than its native counterpart which lies in your machine with less quicker resources!</span></li><li><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><b>Always Up-To-Date</b> : As they are hosted on cloud, one would imagine them to be up-to-date with the latest virus definitions that can really help you detect the newer threat that can easily give a slip to your not-so up-to-date native antivirus.</span></li></ul></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Some people might think how they can use both antiviruses at the same time? Well, there may occur some conflict if you use two antiviruses on a same PC, which they share the resources which results in a conflict. But in the case of Online Antiviruses, as it uses the resources from cloud, there is no reason to worry about any sought of conflict in here!</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><b>Conclusion</b></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-NL-xiRrxWVA/UCFKqPZ17RI/AAAAAAAABFU/u_zr7GiOwJc/s1600/07-08-2012+10-19-24+PM.png" imageanchor="1" style="clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;"><img border="0" height="195" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-NL-xiRrxWVA/UCFKqPZ17RI/AAAAAAAABFU/u_zr7GiOwJc/s320/07-08-2012+10-19-24+PM.png" width="320" /></a></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><b><br /></b></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">As there are more robust and feature rich antiviruses available for free for your PC, there is no need to treat the cloud based antivirus as your primary antivirus. There are quite a few Antiviruses that are available for free like <a href="http://windows.microsoft.com/en-US/windows/products/security-essentials" target="_blank">Microsoft Security Essentials</a> (my personal favorite), <a href="http://www.avast.com/free-antivirus-download" target="_blank">avast!</a> and <a href="http://free.avg.com/ww-en/homepage" target="_blank">AVG</a>.</span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Though there is always good to have a option or two, especially when you're stuck in the worst case scenario, these Online Antiviruses will always come to the rescue!</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div></div>
	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Download Torrents To Your Android Easily via BitTorrent</title>
	  <link>/TechnoTravel-in/2012/08/download-torrents-to-your-android-via-bittorrent</link>
		
				
						<author>Rajat Patel</author>
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
	  <pubDate>2012-08-06T12:28:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/TechnoTravel-in/2012/08/download-torrents-to-your-android-via-bittorrent</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-7wCJxBVau6U/UB-4A-IzEGI/AAAAAAAABD0/cuW9q9zj1fQ/s1600/Bittorrent-Logo-Purple.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;"><img border="0" height="136" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-7wCJxBVau6U/UB-4A-IzEGI/AAAAAAAABD0/cuW9q9zj1fQ/s320/Bittorrent-Logo-Purple.jpg" width="320" /></a></div><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">There has been a long wait till Android had a trustworthy and robust Torrent client, but it seems like the wait is now over! The leading Torrent client on PC has now released its Android version for download on Google Play. And with that Android now has official BitTorrent support. Now it's gonna be fun downloading torrents on the go right from your Android smartphone.</span><br /><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Though there were some other torrent clients in&nbsp;existent before BitTorrent joined the party, but they were buggy and were not as robust as BitTorrent. But now, as the BitTorrent is officially released, lets hope that torrent support on Android will eventually get better as the app is in its beta stage.</span><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-vfx40OL_-mY/UB-2fFusnII/AAAAAAAABDc/_Pldqp8vTmY/s1600/Screenshot_2012-08-06-17-16-15.png" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-vfx40OL_-mY/UB-2fFusnII/AAAAAAAABDc/_Pldqp8vTmY/s1600/Screenshot_2012-08-06-17-16-15.png" /></a></div><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">As far as our testing is concerned, we didn't had much expectations from this "beta" app, but I must mention that even this beta app is so smooth and easy to operate that easily outclass the other so called competitiors. Even large files download with ease and you can easily resume the paused download right away. It also captures the .torrents from the browse which add to the ease of functionality.</span><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-dEf20XV-VmI/UB-25_mvDXI/AAAAAAAABDk/Ir4pfpSTumE/s1600/Screenshot_2012-08-06-17-19-10.png" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-dEf20XV-VmI/UB-25_mvDXI/AAAAAAAABDk/Ir4pfpSTumE/s1600/Screenshot_2012-08-06-17-19-10.png" /></a></div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Though as the app is in its early beta stages, we should not be expecting the features same as the Desktop app, but there are some basic operations such as setting download limits, and start at boot etc. Though we're pretty sure it will increase in numbers once the app moves out of the beta stages. As I use to download torrents a lot, I've been waiting for such reliable Torrent client for android, and much to the delight of the users like me, we've got one.</span><br /><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-_i67SrKut80/UB-3ap4ue4I/AAAAAAAABDs/Ynrm_Bj-aDk/s1600/Screenshot_2012-08-06-17-20-06.png" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-_i67SrKut80/UB-3ap4ue4I/AAAAAAAABDs/Ynrm_Bj-aDk/s1600/Screenshot_2012-08-06-17-20-06.png" /></a></div><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">At TechnoTravel.in we recommend readers to download this app which is, of course, available for free as of now and submit feedback via comment on Google Play to help the app grow more and serve Torrent freaks!</span><br /><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.bittorrent.client" target="_blank">Download BitTorrent Beta</a> (From <a href="https://play.google.com/" target="_blank">Google Play</a>)</span><br /><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div>
	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>How To Access Folders Of Your Android On Your PC via FTP</title>
	  <link>/TechnoTravel-in/2012/08/how-to-access-folders-of-your-android-on-your-pc-via-ftp</link>
		
				
						<author>Rajat Patel</author>
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
	  <pubDate>2012-08-06T06:20:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/TechnoTravel-in/2012/08/how-to-access-folders-of-your-android-on-your-pc-via-ftp</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-c5lXw4qx5nk/UB9eBBYQi6I/AAAAAAAABCY/IlQgcbvqFQc/s1600/06-08-2012+10-48-30+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-c5lXw4qx5nk/UB9eBBYQi6I/AAAAAAAABCY/IlQgcbvqFQc/s1600/06-08-2012+10-48-30+AM.png" /></a></div><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">You can always access the folders of your Android phone on your PC via third party app named <a href="http://www.technotravel.in/2012/06/wirelessly-operate-your-android-from.html" target="_blank">AirDroid</a> from your browser. But what if you want to access these folders in the Windows Explorer wirelessly? You can always connect your Android to your PC via USB cable, but here we're more focused on the use of Wi-Fi to prevent you from the&nbsp;hassle of carrying USB cable wherever you might go.&nbsp;</span><br /><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">In this scenario, all we need is a wireless protocol to access them. We've earlier talked about&nbsp;</span><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="http://www.technotravel.in/2012/08/how-to-access-folders-from-your-windows-pc-and-stream-videos-over-wifi-on-your-android.html">How To Access Folders From Your Windows PC and Stream Videos Over Wi-Fi On Your Android</a>&nbsp;which uses SMB (Samba) protocol to access the folders, and moreover it's a reverse process of what we're gonna discuss here. So, the only famous protocol left for our cause is the File Transfer Protocol or FTP. Via FTP you can easily access the folders of your Android onto your PC irrespective of operating system on your machine as we believe FTP is supported by most Operating Systems.</span><br /><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><b>Start FTP Server On Your Android</b></span><br /><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">To serve this purpose we'll use the popular, user-friendly, free and feature-rich <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.estrongs.android.pop" target="_blank">ES File Explorer</a>. If you haven't tested it yet then click the link to <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.estrongs.android.pop" target="_blank">download it from Google Play</a>. According to me, it's a must have app for each and every Android user.</span><br /><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">After the installation, open up ES File Explorer and goto Settings. Scroll down until you find a menu called Remote Access.</span><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-DFY8YR2eqlg/UB9fwav_lhI/AAAAAAAABCg/mztjLUMNfLg/s1600/Screenshot_2012-08-06-10-44-48.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-DFY8YR2eqlg/UB9fwav_lhI/AAAAAAAABCg/mztjLUMNfLg/s1600/Screenshot_2012-08-06-10-44-48.png" /></a></div><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Click on it as you'll see a checkbox named Remote Manage. Just check it as you'll find the ftp address of your newly made FTP server which is hosted on your Android. There is a link with the port address in the comment area of that menu entry. Just remember it or type it on a notepad. Thus your FTP server on Android is up and running.</span><br /><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><b>How To Access Folders via Windows Explorer</b></span><br /><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">It's pretty easy over here. Make sure your PC and Android are connected over Wi-Fi. Now just open Windows Explorer window and click the address bar to type the address of the ftp server. E.g <i>ftp://ip address:port</i> which is in my case <i>ftp://192.168.43.1:3127/</i>. Just type this and hit Enter.</span><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-laF8vGYf0wM/UB9g4NBD68I/AAAAAAAABCo/szsy881ojTA/s1600/06-08-2012+11-38-56+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-laF8vGYf0wM/UB9g4NBD68I/AAAAAAAABCo/szsy881ojTA/s1600/06-08-2012+11-38-56+AM.png" /></a></div><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Now you can see the folders of your phone on your PC as if it is connected via USB cable.</span><br /><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><b>How To Access Folders via Browser</b></span><br /><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">If your browser supports FTP (Most browser does!), then just type the link ftp://192.168.x.x:xxxx into the address bar of the browser and you can access folders of your phone on your browser.</span><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-hwtzNyN9m9Q/UB9hhehPaMI/AAAAAAAABCw/Uiwc3_sQn5g/s1600/06-08-2012+10-54-39+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-hwtzNyN9m9Q/UB9hhehPaMI/AAAAAAAABCw/Uiwc3_sQn5g/s1600/06-08-2012+10-54-39+AM.png" /></a></div><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">We've used our favorite Chrome for this purpose. But you are free to use the browser of your choice. Just make sure it supports FTP.</span><br /><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div>
	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
