<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>/TechnoTravel-in/</title>
   
   <link>/TechnoTravel-in/</link>
   <description>The daily source of digital inspirations</description>
   <language>en-in</language>
   
   <title>
   <![CDATA[ TechnoTravel.in ]]>
   </title>
   <description>
   <![CDATA[ The daily source of digital inspirations ]]>
   </description>
   <link>/TechnoTravel-in/</link>
   <image>
   <url>/TechnoTravel-in/assets/images/favicon.ico</url>
   <title>TechnoTravel.in</title>
   <link>/TechnoTravel-in/</link>
   </image>
   <generator>Jekyll 3.6.2</generator>
   <lastBuildDate></lastBuildDate>
   <atom:link href="/TechnoTravel-in/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
   <ttl>60</ttl>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>15 Top Free Websites To Backup And Share Your Data On The Cloud</title>
	  <link>/TechnoTravel-in/2012/08/15-top-free-websites-to-backup-and-share-your-data-on-the-cloud</link>
		
				
						<author>Rajat Patel</author>
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
	  <pubDate>2012-08-20T06:18:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/TechnoTravel-in/2012/08/15-top-free-websites-to-backup-and-share-your-data-on-the-cloud</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-McsYNYawaME/UDHWAUhyBqI/AAAAAAAABRM/LYhX9HRxYaU/s1600/cloud_storage_2_web_0.png" imageanchor="1" style="clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-McsYNYawaME/UDHWAUhyBqI/AAAAAAAABRM/LYhX9HRxYaU/s1600/cloud_storage_2_web_0.png" /></a></div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Well, backups are essential and we've been told many times how important they are, although we may not pay attention to it until it's too late and we lose all our data! Though you can always backup your important data on your external physical hard drive,&nbsp;but free online backup services provide useful redundancy that could save your data big time!</span><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">If you are a regular TechnoTravel.in reader, you may get this now that we're fan of <a href="http://www.technotravel.in/2012/08/pros-and-cons-of-cloud-basedonline-antivirus.html">cloud computing</a> and we will be writing numerous articles in coming future to let the world understand it's pros and cons. So, as a part of that effort, here we're mentioning out some useful and FREE websites, 15 to be precise, that offer free cloud storage space to let you backup, share or synchronize your data. Each of these services offers a free plan, most also having options for paid subscriptions that offer more storage space, and possibly additional features. Most of these services offer useful backup features such as automatic backups, scheduling, versioning, and restore features. Some services offer other useful features, such as the ability to access your backed up files anywhere using a browser or mobile apps and the ability to stream your media files to your mobile device.</span><br /><h3 style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Microsoft SkyDrive</span></h3><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="http://windows.microsoft.com/en-US/skydrive/home" target="_blank">Microsoft SkyDrive</a> offers 7GB of free data for the new subscribers. It used to offer 25GB in its initial stages, but now it's reduced down to 7GB. Though 7GB is also a good cloud storage space. The old subscribers, like me, are allowed to keep their 25GBs for free.</span></div><div><br /></div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Store your files on SkyDrive and you can access them from your Android phone, iPhone, iPad, Windows phone in addition to your PC or Mac.&nbsp;Use SkyDrive to share large files and photos with your friends and family. They only need a web browser to access the files and photos.</span><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Though there are some drawbacks of SkyDrive that are worth mentioning here. Firstly, it&nbsp;doesn't&nbsp;offer any considerable security to the files you upload, so if you are about to upload your sensitive data on SkyDrive, stop here. The other drawback is that it offers only one folder named SkyDrive, thus if you have data sorted out in many folders, you might find it difficult to upload it on SkyDrive.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">With 7 GB of free storage, SkyDrive is a good place to store your photos and other non-sensitive documents. Use other free backup services for your sensitive and private files. We mention which ones provide encryption for files uploaded to and retrieved from their service.</span><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-9Eick34xGX4/UDHSVClEmVI/AAAAAAAABPU/Pr2qfk2ov9s/s1600/20-08-2012+10-05-48+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-9Eick34xGX4/UDHSVClEmVI/AAAAAAAABPU/Pr2qfk2ov9s/s1600/20-08-2012+10-05-48+AM.png" /></a></div><div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Box</span></h3><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="http://www.box.com/" target="_blank">Box</a>&nbsp;is a good backup solution for the small but important files, as it offers 5GB of storage space with the file size limit of 100MB.&nbsp;The free account also allows you to create file sharing links and provides secure transfer and storage of your data. You can access your data anywhere, anytime, on any device, such as a desktop computer, a laptop, an iPhone, an iPad, or an Android device.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Organize your files online using folders just like you would on your desktop PC. Edit your documents online and save them directly back into your Box account using your native desktop applications.&nbsp;Use Box to share large files easily, rather than trying to email big files, such as videos or presentations.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">If you need more than 5 GB of storage space, you can <a href="https://www.box.com/pricing/">upgrade your account</a> to 25 GB of space for $9.99 per month, or 50 GB of space for $19.99 per month. Both of these plans also increases the maximum file size to 1 GB. Business and Enterprise plans are also available.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-zAi1Hd63YG8/UDHSuhHtm0I/AAAAAAAABPc/gzy0f6a9Yo4/s1600/20-08-2012+10-20-16+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-zAi1Hd63YG8/UDHSuhHtm0I/AAAAAAAABPc/gzy0f6a9Yo4/s1600/20-08-2012+10-20-16+AM.png" /></a></div><div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">ADrive</span></h3><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="http://www.adrive.com/" target="_blank">ADrive</a> offers a personal basic plan that offers 50GB of free cloud storage and features allows you to&nbsp;backup, share, access, and edit your data from anywhere you have Internet access.&nbsp;</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Share large files with family and friends using ADrive’s File Sharing feature. You can get a unique link for a file you want to share in an email. Simply email that link to anyone with whom you want to share that file. If you don’t want to share a file anymore, you can “unshare” it as well.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">You can also edit your word processing documents, spreadsheets, and presentations online. Open, edit, and save your documents directly from within your ADrive account online.<br /><br />Use ADrive’s convenient search tool to find files you want to access or restore without having to browse through all your directories and files.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-RCP22X90_Uk/UDHS4THnIkI/AAAAAAAABPk/Fmq_OVvTJwE/s1600/20-08-2012+10-19-05+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-RCP22X90_Uk/UDHS4THnIkI/AAAAAAAABPk/Fmq_OVvTJwE/s1600/20-08-2012+10-19-05+AM.png" /></a></div><div><div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Comodo Backup</span></h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="http://backup.comodo.com/">Comodo Backup</a> offers 5 GB of free online backup space and a free, lifetime license. Backup your data to  Stream music and videos from and edit documents directly in your online account.<br /><br />Files you choose to backup are encrypted before they leave your computer and are stored encrypted on Comodo’s servers or other storage media you select. You can backup to a network drive, an external hard drive, CD or DVD, ISO file, .zip file, or online storage.<br /><br />Schedule any combination of full, incremental, differential, and synchronized backups to run at a time of your choosing using their flexible scheduler.<br /><br />Files in use are backed up using Volume Shadow Copy technology.<br /><br />Access your files from any computer with an internet connection using their web interface.<br /><br />If you need more storage space, you can <a href="http://backup.comodo.com/download-buy.php">purchase 250 GB</a> for $9.99 per month. You can get two months for free by purchasing one year in advance for $99.99.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-lhPvl2J431o/UDHTEdOLQRI/AAAAAAAABPs/9b76jzAVXJc/s1600/20-08-2012+11-07-57+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-lhPvl2J431o/UDHTEdOLQRI/AAAAAAAABPs/9b76jzAVXJc/s1600/20-08-2012+11-07-57+AM.png" /></a></div><div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">MyOtherDrive</span></h3><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="http://www.myotherdrive.com/" target="_blank">MyOtherDrive</a> offers 2 GB of free cloud storage. With a free account, you get unmetered bandwidth, unattended, or automatic, backup, and AES 128-bit encryption and HTTPS (SSL) connections.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-xYCgTzORlEM/UDHTSsMl8oI/AAAAAAAABP0/zR8hIE0j1H8/s1600/20-08-2012+11-09-22+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-xYCgTzORlEM/UDHTSsMl8oI/AAAAAAAABP0/zR8hIE0j1H8/s1600/20-08-2012+11-09-22+AM.png" /></a></div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">BuddyBackup</span></h3><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="http://www.buddybackup.com/" target="_blank">Buddy Backup</a> has an interesting concept. It allows you to&nbsp;backup your data to your friends, families, and colleague’s computers for free. All backed up files are encrypted locally before they are sent to your buddies’ machines and only you have the encryption keys. So, your buddies can’t read your files.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">You don’t have to worry about your backups staying on your buddies’ computers. You can setup BuddyBackup to backup multiple copies of your files, so you’re sure you have backups. Two copies of your data are spread among your buddies by default. BuddyBackup also regularly checks that your buddies still have your backups. If there is a problem on a buddy’s computer, BuddyBackup automatically backs up your files to a different buddy instead. So, if one of your buddies uninstalls BuddyBackup or their computer fails, your data is still safe</span><span style="color: #333333; font-family: Verdana;"><span style="font-size: 14px; line-height: 17px;">.</span></span><br /><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">You can also backup your data offline to your own external hard drives.<br /><br />If your computer crashes and you have to restore your data to a new computer, you can easily do so by running BuddyBackup on your new computer. You can also recover your files from a friend’s computer, if you haven’t replaced your computer yet, using the Guest Mode. In Guest Mode, you can’t add to backups; you can only restore files from existing backups.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-EJGH6RQiPcM/UDHTf24_H6I/AAAAAAAABP8/_XQN8FSazLY/s1600/20-08-2012+11-11-28+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-EJGH6RQiPcM/UDHTf24_H6I/AAAAAAAABP8/_XQN8FSazLY/s1600/20-08-2012+11-11-28+AM.png" /></a></div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">DropBox</span></h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="https://www.dropbox.com/pricing">Dropbox</a> offers 2 GB of storage for free, and the ability to sync files and folders between your Windows, Mac, or Linux computer and the cloud. Use the desktop client or the web interface to add your files and folders to the Dropbox folder. Once in the Dropbox folder, the files are synced among the PC, the cloud, and any other devices enabled with Dropbox, including mobile devices like phones and tablets.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-P4h_lohISKo/UDHTpvYLUII/AAAAAAAABQE/IVvc5Fm7xEQ/s1600/20-08-2012+11-13-32+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-P4h_lohISKo/UDHTpvYLUII/AAAAAAAABQE/IVvc5Fm7xEQ/s1600/20-08-2012+11-13-32+AM.png" /></a></div><div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">SpiderOak</span></h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="https://spideroak.com/">SpiderOak</a> offers 2 GB of secure, free storage space for online backups, synchronization, sharing, remote access, and storage of your files from unlimited Windows, Mac OS X, and Linux (Ubuntu, Debian, Fedora, and openSUSE) computers and locations, such as USB flash drives, external hard drives, and network drives.</span></div><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">ShareRooms are password-protected locations on SpiderOak’s servers that allow you to securely share files gathered from multiple machines with others. Any data in a ShareRoom is updated automatically when changes are made, and a notification of the changes is sent out as an RSS feed.<br /><br />Apps for Android and iOS devices are provided that allow you to access your data from anywhere. You can view, watch, or listen to any file in your SpiderOak account, visit ShareRooms, share files, and download files to your device for offline access.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-aa2-7qqRkMQ/UDHTzlDPrRI/AAAAAAAABQM/1NWG4PvKTks/s1600/20-08-2012+11-14-43+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-aa2-7qqRkMQ/UDHTzlDPrRI/AAAAAAAABQM/1NWG4PvKTks/s1600/20-08-2012+11-14-43+AM.png" /></a></div><div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">MozyHome Free</span></h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="http://mozy.com/home/free">MozyHome Free</a> offers 2 GB of storage for free along with the option to add more storage space through a paid subscription. Clients for PC and Mac are available for download that you can set up to perform fully automated backups. Select folders to be backed up, set a schedule, and Mozy will keep a backup of these folders online, regularly syncing them without interaction from you. Mozy also provides military-grade encryption prior to transfer using a secure SSL connection.<br /><br />Once you perform your initial backup of your files, Mozy saves bandwidth by only backing up new or changed portions of files, helping to speed up future backups. Mozy also backs up all open and locked files, such as Outlook PST files. You can schedule backups to happen while your computer is on but not in use. Backups can occur daily or weekly at a specific time of day.<br /><br />When you need to restore your data, you can choose to do so using the software client, on the web, or by ordering a DVD to restore. If you’re using Windows, you can also restore your data using the right-click context menu or through the Mozy Virtual Drive. You can restore file versions up to 30 days into the past.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-rwA86PAdYmY/UDHT_OQKyMI/AAAAAAAABQU/Yi9i8FTs1j8/s1600/20-08-2012+11-16-36+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-rwA86PAdYmY/UDHT_OQKyMI/AAAAAAAABQU/Yi9i8FTs1j8/s1600/20-08-2012+11-16-36+AM.png" /></a></div><div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">MiMedia</span></h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="http://www.mimedia.com/">MiMedia</a> offers 7 GB of storage space for free, and features such as secure, automatic online backup and cloud sync. Access your files from anywhere and stream your music and videos and view your photos using MiMedia’s free iPhone and iPad apps. Easily share your photos, videos, and files and post to your favorite social networks.<br /><br />Unlike some other online backup services, MiMedia allows you to backup from any number of computers and devices, such as a laptop, desktop computer, external hard drives, network drives, and more.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-alF-agGJ1sY/UDHULrgcJmI/AAAAAAAABQc/UARiR_BIDOU/s1600/20-08-2012+11-17-55+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-alF-agGJ1sY/UDHULrgcJmI/AAAAAAAABQc/UARiR_BIDOU/s1600/20-08-2012+11-17-55+AM.png" /></a></div><div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Google Drive</span></h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="https://drive.google.com/start?authuser=0#home">Google Drive</a> offers 5 GB of storage for free. Store files online, share them with family and friends, and edit your documents online using Google Docs from your PC or Mac, iPhone, iPad, Android device, and from Chrome OS. View any of over 30 file types on your PC using your browser, without having the program installed on your computer.<br /><br />There are special apps on the Chrome Web Store that allow you to create, open, and share files directly in Google Drive.<br /><br />Search for your files on Google Drive by keyword, and filter by file type, owner, and more. Google Drive’s search feature can even find text in scanned documents and objects in images.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-DmyqP6ugLQQ/UDHUXrp-arI/AAAAAAAABQk/Vs1xakCbvzc/s1600/20-08-2012+11-19-13+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-DmyqP6ugLQQ/UDHUXrp-arI/AAAAAAAABQk/Vs1xakCbvzc/s1600/20-08-2012+11-19-13+AM.png" /></a></div><div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">SugarSync</span></h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="https://www.sugarsync.com/">SugarSync</a> also offers 5 GB of storage space for free. You can use SugarSync not only as an online backup service, but also as a way to sync your files, such as music and photos, among your computers and other devices, such as your Android device, iPhone, iPad, BlackBerry, and Kindle Fire. SugarSync can be handy if you need to transfer files between a PC and a Mac.<br /><br />Just like Mozy, you can backup your data from any folders on your hard drive. You can also select folders to share with your friends and family. You can edit files on your computer while it’s offline, and the changed files are quietly synced with SugarSync the next time your computer is online without interfering with your productivity.<br /><br />SugarSync keeps the previous five versions of all your files so you can reference or restore them in the future. Only the most recent version of each file counts against your storage limit.<br /><br />If you just want to backup a set of files without automatically syncing them or updating them, you can use SugarSync’s Web Archive feature. Everything stored in the Web Archive is accessible from the web and your mobile devices.<br /><br />SugarSync offers mobile apps for devices such as Android, iPad, iPhone, iPod Touch, BlackBerry, and Windows Mobile. You can access files backed up to your SugarSync account from any of your other computers, share photos, upload files and photos of any size from your mobile device to your computer (even if it’s turned off), and even edit documents, depending upon the capabilities of your device.<br /><br />Data uploaded to and retrieved from SugarSync’s servers are sent over the Internet using TLS (SSL 3.3) encryption. Every piece of information moved between your computers, mobile devices, and SugarSync’s servers is verified as a secure communication, whether you are backing up files to their servers or restoring files from them. You can also protect folders you share with other people, such as clients or coworkers.<br /><br />SugarSync offers some handy features for transferring music and photos between your mobile devices and your computers. You can also stream music to your mobile device. For Android devices and iPhones, you can sync your music to your phone so you can listen to it offline. Share a large video file by sending a link to the file rather than sending an email with a large attachment.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-DKUPEZuvOu4/UDHUit9xr7I/AAAAAAAABQs/B6M5dmFB0ek/s1600/20-08-2012+11-20-46+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-DKUPEZuvOu4/UDHUit9xr7I/AAAAAAAABQs/B6M5dmFB0ek/s1600/20-08-2012+11-20-46+AM.png" /></a></div><div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">ElephantDrive</span></h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="http://home.elephantdrive.com/plans-and-pricing/free-plans/">ElephantDrive’s Lite Edition</a> plan offers 2 GB of free online backup space and has all the features of ElephantDrive’s premium plans, including automatic online storage and backup, military-grade encryption, and support for up to three computers or devices. You can also access your data from any internet-enabled device and share files and photos with a single click.<br /><br />One advantage of ElephantDrive’s service is their “Web Explorer.” It allows you to access and upload files using a web browser anywhere you have internet access. You do not have to wait until you have access to an approve device using proprietary software.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-uf9dsPkRSac/UDHUui3tU6I/AAAAAAAABQ0/iNSoCpLnRdw/s1600/20-08-2012+11-23-30+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-uf9dsPkRSac/UDHUui3tU6I/AAAAAAAABQ0/iNSoCpLnRdw/s1600/20-08-2012+11-23-30+AM.png" /></a></div><div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">CrashPlan</span></h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="http://www.crashplan.com/">CrashPlan</a> offers the ability to backup your data to multiple destinations for free (for personal backup). You can backup using your own computers and external hard drives for onsite backups, as well as backup your data to computers belonging to your friends and family for offsite backup.<br /><br />CrashPlan’s backup software runs on PCs, Macs, Linux, and Solaris and backs up data from any combination of these operating systems and from attached hard drives, as well. Backups happen automatically so you don’t have to remember to backup your data or get annoyed from popup dialogs reminding you to perform a backup. You can schedule your backups if you want to control when they are performed. If a backup is interrupted, it is resumed the next time the computers become available again.<br /><br />When you backup data to multiple destinations, your data is sent to one destination one at a time. To make sure you have a full backup as soon as possible, the order of your backups is based on which destination will complete first.<br /><br />With the free version of CrashPlan, your files are secured before they are transferred to CrashPlan’s servers using enterprise-grade, 128-bit encryption. Paid plans provide 448-bit encryption.<br /><br />There are no limitations on the size of files you can backup.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-m8Op9OAwbC4/UDHU9LdRdZI/AAAAAAAABQ8/t1vwlLVwGXg/s1600/20-08-2012+11-25-23+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-m8Op9OAwbC4/UDHU9LdRdZI/AAAAAAAABQ8/t1vwlLVwGXg/s1600/20-08-2012+11-25-23+AM.png" /></a></div><div><h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Ubuntu One</span></h3><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="https://one.ubuntu.com/">Ubuntu One</a> allows you to sync up to 5 GB of files to the cloud for free and access it anywhere. It may seem like it’s only for Ubuntu Linux machines, but you can also sync your Windows computer to Ubuntu One account. They offer apps for Android and iOS devices that let you manage your files and photos directly from your mobile device.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-7OGgbbnea9g/UDHVL7nnnLI/AAAAAAAABRE/WHNLOq0LfwQ/s1600/20-08-2012+11-27-11+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-7OGgbbnea9g/UDHVL7nnnLI/AAAAAAAABRE/WHNLOq0LfwQ/s1600/20-08-2012+11-27-11+AM.png" /></a></div><div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">If you don't want to shell out any money on paid cloud storage, then you always can sign up on the multiple websites above to have yourself a decent amount of cloud storage to go with for free. If you sign up for all the above mentioned cloud storage websites, you'll avail yourself as good as 100GB (approx) of cloud storage, which is&nbsp;humongous indeed! However, you must not forget which file is stored at which place, otherwise it can be a headache!!</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif; font-size: xx-small;">Top Image Courtesy : <a href="http://www.savageio.com/page/cloud-storage-backup-services" target="_blank">Savageio.com</a></span></div><div><br /></div></div></div></div>
	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>What is OpenDNS? Why You Absolutely Need It To Stay Secure and Protected?</title>
	  <link>/TechnoTravel-in/2012/08/what-is-opendns-why-you-absolutely-need-it-to-stay-secure-and-protected</link>
		
				
						<author>Rajat Patel</author>
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
	  <pubDate>2012-08-14T06:36:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/TechnoTravel-in/2012/08/what-is-opendns-why-you-absolutely-need-it-to-stay-secure-and-protected</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-z7mYAXIUzTA/UCnwYrCBqFI/AAAAAAAABNo/0OtquudE6pg/s1600/common-sprite+(1).png" imageanchor="1" style="clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-z7mYAXIUzTA/UCnwYrCBqFI/AAAAAAAABNo/0OtquudE6pg/s1600/common-sprite+(1).png" /></a></div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Well, instead of diving into OpenDNS thing&nbsp;straight&nbsp;away, we believe you might want to have a look at what DNS actually is? DNS is the abbreviated form of the term "Domain Name Server" (You can actually replace Server with Service or System as well!).</span><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">The primary job of the DNS server is providing the ip address of the different websites to your computer. Which means, when you type www.google.com or www.yahoo.com in your browser address bar, your computer actually queries the DNS server which it is configured to use. In response to that query DNS server returns the ip address of that queried website, in this case say www.google.com. Thus DNS server will return the ip address of www.google.com's server. With the help of this ip address, your computer can finally reach to Google.com. Thus there is an important role of DNS server to let you access the internet from your PC.</span><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">No matter what operating system you use, say <a href="http://www.technotravel.in/search/label/windows">Windows</a>, <a href="http://www.technotravel.in/search/label/Linux">Linux</a> or <a href="http://www.technotravel.in/search/label/iOS">Mac</a>, your computer have to have DNS server configured to be able to access the Internet. Now, by default, your ISP (Internet Service Provider) has their own DNS server in most cases. Thus up till now, if you haven't changed your DNS server ever, then you surely are running your ISP's DNS server.</span><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Unfortunately, your DNS server can be the weakest link in the entire Internet Workflow. In a easy language, no matter how speedy or robust your internet link is, if the DNS server of your ISP is faulty or say tad slow, it can ruin your browsing experience. If the DNS server of your ISP is slow, it takes more time to reply to the query sent by your computer, resulting in the slowness of the rendering of the webpage. And in India, ISPs seems not to be too concerned about having a robust DNS server. Which means, even if your ISP provides you the speed of 2Mbps, it can feel like 1Mbps if your DNS server is running slow!</span><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">To solve this problem,</span><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">We can always opt for any other DNS server which is faster and equipped with more robust features than your ISP's DNS server. There are plenty of fast DNS servers to choose from to use for your computer, but we like OpenDNS the most.</span><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="http://www.opendns.com/" target="_blank">OpenDNS</a> is a dedicated DNS servers. Which directly means that the developer staff at OpenDNS is only focused on making their DNS server faster and more reliable, nothing else. OpenDNS dramatically speeds up your internet connection and also enhances your overall internet experience as you'll get this after reading the full post.</span><br /><h3 style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">How To Get Started?</span></h3><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">There is no need of any software or registration to avail yourself the benefits of OpenDNS. All you need to do is to change your computer's DNS servers with the following ip addresses:</span></div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><ul><li>208.67.222.222&nbsp;</li><li>208.67.220.220</li></ul>Don't know how to change your computer's DNS server? <a href="http://www.technotravel.in/2011/08/how-to-change-dns-servers-for-fast.html" target="">Here</a> is the guide that might help you! <a href="http://www.technotravel.in/2011/08/how-to-change-dns-servers-for-fast.html" target="">How To Change DNS Server in Windows</a></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">The whole process takes a few seconds but with this single step alone, you just made your computer safer and increased the overall browsing speed. Here's why: </span><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Unlike the DNS servers of your less reliable ISP, OpenDNS servers store the IP addresses of millions of websites in their cache so it would take less time to resolve your requests. So if you have asked for an IP address of a website that has been previously requested by another OpenDNS user, you will get the reply instantly.</span><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-oaBfZRblaSg/UCnxP8vAgUI/AAAAAAAABNw/6HbthGSKPuQ/s1600/opendns.gif" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-oaBfZRblaSg/UCnxP8vAgUI/AAAAAAAABNw/6HbthGSKPuQ/s1600/opendns.gif" /></a></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Another huge advantage of OpenDNS is that it prevents phishing sites that has ability to steal your important passwords from loading in your computer. Thus OpenDNS does the job which your normal antivirus can't do.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">The another very good&nbsp;feature&nbsp;is Parental Control. If you enable this, you can actually prevent your kids from accessing porn sites using OpenDNS shield! There are another plenty of features included in the OpenDNS like Solving Typo Errors, Shortcuts for your favorite sites and many more.</span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-s3RfsaRLXqM/UCnxeNMyVYI/AAAAAAAABN4/O6GX8lE3mD0/s1600/14-08-2012+11-37-25+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-s3RfsaRLXqM/UCnxeNMyVYI/AAAAAAAABN4/O6GX8lE3mD0/s1600/14-08-2012+11-37-25+AM.png" /></a></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Thus in many ways, OpenDNS is a very useful and easy to set-up DNS server to enhance your overall internet browsing experience.</span></div><div><br /></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">So why wait? Get started here&nbsp;<a href="http://www.opendns.com/">www.opendns.com</a></span></div><div><br /></div></div>
	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>How To Build A Website Cheaply? Get Upto 20% Off on BigRock Products Using Our Code Here</title>
	  <link>/TechnoTravel-in/2012/08/how-to-build-website-cheaply-get-upto-20-off-on-bigrock-products</link>
		
				
						<author>Rajat Patel</author>
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
				
		
	  <pubDate>2012-08-13T18:27:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/TechnoTravel-in/2012/08/how-to-build-website-cheaply-get-upto-20-off-on-bigrock-products</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Have you ever&nbsp;dream of owning your own website? If yes, the you've landed at the right page. At <a href="http://technotravel.in/">TechnoTravel.in</a>, we respect your values and have a great desire to give your dreams wings. As an effort to that we've come forward along with our sponsor <a href="http://technotravel.bigrock.in/" target="_blank">BigRock</a> to turn your dream into reality. But how? Read on.</span><br /><h3 style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">What is BigRock?</span></h3><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Well, in simple language, <a href="http://technotravel.bigrock.in/" target="_blank">BigRock</a> is a leading domain registrar in India which along with Domain Registration also provides other essential services to setup your website like, Website Hosting, Email Hosting, Do-It-Yourself Website Builder, Web Designing and many more services that you'll surely need to setup your website. Thus BigRock is just the place that you want to be at, if you are really serious about setting up your own website.</span></div><h3 style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">How To Get Started?</span></h3><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Nowadays, setting up your website requires absolutely zero knowledge of any sought of coding or programming language. Yeah, you read that right.&nbsp;</span></div><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">No matter in which&nbsp;profession you are, you can build your own website right away on your own.&nbsp;The leading websites like BigRock take the responsibility of such cumbersome coding work on their own shoulders to provide you a flawless and smooth experience in building your website.&nbsp;</span></blockquote><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">So, how it's done? Here is a step-by-step procedure that will lead you to your own website.</span></div><h3 style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Register a Domain Name</span></h3><div><span style="margin-left: 150px;"><script type="text/javascript">document.write("<iframe name='banner' src='http://affiliates.bigrock.com/scripts/banner.php?a_aid=5027f481261b5&a_bid=90ec8a42&w=1' framespacing='0' frameborder='no' scrolling='no' width='300' height='250' allowtransparency='true'><a href='http://www.bigrock.in/domain-registration/index.php5027f481261b5?a_aid=5027f481261b5&amp;a_bid=90ec8a42' target='_top'>Domain Check Availability Widget</a></iframe>"); </script><noscript>&amp;amp;amp;lt;h2&amp;amp;amp;gt;&amp;amp;amp;lt;a href="http://www.bigrock.in/domain-registration/index.php5027f481261b5"&amp;amp;amp;gt;Domain Check Availability Widget&amp;amp;amp;lt;/a&amp;amp;amp;gt;&amp;amp;amp;lt;/h2&amp;amp;amp;gt; </noscript></span><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">First of all choose a proper domain name that suits your idea or theme of the website. E.g, if you want to setup a website of your company, the domain name <i>www.yourcompanyname.com</i> looks good and sounds professional. Thus grab your desired domain before it gets booked by others. Just head over to BigRock and enter your domain name and book it for the desired term. You can book your domain as long as 10 years!&nbsp;</span></div><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Its recommended to book a domain for a longer term so that there is no need to renew it every year. As a failure in domain renewal may cause you lose your domain which is absolutely undesirable thing to happen.</span></blockquote><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">So, head over to <a href="http://technotravel.bigrock.in/domain-registration/index.php" target="_blank">BigRock</a> and choose a domain for yourself. Now, as a TechnoTravel.in reader, we have a offer for you.&nbsp;</span><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Now <a href="http://technotravel.bigrock.in/domain-registration/index.php" target="_blank">BigRock</a> provides <b>flat 10% discount</b> on the purchase of domain using our coupon code. You can use this coupon code at the checkout page of your purchase to avail 10% discount.</span><br /><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">The Coupon Code is <b><u>BRRAJAT</u></b></span><br /><h3 style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Choose Your Host</span></h3><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">The Host is a place where your website is stored. You can say the Host as a place to park your website in the Internet which let your visitors access your website easily and 24 hours a day. Thus choosing a better host is an Important aspect in website building.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">Choosing <a href="http://technotravel.bigrock.in/web-hosting/index.php" target="_blank">BigRock</a> as a host makes sense due to its higher reliability and low costs. BigRock offers you the hosting service as low as Rs.59 (or $1.00 approx). Which is very low indeed in terms of service they provide. And as a TechnoTravel.in reader, you'll always have an offer, so here it is!</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><a href="http://technotravel.bigrock.in/web-hosting/index.php" target="_blank">BigRock</a> provides a special <b>20% discount</b> on web hosting. Just enter the following coupon code to avail yourself 20% discount.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">The Coupon Code is&nbsp;</span><b style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><u>BRRAJAT</u></b><br /><b style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><u><br /></u></b></div><div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-K9ucClN4cwY/UClGXu26VvI/AAAAAAAABNA/8zzHXrw-AzA/s1600/13-08-2012+11-11-34+PM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-K9ucClN4cwY/UClGXu26VvI/AAAAAAAABNA/8zzHXrw-AzA/s1600/13-08-2012+11-11-34+PM.png" /></a></div><b style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><u><br /></u></b></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">You can also avail <b>20% discount</b> for <a href="http://www.bigrock.in/website-design/index.php" target="_blank">Do-It-Yourself Website Builder</a> using the same code <u style="font-weight: bold;">BRRAJAT</u>. The good thing here is that you can have a demo of website builder before you actually make a payment. So, just try out the demo and then decide whether to use it or not. Personally, I'm very satisfied with the demo and recommend to my readers.</span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;"><b><u><br /></u></b></span></div><div><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif;">So why wait, just head over to <a href="http://technotravel.bigrock.in/">BigRock.in</a> and claim your website at discounted rate.</span></div><div><br /></div></div>
	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
